<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A Pelican Blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/all-en.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>2017</title><link href="/2017.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-10-25:2017.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Ioannis -- Mourtos</title><link href="/ioannis-mourtos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-10-20:ioannis-mourtos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yiannis Mourtos&lt;/strong&gt; is an Associate Professor in "Mathematics of Operations Research" at the Department of Management Science &amp;amp; Technology, Athens University of Economics and Business. He studied Computer Engineering and Informatics at the corresponding department of the University of Patras and obtained both his MSc and PhD from the Operational Research Department, London School of Economics and Political Science. He has worked as a Lecturer at the Department of Economics, University of Patras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His research is focused in the areas of Combinatorial Optimisation and Integer Programming, examining also the integration of Integer Programming with Constraint Programming algorithms. He has published in Operations Research journals like Mathematical Programming, Mathematics of Operations Research, INFORMS Journal on Computing, SIAM Journal on Discrete Mathematics Operations Research Letters, European Journal of Operational Research and Discrete Mathematics, for several of which he has served as a reviewer. He has also participated in national and European research projects, in most of them as a Scientific Coordinator.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>George - Metaxopoulos</title><link href="/george-metaxopoulos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-10-15:george-metaxopoulos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Metaxopoulos&lt;/strong&gt; is an undergraduate student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB) in the Department of Management Science and Technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is an active member of JA Alumni Greece since 2013, being the Financial Planning Manager of the Organization since 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His main research interests involve Software Security and Privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Stefanos - Chaliaso</title><link href="/stefanos-chaliaso.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-10-15:stefanos-chaliaso.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stefanos Chaliasos&lt;/strong&gt; is an undergraduate student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB) in the Department of Management Science and Technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His research interests are in the areas of Security and Privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is a member of the &lt;a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/"&gt;ISTLab&lt;/a&gt; group.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Anastasia - Griva</title><link href="/anastasia-griva.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-09-07:anastasia-griva.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anastasia Griva&lt;/strong&gt; is PhD Candidate at the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business. Apart from Business Analytics Lab (BALab), she is also researcher in the SCORE research group of the ELTRUN Research Center, where she participates in projects funded by the EU (UTURN, SERAMIS) and other projects that require a close cooperation with the retail industry. Her specializations are retail analytics and data mining. The context of her PhD involves pattern identification in customer’s visits that reveal their shopping missions. To this end, different data sources, such as POS data, RFID data, Google Analytics, web transactions and data derived from other sensor devices, are processed and combined to provide insights regarding the shopper behavior. Moreover, she holds a BSc in Management Science and Technology with a specialization in Quantitative Methods in Economics and Management, and an MSc (with honors) in Information Systems, both from the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB). Furthermore, she has attended the seminar “Big Data and Business Analytics” provided by the Executive Training Center of AUEB. In general, her research interests lie in the areas of Business Analytics, Retail Analytics, IoT Analytics, Customer behavior, Data Mining, and Marketing Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>ckjm</title><link href="/https://www.spinellis.gr/sw/ckjm/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-26:https://www.spinellis.gr/sw/ckjm/</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>CScout</title><link href="/https://www.spinellis.gr/cscout/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-26:https://www.spinellis.gr/cscout/</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>dgsh</title><link href="/http://www.spinellis.gr/sw/dgsh/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-26:http://www.spinellis.gr/sw/dgsh/</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>gi</title><link href="/https://github.com/dspinellis/gi" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-26:https://github.com/dspinellis/gi</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>PiCO QL</title><link href="/https://github.com/mfragkoulis/PiCO_QL" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-26:https://github.com/mfragkoulis/PiCO_QL</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>UMLGraph</title><link href="/https://www.spinellis.gr/umlgraph/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-26:https://www.spinellis.gr/umlgraph/</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Unix history</title><link href="/https://github.com/dspinellis/unix-history-repo" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-26:https://github.com/dspinellis/unix-history-repo</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Ioannis Batas</title><link href="/ioannis-batas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-19:ioannis-batas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Ioannis Batas is an undergraduate student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB) in the Department of Management Science and Technology and an Erasmus student at Southern Denmark University (SDU)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ioannis has a passion for tech-related startups; being co-founder of MyPharmacy, TripSleep, Instashop and Yayaka and mentor at Junior Achievement. Furthermore, he gets involved in many social activities; being in the Organizing Committee of TEDxAcademy, Athens Startup Weekend University and DMST Student Conference and member of AIESEC.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Since the first year of university, Ioannis has acquired fundamental programming skills (programming languages, data structures and web frameworks) and has developed several web applications.
&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Efstathia Chioteli</title><link href="/efstathia-chioteli.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-18:efstathia-chioteli.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
 Efstathia Chioteli is an undergraduate student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), in the Department of Management Science and Technology and an Erasmus student at the The Hague University of Applied sciences.
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the first year of university she got involved with entrepreneurship by participating in some contests like Startup Weekend University, entrepreneurship school etc starting her own startup called Yayaka.gr, an online platform of searching and evaluation of professionals’ caregivers for elderly. 
 Beyond her love for startups and innovation, she also loves coding and web development. In addition to the knowledge given to her by the university she also develops her skills on coding in her free time, doing some projects and learning new programming languages, frameworks, tools etc
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Theodore - Stassinopoulos</title><link href="/theodore-stassinopoulos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-04-28:theodore-stassinopoulos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theodore Stassinopoulos&lt;/em&gt; is a PhD candidate in AUEB (Athens University of Economics and Business) and currently works on CROSSMINER project. Holds an MSc in theoretical mathematics from University of Athens and a BSc in mathematics from the saeme university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His research interests lie at algorithm design and analysis, design patterns and best practices for clean code.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SlideQ</title><link href="/https://github.com/tushartushar/slideQ" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-01-01:https://github.com/tushartushar/slideQ</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Action II(2)</title><link href="/action-ii2.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-12-08:action-ii2.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;JavaScript is one of the most important elements of the web. It is being used by the majority of websites and it is supported by all modern browsers. On the other hand though, it can be a vector for many dangerous attacks like cross-site scripting (XSS). With the proposed research we will aim to examine the evolution of JavaScript code over time. Specifically, by using building blocks from our previous research thrusts we will create a framework that collects the scripts used by different websites on a daily basis. Then, we will analyze the resulting dataset to (a) observe if whitelisting defenses can be efficiently employed by websites, (b) examine the development pace of multiple web applications and (c) examine the evolution of potential bugs found in the JavaScript code.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2016</title><link href="/2016.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-10-25:2016.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Nikiforos - Botis</title><link href="/nikiforos-botis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-10-25:nikiforos-botis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nikiforos Botis holds a Bachelor’s degree with distinction from the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB). At January 2016, Nikiforos was admitted at University College London (UCL), in the department of Management Science and Innovation as part of the Erasmus+ program, where he spent the 6th semester of his undergraduate studies. At March 2016, Nikiforos participated in the InnoJam++ @CeBIT 2016 co-organized by SAP and Volkswagen in Hanover, a 32-hour hands-on experience in the latest technologies that are utilized by SAP, following his excellence at the SAP ERP labs which took place in the university (scoring at the 2.5% of the class). In his last year at AUEB, he worked as a Research and Development Intern in the Dutch consultancy company Software Improvement Group, under the supervision of Dr. Yiannis Kanellopoulos. During his internship, Nikiforos developed a new way to holistically depict an Information System, named Information System Canvas. Currently, he is a postgraduate student at Imperial College London, pursuing a Master’s degree at Computer Science. He has been awarded two scholarships (from the General Michael Arnaoutis Foundation and the Greek State Scholarship Foundation) in order to fund his studies. Nikiforos has joined the SENSE (currently BA) group in March 2016 and the OIS group in October 2016 as a research assistant.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vitalis - Salis</title><link href="/vitalis-salis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-07-15:vitalis-salis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vitalis Salis&lt;/em&gt; is a student at the National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is a software engineer on the Greek Research and Technology Network (GRNET), working on &lt;a href="https://www.synnefo.org/"&gt;Synnefo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://okeanos.grnet.gr/home/"&gt;~okeanos&lt;/a&gt;. Previously he's worked on multiple personal projects, most notably &lt;a href="https://github.com/dionyziz/ting"&gt;ting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Alexander - Lattas</title><link href="/alexander-lattas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-07-12:alexander-lattas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexandros Lattas&lt;/strong&gt; is a postgraduate Advanced Computing student in Imperial College London, with an academic interest in Machine Learning, Security and Entrepreneurship. He holds a BSc in Management Science and Technology from Athens University of Economics and Business and has been an Innovation Management affiliate student at University College London. Alexandros has been a Security Consultant Intern at Oracle and a Co-Founder and Board Member at Junior Achievement Alumni Greece. He has been awarded the Hellenic Petroleum scholarship, the Social Impact Award (2014), the Junior Achievement Company Programme Award (2012), three honorary distinctions from Athens University of Economics and Business and one from the Greek Ministry of Education and has participated in the Edutrip 2016 program at UC Berkeley. Full CV is available at http://cv.lattas.eu. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vasilis - Stavrou</title><link href="/vasilis-stavrou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-05-11:vasilis-stavrou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vasilis Stavrou&lt;/strong&gt; is PhD Candidate at the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics 
and Business. Apart from Business Analytics Lab, he is also researcher in the SCORE team of the ELTRUN Research Center, where he 
participates in projects funded by the EU (SERAMIS) and other projects of the private sector that require cooperation with the retail 
industry. His research areas are IoT and Business Analytics while his PhD examines the leveraging of indoor positioning techniques to 
support decision making in the retail context. In the last years he has also worked as a researcher has publications in the area of 
Social Media Intelligence. He holds a diploma degree in Computer Engineering from University of Patras and an MSc (with honors) in 
Information Systems from Athens University of Economics and Business. His interests focus on Business Analytics, Business Intelligence, 
Shopper Behavior, Data Mining and Machine Learning. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Designite</title><link href="/http://www.designite-tools.com" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-01-01:http://www.designite-tools.com</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Puppeteer</title><link href="/https://github.com/tushartushar/Puppeteer" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-01-01:https://github.com/tushartushar/Puppeteer</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Antonios - Gkortzis</title><link href="/antonios-gkortzis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-12-20:antonios-gkortzis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antonios Gkortzis&lt;/em&gt; is a PhD Candidate at the SENECA (http://senecaproject.github.io/) project. The reasearch topic of this industrial PhD position is "Secure Systems on Cloud Computing Infrastructures" and is offered by Singular Logic, the Athens University of Economics and Bussiness, and the King Juan Carlos University. He holds a BSc in Information Technology Engineering from the Alexandreio Technological Educational Institute of Thessaloniki and a Master Degree in Computing Science (Software Engineering and Distributed Systems) from the University of Gronignen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His main research interests are: Cloud Computing, Security, Software Engineering, Software Quality Assurance and Code Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His current PhD position is founded by Marie Skłodowska-Curie from the framework Horizon 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Stefanos - Georgiou</title><link href="/stefanos-georgiou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-12-16:stefanos-georgiou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stefanos Georgiou&lt;/em&gt; is a PhD Candidate in SENECA (Software ENineering in Enterprise Cloud Applications) project.&lt;br /&gt;
In the context of his European Industrial Doctorate (Eid) he is expected to conduct his research at&lt;br /&gt;
AUEB (Athens University of Economics and Business) and TU Deflt (Delft University) as academic partners&lt;br /&gt;
and with SLG (Singular Logic) as industrial partner.&lt;br /&gt;
He holds a BSc in Networks and Systems Programming from University of Cyprus and a MSc in PERCCOM&lt;br /&gt;
(PERvasive Computing and COMmunications for sustainable development), a joint Master Degree from four&lt;br /&gt;
different Universities (i.e., University of Lorraine, Lappeenranta University of Technology, Lulea University of Technology,&lt;br /&gt;
and ITMO University of Saint Petersburg).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His research interests lie at Green IT, Cloud Computing, Distributed Applications,Big Data Transfer,&lt;br /&gt;
and IoT (Internet of Things)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His current PhD position is founded by Marie Sklodowska-Curie from framework Horizon 2020.&lt;br /&gt;
As a PhD is to provide energy-efficient approach on cloud computing systems using software&lt;br /&gt;
engineering techniques and practices.&lt;br /&gt;
However, in the context of his industrial PhD position task like writing proposals&lt;br /&gt;
, such as RIA (Research Innovation Action) is one of his duties in SLG.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Tushar - Sharma</title><link href="/tushar-sharma.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-12-14:tushar-sharma.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tushar Sharma&lt;/em&gt; is a researcher and PhD candidate at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), Department of Management Science and Technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier, he worked with &lt;em&gt;Siemens Research and Technology Center&lt;/em&gt;, Bangalore, India for more than 7 years. The topics related to software design and architecture, refactoring, code smells, code quality, and technical debt define his career interests. He has an MS (by research) degree in Computer Science from the Indian Institute of Technology-Madras (IIT-M), Chennai, India, where he specialised in design patterns and refactoring. He co-authored the book &lt;em&gt;"Refactoring for Software Design Smells: Managing Technical Debt"&lt;/em&gt; published by Morgan Kaufmann in November 2014. Additionally, he has also co-authored books for Oracle certifications for Java. He is an IEEE Senior Member.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Thodoris - Sotiropoulos</title><link href="/thodoris-sotiropoulos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-11-05:thodoris-sotiropoulos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thodoris Sotiropoulos&lt;/em&gt; is an undergraduate student at the Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens University of Economics and Business. He is a member of &lt;a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/content/groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group. He is currently working at the Greek Research &amp;amp; Technology Network (GRNET) as a software engineer and he has participated in two research projects in the fields of a) Security and Privancy, b) Machine Learning and Information Retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2015</title><link href="/2015.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-10-25:2015.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>SENECA</title><link href="/seneca.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-01-01:seneca.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The project provides the opportunity to nine early-stage researchers to pursue their PhD in the area of software engineering of cloud-based systems. The research programme is organized in three research streams: A) Product quality in cloud-related software development projects B) Process quality in cloud-related software development C) Operations' quality in cloud systems.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2014</title><link href="/2014.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2014-10-25:2014.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Action II</title><link href="/action-ii.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2014-10-09:action-ii.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Code injection attacks are considered as one of the most damaging classes of application attacks that can harm various entities existing either on a web server, a client machine or a mobile device. With the proposed research we will aim to synthesize empirical findings coming of the analysis of the evolution and the behavior of software bugs that lead to code injection attacks, with existing pieces of theoretical work into an approach that covers all types of code injection attacks. Then, we will try to apply out approach to tame such attacks in different problem domains (web, mobile, etc.). For every application of our method, we will provide corresponding prototypes, deploy them in real world conditions and test them in terms of accuracy, operation cost and maintenance cost.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Christos - Oikonomou</title><link href="/christos-oikonomou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2014-01-15:christos-oikonomou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christos Oikonomou&lt;/em&gt; is a student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), Department of Management Science and Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2013, he helped in a research project regarding the evolution of prices at the Greek Ministry for Development and Competitiveness, under the supervision of &lt;a href="http://www.kepe.gr/index.php/el/profil-cb/userprofile/pjprodr"&gt;Dr. Prodromidis&lt;/a&gt;, presented the results at the eleventh &lt;a href="http://fsdet.dmst.aueb.gr/"&gt;DMST Conference&lt;/a&gt; (13/05/2014); and tutored (TAed) certain microeconomic and macroeconomic review sessions for the freshmen class of 2013-14 at the request of &lt;a href="http://www.kepe.gr/index.php/el/profil-cb/userprofile/pjprodr"&gt;Dr. Prodromidis&lt;/a&gt;. Also he has worked in extensive software systems under supervision of &lt;a href="http://www.spinellis.gr/index.html.var"&gt;Dr. Diomidis Spinellis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2013</title><link href="/2013.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2013-10-25:2013.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Damianos - Chatziantoniou</title><link href="/damianos-chatziantoniou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2013-02-19:damianos-chatziantoniou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Damianos Chatziantoniou received his B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics from the University of
Athens (June 1991, summa cum laude) and continued his studies in Computer Science at
Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences of New York University (M.Sc., Dec. 1992) and
Columbia University (M.Phil., Feb. 1996, Ph.D., June 1997). His academic research interests
include big data, business intelligence (data warehousing, OLAP), large-scale analytics
(MapReduce and beyond), query processing, data streams and real-time analysis. He has
published more than 30 articles at top conferences and journals, such as VLDB, ICDE, EDBT,
KDD, SIGMOD, Journal of Information Systems, Journal of Data and Knowledge Engineering and
elsewhere. His research work has influenced Microsoft’s SQL Server (query processor),
Oracle’s 8i and 9i Systems (Analytic Functions for OLAP, a benchmark for any BI system), and
ANSI SQL Standard (OLAP Amendment). There are more than 11 U.S. patents using Damianos’ research
work as primary reference (among these, 4 from Microsoft, 2 from IBM and 2 from Oracle) and
more than 150 citations to his work, including 9 data management textbooks.  He is currently
an Assistant Professor at Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), Department of
Management Science and Technology. Prior to AUEB, he has served as a tenure-track Assistant
Professor at Stevens Institute of Technology (September 1997-December 1999.)
&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/BR&gt;
Besides academia, Damianos has been involved in several technology startups. Panakea Software
Inc. (founder, 1998), based in New York City, developed and marketed database querying/reporting
technology to make certain analytic tasks (OLAP) easier to express and faster to evaluate. Clients
included Dun &amp;amp; Bradstreet, Columbia-Presbyterian Medical Center and Philips North America.
VoiceWeb SA (founder, 2001), based in Athens, focused on speech and telecom applications. VoiceWeb is
currently the leading company in the Balkans in speech-related applications. In 2011, Bank of Piraeus
acquired a stake at Voiceweb. Clients include Vodafone, Wind, Alpha Bank, Village Cinemas, Athens
Festival, etc. Damianos has served in 2007-2008 as a senior research consultant in Aster Data
Systems, a high-profile database technology startup based on Silicon Valley, dealing with distributed data
warehouses. Aster Data was acquired in March of 2011 by Teradata.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information please visit his
&lt;a href="http://dmst.aueb.gr/damianos/"&gt;personal web page&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2012</title><link href="/2012.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2012-10-25:2012.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Stavros - Trihias</title><link href="/stavros-trihias.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2012-10-01:stavros-trihias.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stavros Trihias&lt;/em&gt; has graduated from Athens University of Economics and Business, from the Department of Management Science and Technology. He is now a member of &lt;a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/"&gt;ISTLab&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; and has been working on "Fuzzer" research project.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>STEREO</title><link href="/stereo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2012-10-01:stereo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The project aims to provide an infrastructure that will facilitate research efforts by integrating
data collection, data processing in large-scale infrastructures, and dissemination of results.
In order to evaluate software quality,
data from Free/Libre/Open Source Software (FLOSS) projects will be used.
Such an infrastructure will consist of:
1) Software, enabling researchers to develop and run experiments efficiently on large data volumes,
along with a collection of readily available data processing, curating and analysis methods
2) Pre-processed data, from FLOSS projects, in a form that is suitable for analysis
3) A cloud based computation infrastructure, suitable for mass data processing.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2011</title><link href="/2011.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2011-10-25:2011.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>TRACER</title><link href="/tracer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2011-04-18:tracer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Legacy systems are likely to contain software vulnerabilities that can lead
to various security breaches. On the other hand, these systems contain valuable
information about the environment, the creation and the evolution of the
organization they support. For this reason, redesigning large systems in order
to be secure and compatible with new technologies is not a practical option,
since the information mentioned above could be lost. In addition the cost of replacing
such system and retrain its various users, could be prohibitive. In this project we
propose a framework that shields legacy systems based on two basic steps:
First, our framework analyzes the source code of the system to identify potential
software vulnerabilities and eliminates them. Then, depending on the previous
analysis the framework proposes solutions to protect
the system from the most common web-application attacks.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2010</title><link href="/2010.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2010-10-25:2010.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Iraklitos II</title><link href="/iraklitos-ii.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2010-09-01:iraklitos-ii.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Code injection attacks are one of the most damaging class of attacks because: they can occur in different layers, like databases, native code, applications, libraries and others; and they span a wide range of security and privacy issues, like viewing sensitive information, destruction or modification of sensitive data, or even stopping the execution of the entire application. Our research attempts to prevent a wide class of such attacks in a novel way.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Marios - Fragkoulis</title><link href="/marios-fragkoulis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2009-11-01:marios-fragkoulis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marios Fragkoulis&lt;/em&gt; holds a PhD in main memory data analytics from the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business. He has published in the European Conference of Computer Systems (EuroSys) and Springer's journal of Computing. Marios is the developer of the PiCO QL online data analytics system and co-developer of the directed acyclic graph shell (dgsh). He holds an MSc with distinction in Computer Science from the Department of Computing of the Imperial College London. Marios is a student member of the ACM and the EuroSys society and a member of the &lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group. His research interests regard data representations, big data management, computational and machine learning models, and software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was funded by Foundation Propondis.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2009</title><link href="/2009.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2009-10-25:2009.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Maria - Kechagia</title><link href="/maria-kechagia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2009-09-07:maria-kechagia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maria Kechagia&lt;/em&gt; is a PhD candidate at Athens University of Economics and Business, in the Department of Management Science and Technology. She holds a BSc in Management Science and Technology and an MSc in Computing (Software Engineering) from Imperial College London. She has participated in EU funded R&amp;amp;D projects. From October 2012 until November 2015 she was the project manager of the &lt;a href="../projects/p_stereo.html"&gt;STEREO&lt;/a&gt; project. She is an IEEE student and IEEE Women In Engineering (WIE) member, as well as an ACM student and ACM-Women (ACM-W) member. Her research interests include the design and implementation of Application Programming Interfaces (APIs) and the study of open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is a member of the &lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vaggelis - Giannikas</title><link href="/vaggelis-giannikas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2009-09-04:vaggelis-giannikas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vaggelis Giannikas&lt;/em&gt; holds a BSc in Management Science and Technology from the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB). He is currently a member of the &lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group. His research interests include open source software, software engineering and supply chain information systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also works at the European Project Unit of SingularLogic S.A. and collaborates with the ELTRUN, the e-business research center.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>PEVE (ΠΕΒΕ)</title><link href="/peve-pebe.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2009-03-01:peve-pebe.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Integrating Domain-Specific Languages with General-Purpose Languages&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Domain-specific languages (DSL) are small, usually declarative languages that focus
on a specific problem domain. SQL and regular expressions are two of the most
common DSL's. General-purpose languages (GPL) such as C, C++ and Java are
covering a wider application domain, but lack expressive power when applicable to
specific problems. Usually DSL's are implemented as external application libraries
when used by GPLs and the compiler is unaware of the DSL syntax and data types,
creating a series of problems in the software development process.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Our approach attempts to fill this scientific gap will introduce J% (j-mod), a DSL-aware
programming language. J% will be an extension of the Java programming language.
Its prototype implementation consists of a pre-processor, which translates the J%
source code to Java compatible code.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
The J% approach tries to give a more pragmatic approach to DSL integration. All
research efforts so far, have one of the following weaknesses:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;They deal with the problem for one DSL and for one GPL.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;They propose complex solutions that act as a burden to mainstream programming languages, obliging programmers to remember difficult semantics.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;They offer a new programming language that deals with the problem efficiently, but usually require a complete rewrite of complex DSL systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
In J% we will avoid the aforementioned weaknesses. In addition, we will address the
theoretical aspects of the problem, like possible type system extension etc.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
Our prototype implementation will have as target the Java programming language. As
a research result, we will provide a solid implementation and a more generalised
methodology that could guide the application of our techniques to other programming
languages like C and C++.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2008</title><link href="/2008.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2008-10-25:2008.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>2007</title><link href="/2007.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2007-10-25:2007.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Dimitris - Mitropoulos</title><link href="/dimitris-mitropoulos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2007-03-01:dimitris-mitropoulos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dimitris Mitropoulos&lt;/em&gt; is the Security Officer of the &lt;a href="https://grnet.gr/"&gt;Greek Research and Technology Network (GRNET)&lt;/a&gt;.
Dr. Mitropoulos holds a BSc in Informatics and Telecommunications from the National and Kapodistrian University of Athens,
and an MSc and a PhD in Cyber Security from the Athens University of Economics and Business. He has also been a Postdoctoral researcher at the &lt;a href="http://nsl.cs.columbia.edu/index.html"&gt;Network Security Laboratory (NSL)&lt;/a&gt; of Columbia University in the City of New York. He has worked in the industry as a software engineer and has been involved in several EU and US funded R&amp;amp;D projects. His research interests include application and system security, applied cryptography, software evolution and software engineering. He is a member of ACM, IEEE, &lt;a href="http://www.syssec-project.eu/community/members/"&gt;SysSec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.owasp.org/index.php/Greece"&gt;OWASP&lt;/a&gt;, and an official writer for the &lt;a href="http://xrds.acm.org/blog/?author=8"&gt;XRDS:Crossroads&lt;/a&gt; blog of ACM.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vasiliki - Efstathiou</title><link href="/vasiliki-efstathiou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2007-01-08:vasiliki-efstathiou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Vasiliki Efstathiou holds a PhD in Computer Science from University College London, an MSc in Computer Science from the same University and a BSc in Mathematics from the University of Crete. Her PhD thesis investigated automated theorem proving techniques for implementing computational argumentation based on classical logic. Her research interests lie in the wider area of knowledge representation and reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SOPRANO</title><link href="/soprano.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2007-01-01:soprano.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;SOPRANO aims to design a system that assists older people in coping with everyday life in greater comfort and safety, with integrated delivery of high quality support and care. The project also aims to help all Europeans to continue to live independently and play a full role in society. SOPRANO develops and adapts to normal home environments a sophisticated range of suitably unobtrusive components seamlessly linked to external service provision.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A major objective of SOPRANO is to take a leap forward in the way users can interact with and take charge of their living environment, as well as to develop the way professional care personnel can support the SOPRANO users when called on to do so. The SOPRANO system acts not as a traditional "smart home", passively receiving user commands, nor as pure "remote care", by alerting outside staff to act in case of an alarm. Instead, SOPRANO acts as an informed, friendly agent, taking orders, giving advice or reminders and ready to help, and get help when needed.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2006</title><link href="/2006.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2006-10-25:2006.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>S-OMA SMART CARDS</title><link href="/s-oma-smart-cards.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2006-10-01:s-oma-smart-cards.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The S-OMA Smart Cards project aims to exploit the technological
opportunities arising from recent evolutions in the areas of secure
smart cards. Moreover, the S-OMA SMART CARDS project will identify and
propose best practices and methodologies regarding the design and
testing of secure tamper-resistant multipurpose smart cards. Significant
effort will be put towards the best utilization of the available
resources and the enhancement of portability between different smart
card technologies.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>eBusinessForum - Working Group IA4</title><link href="/ebusinessforum-working-group-ia4.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2006-09-10:ebusinessforum-working-group-ia4.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
    ISTLab/SENSE Members participate actively in E-Business Forum. In particular, working group IA4 focused its attention in the area of "Preliminary Actions for the Establishment of the Greek Computer Emergency Response Team (GR-CERT)".&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;GR-CERT is an initiative, which aims to provide timely notifications regarding software vulnerabilities, malware epidemics and fraud schemes.

The IA4 working group focuses on non experts and SMEs not employing technical personnel  and therefore all the necessary information is provided in a simple and understandable manner for the average user.

Results will be published in the form of reports and will be presented in a workshop.
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Markos - Gogoulos</title><link href="/markos-gogoulos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2006-09-01:markos-gogoulos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Markos Gogoulos&lt;/em&gt; is a research associate of the &lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group and a former member of the &lt;a href="http://www.islab.demokritos.gr"&gt;ISLAB group&lt;/a&gt; in N.C.S.R. Demokritos. He holds a Diploma in Information and Communication Systems Engineering from the University of the Aegean. His research interests include applied security and operating systems hardening, network attack analysis, operating systems and networking.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>SQO-OSS</title><link href="/sqo-oss.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2006-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2006-09-01:sqo-oss.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What do we know about the quality of the software you are using?  A well-known conjecture 
in software engineering is that external quality characteristics are correlated to internal quality 
characteristics and thus the measurement of source code provides useful data for the 
assessment of its quality. Uniquely, open source software allows us to examine the actual 
code and perform white box testing and analysis of it. In most open source projects we can 
also access their version control system, mailing lists and issue databases.  We can use these 
data sources to extract quality indicators through techniques, such as data mining. 
SQO-OSS aims to increase the competitiveness of European software development SMEs 
through a holistic approach of software quality assessment, initially targeting open source 
software. The project seeks to use as many sources of quality indicators as possible so as to 
create a set of metrics that can be applied automatically to a software project’s repository in 
order to extract quantifiable measurements of its quality.  The project will deliver:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A plug-in based quality assessment platform, featuring a web and an idE front-end.
An enhanced set of software metrics that will take into account quality indicators from data that is present in a project’s repository, but not yet used for quality assessment.
A publicly available league of open source software applications, categorised by their quality characteristics.
A methodology that will allow European SMEs to leverage the availability of quality-assessed open source software in the development of horizontal and vertical applications and the provision of value-added services.
Experience reports of how the tool’s application affected a large open source project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project leverages existing tools and will also create new ones in an effort to build an
integrated quality assessment platform. The core will be released as open source software 
under the BSD licence to stimulate business interest around it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Konstantinos - Stroggylos</title><link href="/konstantinos-stroggylos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2005-11-10:konstantinos-stroggylos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Markos Gogoulos&lt;/em&gt; is a research associate of the &lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group and a former member of the &lt;a href="http://www.islab.demokritos.gr"&gt;ISLAB group&lt;/a&gt; in N.C.S.R. Demokritos. He holds a Diploma in Information and Communication Systems Engineering from the University of the Aegean. His research interests include applied security and operating systems hardening, network attack analysis, operating systems and networking.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2005</title><link href="/2005.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2005-10-25:2005.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>PENED</title><link href="/pened.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-09-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2005-09-01:pened.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;On-line business transaction processing systems have so far been based on centralized or client-server architectures. It is our firm belief and
it has also been recognized by the research and industrial community–that such systems may also be based on the constantly evolving decentralized
peer-to-peer architectures, as current peer-to-peer technology has evolved to the extent that it is able to fulfill many of these requirements
to a large extent. The aim of the project is the research and design of eBusiness transaction processing systems based on entirely decentralised
 peer-to-peer architectures, based on a detailed requirements definition and analysis. The proposed design will cover issues such as support
for discovery of services, merchandise or trading parties; authentication and access control, and negotiating collaboration parameters;
support for workflow and collaboration orchestration, logging and non-repudiation; user ranking and reputation management; various other
generic non-functional requirements including security, availability and anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Panos (Panagiotis) - Louridas</title><link href="/panos-panagiotis-louridas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2005-01-01:panos-panagiotis-louridas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panos (Panagiotis) Louridas&lt;/em&gt; holds an MSc by Research and a PhD in Computation from the University of Manchester Institute of Science and Technology (UMIST). He is a consultant at the Greek Research &amp;amp; Technology Network, focusing on electronic infrastructures. Prior to that he has worked as a Software Engineer in the banking sector, developing applications using open source software, and as a consultant in various European projects. His research interests include Software Engineering, Software Design, and Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Louridas is a member of the ACM, the IEEE, and the AAAS. He is the recipient of a cheque by Donald Knuth.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Georgios - Gousios</title><link href="/georgios-gousios.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2004-11-15:georgios-gousios.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Georgios Gousios&lt;/em&gt; holds an MSc with distinction from the University of Manchester, UK and a PhD from the Athens University of Economics and Business,GR, both on Software Engineering. He has worked as a researcher in several national and international research projects and provided consulting services in both multinational and emerging startup companies. He was the project manager, lead designer and top source code contributor of the SQO-OSS project, an FP6 funded project that produced novel tools for facilitating research in the field of software engineering. He has published more that 10 papers in various fields and also co-edited the "Beautiful Architectures" book (OReilly, 2009). His research interests include empirical software engineering, software architectures and systems level software. He is a member of the ACM, the IEEE, Usenix and the technical chamber of Greece.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2004</title><link href="/2004.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2004-10-25:2004.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>EDUPORTAL</title><link href="/eduportal.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2004-03-01:eduportal.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Eduportal is a unified portal allowing access to academic information
and content regarding undergraduate and graduate course curricula.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
It is opeational since March 2004, and currently hosts the DMST
undergraduate Degree courses, the International MBA Courses and the
Graduate Programme in Human Resources Management (MSc) Courses. It can
be seamlessly expanded to cover other courses, without the need for
software or hardware updates.
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
A powerful "back-office" allows the teaching staff to individually:
provide information about their courses, the teaching and laboratory
support stuff, contact information etc; structure their courses,
lectures and laboratories; upload material to be made available to the
students; post announcements; etc.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Giorgos - Zervas</title><link href="/giorgos-zervas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2004-01-01:giorgos-zervas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Giorgos Zervas&lt;/em&gt; holds an MSc in Advanced Computing and a BEng in Computing both from Imperial College (University of London, UK) and an MA in Interactive Multimedia from the London College of Printing (London Institute). His research interests include Information Retrieval, Distributed Computing and Open Source Software. He is the author of the open source &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.perlfect.com/freescripts/search"&gt;Perlfect Search&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; search engine.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Stefanos - Androutsellis-Theotokis</title><link href="/stefanos-androutsellis-theotokis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2003-11-14:stefanos-androutsellis-theotokis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Androutsellis-Theotokis was born in Athens, Greece, in 1970. He holds a B.Eng in Information Systems Engineering, an M.Sc. in Engineering and Physical Sciences in Medicine both from Imperial College (University of London, UK), an M.S.E. in Biomedical Engineering from Johns Hopkins University, MD, US, and a Ph.D. from the Athens University of Economics and Business. He has worked in the industry as a software analyst and developer and has been involved in several EU funded R&amp;amp;D projects. Dr. Androutsellis-Theotokis is a member of the Technical Chamber of Greece and the IEEE. His research interests include Information Security, Peer-to-Peer architectures and Software Engineering, and his current doctoral research concerns the design of transaction processing systems based on peer-to-peer architectures.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vasileios - Vlachos</title><link href="/vasileios-vlachos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2003-11-14:vasileios-vlachos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Vasileios Vlachos was born in Athens, Greece, in 1976. He holds a Dipl.-El.-Eng. (Comp. Eng.) (Diploma of Engineering, a 5 date Degree which is equivalent to British and Greek MSc Degrees) in Electronic &amp;amp; Computer Engineering from Technical University of Crete , Greece and a MSc in Integrated Hardware and Software Systems from the Department of Computer Engineering and Informatics of the University of Patras , Greece. His Master's Thesis was completed at the Interuniversity MicroElectronics Center (IMEC), Leuven, Belgium. Dr. Vlachos also holds a Ph.D. degree in Information Systems Security (specialization on Computer Virology, Thesis title: Security Applications of Peer to Peer Networks) from the Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens University of Economics and Business (2007). He is a member of ISTLab/SENSE for the last 5 dates. During his studies he obtained a number of scholarships from several foundations and worked in several national and European projects. Dr. Vlachos is a member of IEEE, and IEEE Computer Society, member of the Technical Chamber of Greece, and the Hellenic Association of Computer Engineers. His research interests include: Computer Virology, Computer Epidemiology, Peer to Peer Networks and Open Source Software.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vassilios - Karakoidas</title><link href="/vassilios-karakoidas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2003-11-14:vassilios-karakoidas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Vassilios Karakoidas&lt;/em&gt; holds a BSc in Informatics (University of Piraeus), a MSc in Information Systems (Athens of Economics and Business) and a PhD in Programming Languages (Athens University of Economics and Business). He is now a member of &lt;a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/"&gt;ISTLab&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; and a former member of the Health Informatics Laboratory at University of Piraeus. He has been involved in various research projects. The most recent are &lt;a href="../projects/p_gemini.html"&gt;GEMINI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="../projects/p_praxis.html"&gt;PRAXIS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="../projects/p_sqo-oss.html"&gt;SQO-OSS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="../projects/p_tracer.html"&gt;TRACER&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="../projects/p_stereo.html"&gt;STEREO&lt;/a&gt; In 2008, he co-founded Wizhut, a software company that was involved with various software development projects. He was leading the design and the implementation effort of &lt;a href="http://www.warp.ly/"&gt;warp.ly&lt;/a&gt; mobile marketing platform. He worked part-time with the &lt;a href="http://www.totaleclipsegames.com/"&gt;Total Eclipse&lt;/a&gt; development team and he was the lead software architect at Emaginal AG. He is the author of a number of open-source and public-domain software packages and tools. His research interests include Software Engineering, Programming Languages, Operating Systems and Networking. He has published more than 25 scientific articles in refereed scientific journals and conferences.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2003</title><link href="/2003.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2003-10-25:2003.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>PRAXIS</title><link href="/praxis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2003-10-01:praxis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The aim of the project is the interconnection of commercial applications
and the conduct of inter-business transactions through the internet,
based on open standards. The resulting system will allow companies to
carry out business transactions through the internet in an ad-hoc
manner, minimizing the paperwork required. The system design will
utilize know-how and standards based on the Extensible Markup Language
(XML), such as ebXML, allows the effective design of e-business
applications based on data interchange.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Iraklitos</title><link href="/iraklitos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-11-08:iraklitos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;During the last years several worm epidemics have emerged as major threats to critical digital infrastructures.
To make large-scale networks more resilient against these kind of threats, we evaluate the usage of peer-to-peer architectures whereby each peer is responsible for
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detecting whether a virus or worm is uncontrollably propagating through the network resulting in an epidemic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically dispatching warnings and information to other peers of a security-focused group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking specific precautions for their host by automatically hardening their security measures during the epidemic.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>2002</title><link href="/2002.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-10-25:2002.html</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>TEMPO</title><link href="/tempo.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-03-26T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-03-26:tempo.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The TEMPO project aims to:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Support the Hellenic Organization of Telecommunications national IP network and to address issues regarding it's further upgrading.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Utilize the MPLS technology for the provision of Quality of Service (QoS) applications over IP networks
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Provide and support service level agreements (SLAs)
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Demonstrate services to customers (pre-sales support) and to present potential scenarios of Classes of Services
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        Support the Hellenic Organization of Telecommunications international IP network and to address issues regarding it's further upgrading
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>mExpress</title><link href="/mexpress.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-03-05:mexpress.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;mEXPRESS aims to exploit the technological opportunities arising from
evolution in the areas of wireless networks and positioning mechanisms in
order to support and facilitate the professional exhibition industry in
a context-aware manner. It will contribute to the economic development of
the Community by providing means for efficient operation and interaction
in information-rich environments such as exhibitions, and significantly
enhancing promotional activities and business communications. The mEXPRESS
project will provide an integrated mediation platform (mEXPRESS Service
Provider) oriented to exhibition shows and events that will satisfy
three types of objectives:
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enhance and facilitate visitors experience in terms of interaction and functionality in an information-rich environment such as an exhibition show.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Improve business communications and promotions within the exhibition and extend promotional effectiveness during and after the exhibition&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Assist and support exhibition management and operations by offering real-time location information of persons within the exhibition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>TRAINSEE</title><link href="/trainsee.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-02-01:trainsee.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Train-SEE aims to develop a corporate e-learning environment for ICT skill development based on generic ICT skill profiles and targeted to the SE European market. The Athens University of Economics and Business helped in conducting training needs assessment in the market of SE Europe, was responsible for the preparation and delivery of the content in appropriate form, and helped in the evaluation and usability testing of the implemented training service.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Diomidis - Spinellis</title><link href="/diomidis-spinellis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-01-01:diomidis-spinellis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diomidis Spinellis&lt;/strong&gt; is a Professor in the Department of Management Science and Technology at the Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece.  His research interests include software engineering, IT security, and  cloud systems engineering.  He has written two award-winning, widely-translated books: “&lt;em&gt;Code Reading&lt;/em&gt;” and “&lt;em&gt;Code Quality: The Open Source Perspective&lt;/em&gt;”.  Dr. Spinellis has also published more than 250 technical papers in journals and refereed conference proceedings, which have received more than 5000 citations.  He served for a decade as a member of the &lt;em&gt;IEEE Software&lt;/em&gt; editorial board, authoring the regular “Tools of the Trade” column.  He has contributed code that ships with Apple’s macOS and BSD Unix and is the developer of &lt;em&gt;CScout&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;UMLGraph&lt;/em&gt; and other open-source software packages, libraries, and tools.  He holds an MEng in Software Engineering and a PhD in Computer Science, both from Imperial College London.  Dr. Spinellis has served as an elected member of the IEEE Computer Society Board of Governors (2013–2015), and is a senior member of the ACM and the IEEE. From January 2015 he is serving as the Editor-in-Chief for IEEE Software.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>eAware</title><link href="/eaware.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-01-01:eaware.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;eAWARe aims to educate the everyday Internet user about online risks and the
steps users can take to protect themselves. eAWARe reaches out to the public
through local events across Europe. We will also produce a free guide on how to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;have and host your own event to promote information security awareness. eAWARe
is supported by the Directorate General for Research of the European
Commission. eAWARe will hold its final international conference during the
first week of November 2003 in Rome, Italy. This event is part of the European
Commission's initiatives in the context of European Science Week. eAWARe also
supports the dissemination of the OECD Guidelines for Information and Network
Security.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>GEMINI</title><link href="/gemini.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-01-01:gemini.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;GEMNINI aims to explore the opportunities deriving from the convergence of different mass media (Digital Television, Internet, Newspapers, etc.), the ability to transfer digital content fast, accurately and at low cost, and the existence of several potential suppliers and customers. The project will contribute to the economic development of the European market by providing means for the initialization, development and maintenance of a dynamic constellation delivering value to all the participants in the media and entertainment sectors. The project introduces value-adding services to consumers by providing access to a large repository of (re-usable) content, based upon viewers’ requests and needs. In addition, GEMINI will pave the ground for additional interactive services related to provision of content in irrespective of format or type in a user-friendly manner. Specifically, the GEMINI project will develop an integrated mediation platform offering enhanced content services to viewers of sports events.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Victoria - Skoularidou</title><link href="/victoria-skoularidou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-01-01:victoria-skoularidou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mrs. Skoularidou was born in Athens, Greece, in 1973. She holds a BSc in Applied Informatics and an MSc in Information Systems both from AUEB (Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece). During her studies she obtained a number of scholarships from several foundations and worked in projects funded by the General Secretariat of Research and Technology (GSRT) and the European Union (EU) including DEDICS (Telematics Applications Programme, EC-DG XIII), and PENED (Project No 339). Since January 2002 she is pursuing her PhD Thesis in the Department of Management Science and Technology (DMST) of AUEB, in the area of Computer/Information Security.&lt;br /&gt;
From July 1995 till December 1995 she was employed as Computer Programmer/Analyst and IT seminars instructor in the IT department of SIGNON Ltd.&lt;br /&gt;
From January 1998 till February 2003 she worked as Information Systems Analyst/Systems Engineer and later on as Technical/Project Manager in the Development Programmes Department of INTRACOM S.A, Greece directly involved in research projects funded by the EU. She participated in the co-operative research projects HyNoDe (EP 22160), and DiVAN (EP 24956) and co-ordinated projects related to e-business/e-commerce services including ACTIVE, iMEDIA, ACTIVE SME, MUSICAL . Mrs. Skoularidou has also participated in, and coordinated the proposal preparation and submission for a number of IT projects funded by the EU.&lt;br /&gt;
From March 2003 till May 2003 she worked as Senior Software Developer in the IT Department of ONIA-NET Electronic Transactions S.A, Greece.&lt;br /&gt;
Since June 2003 she is a Researcher in the ELTRUN e-Business Center of AUEB involved in the EU dissemination project eAWARe.&lt;br /&gt;
Mrs. Skoularidou is a member of the ACM, the IEEE Computer Society, and the Greek Computer Society. She has published a number of research papers in International Journals and Conferences and is also a Reviewer for professional submittals. Her research interests include: Information and Communication Systems Security, Network Security, Computer Security, Mobile Code Security, Application and Software Security, Security and Privacy in E-Business/E-Commerce, and Mobile and TV Commerce.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>CONTESSA</title><link href="/contessa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2001-06-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2001-06-15:contessa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;CONTESSA aims to transform the content creation and distribution industry by
allowing content to be automatically and cost effectively adapted
to any requesting device (PC, smart phones, mobile phones, PDAs, DTV
set-top-boxes, etc.) seamlessly over any network infrastructure. The
main objectives of CONTESSA are:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a content transformation engine that will provide translation
and integration of content into device-tailored user interfaces through
alternative communication channels. The system will track and manage
alternative access devices while providing a personalized environment
for content deployment based on a standardized XML framework that will
allow the content to be extracted, converted and integrated, without
the creator's interference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Validate the system through a number of interactive transactional
services to be delivered over multiple types of networks, to devices
using different access protocols enabling e-Commerce and e-Business
widespread application.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>myGrocer</title><link href="/mygrocer.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2001-01-01:mygrocer.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
MyGROCER is a research project
partially funded by the European Commission (IST Programme). The project
spanned over two years (from January 2001 to November 2002) and exploited the
potential of wireless technologies (namely Wireless LANs) and automatic product
identification techniques (Radio Frequency identification, RF-id) to develop
an innovative business and technological solution for the retail environment. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;

In effect, MyGROCER implemented
and field-tested a new and integrated shopping scheme
that supports the shopper throughout his/her entire supermarket visit by means
of a prototype shopping cart capable to automatically scan supermarket products
while at the same time provide valuable information to the shopper through a display
device thus, create a fully interactive shopping trip. The use of the system by
supermarket shoppers revealed that the new shopping scheme can provide a more
entertaining and efficient shopping trip compared to the conventional way of
shopping, and thus generate new shopping experiences. &lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Web</title><link href="/web.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2001-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2001-01-01:web.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Web site&lt;/em&gt; project aims to create a dynamic,
distributed, and maintanable Web site for ISTLab.
&lt;br/&gt;
Traditionally, the realization of Web sites involves either
static content developed using web authoring tools like
Microsoft's Front Page and DreamWeaver, or dynamic
content delivered by a database driven front-end,
where the structured content is organized
in a relational schema and dynamically generated on the fly.
When our group faced the successive failure of both the above approaches,
we decided to adopt the task of exploring ideas for a radically different
implementation style, based on the declarative specification
of all the site's elements.
We believe that our approach and many of the lessons we learned
can be applied numerous similar situations,
leading to a lightweight, structured, consistent, and maintainable
web site building method.
&lt;br/&gt;
The guiding principles behind our design are:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Openness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Observability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robustness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parsimony&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>