<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>A Pelican Blog</title><link href="/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="/feeds/members.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>/</id><updated>2017-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated><entry><title>Ioannis -- Mourtos</title><link href="/ioannis-mourtos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-10-20:ioannis-mourtos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yiannis Mourtos&lt;/strong&gt; is an Associate Professor in "Mathematics of Operations Research" at the Department of Management Science &amp;amp; Technology, Athens University of Economics and Business. He studied Computer Engineering and Informatics at the corresponding department of the University of Patras and obtained both his MSc and PhD from the Operational Research Department, London School of Economics and Political Science. He has worked as a Lecturer at the Department of Economics, University of Patras.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His research is focused in the areas of Combinatorial Optimisation and Integer Programming, examining also the integration of Integer Programming with Constraint Programming algorithms. He has published in Operations Research journals like Mathematical Programming, Mathematics of Operations Research, INFORMS Journal on Computing, SIAM Journal on Discrete Mathematics Operations Research Letters, European Journal of Operational Research and Discrete Mathematics, for several of which he has served as a reviewer. He has also participated in national and European research projects, in most of them as a Scientific Coordinator.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>George - Metaxopoulos</title><link href="/george-metaxopoulos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-10-15:george-metaxopoulos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;George Metaxopoulos&lt;/strong&gt; is an undergraduate student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB) in the Department of Management Science and Technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is an active member of JA Alumni Greece since 2013, being the Financial Planning Manager of the Organization since 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His main research interests involve Software Security and Privacy.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Stefanos - Chaliaso</title><link href="/stefanos-chaliaso.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-10-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-10-15:stefanos-chaliaso.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stefanos Chaliasos&lt;/strong&gt; is an undergraduate student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB) in the Department of Management Science and Technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His research interests are in the areas of Security and Privacy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is a member of the &lt;a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/"&gt;ISTLab&lt;/a&gt; group.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Anastasia - Griva</title><link href="/anastasia-griva.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-09-07:anastasia-griva.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anastasia Griva&lt;/strong&gt; is PhD Candidate at the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business. Apart from Business Analytics Lab (BALab), she is also researcher in the SCORE research group of the ELTRUN Research Center, where she participates in projects funded by the EU (UTURN, SERAMIS) and other projects that require a close cooperation with the retail industry. Her specializations are retail analytics and data mining. The context of her PhD involves pattern identification in customer’s visits that reveal their shopping missions. To this end, different data sources, such as POS data, RFID data, Google Analytics, web transactions and data derived from other sensor devices, are processed and combined to provide insights regarding the shopper behavior. Moreover, she holds a BSc in Management Science and Technology with a specialization in Quantitative Methods in Economics and Management, and an MSc (with honors) in Information Systems, both from the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB). Furthermore, she has attended the seminar “Big Data and Business Analytics” provided by the Executive Training Center of AUEB. In general, her research interests lie in the areas of Business Analytics, Retail Analytics, IoT Analytics, Customer behavior, Data Mining, and Marketing Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Ioannis Batas</title><link href="/ioannis-batas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-19:ioannis-batas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Ioannis Batas is an undergraduate student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB) in the Department of Management Science and Technology and an Erasmus student at Southern Denmark University (SDU)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Ioannis has a passion for tech-related startups; being co-founder of MyPharmacy, TripSleep, Instashop and Yayaka and mentor at Junior Achievement. Furthermore, he gets involved in many social activities; being in the Organizing Committee of TEDxAcademy, Athens Startup Weekend University and DMST Student Conference and member of AIESEC.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Since the first year of university, Ioannis has acquired fundamental programming skills (programming languages, data structures and web frameworks) and has developed several web applications.
&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Efstathia Chioteli</title><link href="/efstathia-chioteli.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-08-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-08-18:efstathia-chioteli.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
 Efstathia Chioteli is an undergraduate student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), in the Department of Management Science and Technology and an Erasmus student at the The Hague University of Applied sciences.
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the first year of university she got involved with entrepreneurship by participating in some contests like Startup Weekend University, entrepreneurship school etc starting her own startup called Yayaka.gr, an online platform of searching and evaluation of professionals’ caregivers for elderly. 
 Beyond her love for startups and innovation, she also loves coding and web development. In addition to the knowledge given to her by the university she also develops her skills on coding in her free time, doing some projects and learning new programming languages, frameworks, tools etc
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Theodore - Stassinopoulos</title><link href="/theodore-stassinopoulos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2017-04-28:theodore-stassinopoulos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theodore Stassinopoulos&lt;/em&gt; is a PhD candidate in AUEB (Athens University of Economics and Business) and currently works on CROSSMINER project. Holds an MSc in theoretical mathematics from University of Athens and a BSc in mathematics from the saeme university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His research interests lie at algorithm design and analysis, design patterns and best practices for clean code.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Nikiforos - Botis</title><link href="/nikiforos-botis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-10-25:nikiforos-botis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Nikiforos Botis holds a Bachelor’s degree with distinction from the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB). At January 2016, Nikiforos was admitted at University College London (UCL), in the department of Management Science and Innovation as part of the Erasmus+ program, where he spent the 6th semester of his undergraduate studies. At March 2016, Nikiforos participated in the InnoJam++ @CeBIT 2016 co-organized by SAP and Volkswagen in Hanover, a 32-hour hands-on experience in the latest technologies that are utilized by SAP, following his excellence at the SAP ERP labs which took place in the university (scoring at the 2.5% of the class). In his last year at AUEB, he worked as a Research and Development Intern in the Dutch consultancy company Software Improvement Group, under the supervision of Dr. Yiannis Kanellopoulos. During his internship, Nikiforos developed a new way to holistically depict an Information System, named Information System Canvas. Currently, he is a postgraduate student at Imperial College London, pursuing a Master’s degree at Computer Science. He has been awarded two scholarships (from the General Michael Arnaoutis Foundation and the Greek State Scholarship Foundation) in order to fund his studies. Nikiforos has joined the SENSE (currently BA) group in March 2016 and the OIS group in October 2016 as a research assistant.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vitalis - Salis</title><link href="/vitalis-salis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-07-15:vitalis-salis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vitalis Salis&lt;/em&gt; is a student at the National Technical University of Athens (NTUA), Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is a software engineer on the Greek Research and Technology Network (GRNET), working on &lt;a href="https://www.synnefo.org/"&gt;Synnefo&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://okeanos.grnet.gr/home/"&gt;~okeanos&lt;/a&gt;. Previously he's worked on multiple personal projects, most notably &lt;a href="https://github.com/dionyziz/ting"&gt;ting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Alexander - Lattas</title><link href="/alexander-lattas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-07-12:alexander-lattas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alexandros Lattas&lt;/strong&gt; is a postgraduate Advanced Computing student in Imperial College London, with an academic interest in Machine Learning, Security and Entrepreneurship. He holds a BSc in Management Science and Technology from Athens University of Economics and Business and has been an Innovation Management affiliate student at University College London. Alexandros has been a Security Consultant Intern at Oracle and a Co-Founder and Board Member at Junior Achievement Alumni Greece. He has been awarded the Hellenic Petroleum scholarship, the Social Impact Award (2014), the Junior Achievement Company Programme Award (2012), three honorary distinctions from Athens University of Economics and Business and one from the Greek Ministry of Education and has participated in the Edutrip 2016 program at UC Berkeley. Full CV is available at http://cv.lattas.eu. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vasilis - Stavrou</title><link href="/vasilis-stavrou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2016-05-11T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2016-05-11:vasilis-stavrou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vasilis Stavrou&lt;/strong&gt; is PhD Candidate at the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics 
and Business. Apart from Business Analytics Lab, he is also researcher in the SCORE team of the ELTRUN Research Center, where he 
participates in projects funded by the EU (SERAMIS) and other projects of the private sector that require cooperation with the retail 
industry. His research areas are IoT and Business Analytics while his PhD examines the leveraging of indoor positioning techniques to 
support decision making in the retail context. In the last years he has also worked as a researcher has publications in the area of 
Social Media Intelligence. He holds a diploma degree in Computer Engineering from University of Patras and an MSc (with honors) in 
Information Systems from Athens University of Economics and Business. His interests focus on Business Analytics, Business Intelligence, 
Shopper Behavior, Data Mining and Machine Learning. &lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Antonios - Gkortzis</title><link href="/antonios-gkortzis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-12-20:antonios-gkortzis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Antonios Gkortzis&lt;/em&gt; is a PhD Candidate at the SENECA (http://senecaproject.github.io/) project. The reasearch topic of this industrial PhD position is "Secure Systems on Cloud Computing Infrastructures" and is offered by Singular Logic, the Athens University of Economics and Bussiness, and the King Juan Carlos University. He holds a BSc in Information Technology Engineering from the Alexandreio Technological Educational Institute of Thessaloniki and a Master Degree in Computing Science (Software Engineering and Distributed Systems) from the University of Gronignen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His main research interests are: Cloud Computing, Security, Software Engineering, Software Quality Assurance and Code Analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His current PhD position is founded by Marie Skłodowska-Curie from the framework Horizon 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Stefanos - Georgiou</title><link href="/stefanos-georgiou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-12-16:stefanos-georgiou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stefanos Georgiou&lt;/em&gt; is a PhD Candidate in SENECA (Software ENineering in Enterprise Cloud Applications) project.&lt;br /&gt;
In the context of his European Industrial Doctorate (Eid) he is expected to conduct his research at&lt;br /&gt;
AUEB (Athens University of Economics and Business) and TU Deflt (Delft University) as academic partners&lt;br /&gt;
and with SLG (Singular Logic) as industrial partner.&lt;br /&gt;
He holds a BSc in Networks and Systems Programming from University of Cyprus and a MSc in PERCCOM&lt;br /&gt;
(PERvasive Computing and COMmunications for sustainable development), a joint Master Degree from four&lt;br /&gt;
different Universities (i.e., University of Lorraine, Lappeenranta University of Technology, Lulea University of Technology,&lt;br /&gt;
and ITMO University of Saint Petersburg).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His research interests lie at Green IT, Cloud Computing, Distributed Applications,Big Data Transfer,&lt;br /&gt;
and IoT (Internet of Things)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His current PhD position is founded by Marie Sklodowska-Curie from framework Horizon 2020.&lt;br /&gt;
As a PhD is to provide energy-efficient approach on cloud computing systems using software&lt;br /&gt;
engineering techniques and practices.&lt;br /&gt;
However, in the context of his industrial PhD position task like writing proposals&lt;br /&gt;
, such as RIA (Research Innovation Action) is one of his duties in SLG.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Tushar - Sharma</title><link href="/tushar-sharma.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-12-14:tushar-sharma.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tushar Sharma&lt;/em&gt; is a researcher and PhD candidate at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), Department of Management Science and Technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier, he worked with &lt;em&gt;Siemens Research and Technology Center&lt;/em&gt;, Bangalore, India for more than 7 years. The topics related to software design and architecture, refactoring, code smells, code quality, and technical debt define his career interests. He has an MS (by research) degree in Computer Science from the Indian Institute of Technology-Madras (IIT-M), Chennai, India, where he specialised in design patterns and refactoring. He co-authored the book &lt;em&gt;"Refactoring for Software Design Smells: Managing Technical Debt"&lt;/em&gt; published by Morgan Kaufmann in November 2014. Additionally, he has also co-authored books for Oracle certifications for Java. He is an IEEE Senior Member.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Thodoris - Sotiropoulos</title><link href="/thodoris-sotiropoulos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2015-11-05:thodoris-sotiropoulos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thodoris Sotiropoulos&lt;/em&gt; is an undergraduate student at the Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens University of Economics and Business. He is a member of &lt;a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/content/groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group. He is currently working at the Greek Research &amp;amp; Technology Network (GRNET) as a software engineer and he has participated in two research projects in the fields of a) Security and Privancy, b) Machine Learning and Information Retrieval.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Christos - Oikonomou</title><link href="/christos-oikonomou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2014-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2014-01-15:christos-oikonomou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Christos Oikonomou&lt;/em&gt; is a student at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), Department of Management Science and Technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the summer of 2013, he helped in a research project regarding the evolution of prices at the Greek Ministry for Development and Competitiveness, under the supervision of &lt;a href="http://www.kepe.gr/index.php/el/profil-cb/userprofile/pjprodr"&gt;Dr. Prodromidis&lt;/a&gt;, presented the results at the eleventh &lt;a href="http://fsdet.dmst.aueb.gr/"&gt;DMST Conference&lt;/a&gt; (13/05/2014); and tutored (TAed) certain microeconomic and macroeconomic review sessions for the freshmen class of 2013-14 at the request of &lt;a href="http://www.kepe.gr/index.php/el/profil-cb/userprofile/pjprodr"&gt;Dr. Prodromidis&lt;/a&gt;. Also he has worked in extensive software systems under supervision of &lt;a href="http://www.spinellis.gr/index.html.var"&gt;Dr. Diomidis Spinellis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Damianos - Chatziantoniou</title><link href="/damianos-chatziantoniou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2013-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2013-02-19:damianos-chatziantoniou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Damianos Chatziantoniou received his B.Sc. in Applied Mathematics from the University of
Athens (June 1991, summa cum laude) and continued his studies in Computer Science at
Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences of New York University (M.Sc., Dec. 1992) and
Columbia University (M.Phil., Feb. 1996, Ph.D., June 1997). His academic research interests
include big data, business intelligence (data warehousing, OLAP), large-scale analytics
(MapReduce and beyond), query processing, data streams and real-time analysis. He has
published more than 30 articles at top conferences and journals, such as VLDB, ICDE, EDBT,
KDD, SIGMOD, Journal of Information Systems, Journal of Data and Knowledge Engineering and
elsewhere. His research work has influenced Microsoft’s SQL Server (query processor),
Oracle’s 8i and 9i Systems (Analytic Functions for OLAP, a benchmark for any BI system), and
ANSI SQL Standard (OLAP Amendment). There are more than 11 U.S. patents using Damianos’ research
work as primary reference (among these, 4 from Microsoft, 2 from IBM and 2 from Oracle) and
more than 150 citations to his work, including 9 data management textbooks.  He is currently
an Assistant Professor at Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), Department of
Management Science and Technology. Prior to AUEB, he has served as a tenure-track Assistant
Professor at Stevens Institute of Technology (September 1997-December 1999.)
&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/BR&gt;&lt;BR&gt;&lt;/BR&gt;
Besides academia, Damianos has been involved in several technology startups. Panakea Software
Inc. (founder, 1998), based in New York City, developed and marketed database querying/reporting
technology to make certain analytic tasks (OLAP) easier to express and faster to evaluate. Clients
included Dun &amp;amp; Bradstreet, Columbia-Presbyterian Medical Center and Philips North America.
VoiceWeb SA (founder, 2001), based in Athens, focused on speech and telecom applications. VoiceWeb is
currently the leading company in the Balkans in speech-related applications. In 2011, Bank of Piraeus
acquired a stake at Voiceweb. Clients include Vodafone, Wind, Alpha Bank, Village Cinemas, Athens
Festival, etc. Damianos has served in 2007-2008 as a senior research consultant in Aster Data
Systems, a high-profile database technology startup based on Silicon Valley, dealing with distributed data
warehouses. Aster Data was acquired in March of 2011 by Teradata.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information please visit his
&lt;a href="http://dmst.aueb.gr/damianos/"&gt;personal web page&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Stavros - Trihias</title><link href="/stavros-trihias.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2012-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2012-10-01:stavros-trihias.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Stavros Trihias&lt;/em&gt; has graduated from Athens University of Economics and Business, from the Department of Management Science and Technology. He is now a member of &lt;a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/"&gt;ISTLab&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; and has been working on "Fuzzer" research project.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Marios - Fragkoulis</title><link href="/marios-fragkoulis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2009-11-01:marios-fragkoulis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Marios Fragkoulis&lt;/em&gt; holds a PhD in main memory data analytics from the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business. He has published in the European Conference of Computer Systems (EuroSys) and Springer's journal of Computing. Marios is the developer of the PiCO QL online data analytics system and co-developer of the directed acyclic graph shell (dgsh). He holds an MSc with distinction in Computer Science from the Department of Computing of the Imperial College London. Marios is a student member of the ACM and the EuroSys society and a member of the &lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group. His research interests regard data representations, big data management, computational and machine learning models, and software engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He was funded by Foundation Propondis.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Maria - Kechagia</title><link href="/maria-kechagia.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2009-09-07:maria-kechagia.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maria Kechagia&lt;/em&gt; is a PhD candidate at Athens University of Economics and Business, in the Department of Management Science and Technology. She holds a BSc in Management Science and Technology and an MSc in Computing (Software Engineering) from Imperial College London. She has participated in EU funded R&amp;amp;D projects. From October 2012 until November 2015 she was the project manager of the &lt;a href="../projects/p_stereo.html"&gt;STEREO&lt;/a&gt; project. She is an IEEE student and IEEE Women In Engineering (WIE) member, as well as an ACM student and ACM-Women (ACM-W) member. Her research interests include the design and implementation of Application Programming Interfaces (APIs) and the study of open source software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She is a member of the &lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vaggelis - Giannikas</title><link href="/vaggelis-giannikas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2009-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2009-09-04:vaggelis-giannikas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vaggelis Giannikas&lt;/em&gt; holds a BSc in Management Science and Technology from the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB). He is currently a member of the &lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group. His research interests include open source software, software engineering and supply chain information systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also works at the European Project Unit of SingularLogic S.A. and collaborates with the ELTRUN, the e-business research center.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Dimitris - Mitropoulos</title><link href="/dimitris-mitropoulos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2007-03-01:dimitris-mitropoulos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dimitris Mitropoulos&lt;/em&gt; is the Security Officer of the &lt;a href="https://grnet.gr/"&gt;Greek Research and Technology Network (GRNET)&lt;/a&gt;.
Dr. Mitropoulos holds a BSc in Informatics and Telecommunications from the National and Kapodistrian University of Athens,
and an MSc and a PhD in Cyber Security from the Athens University of Economics and Business. He has also been a Postdoctoral researcher at the &lt;a href="http://nsl.cs.columbia.edu/index.html"&gt;Network Security Laboratory (NSL)&lt;/a&gt; of Columbia University in the City of New York. He has worked in the industry as a software engineer and has been involved in several EU and US funded R&amp;amp;D projects. His research interests include application and system security, applied cryptography, software evolution and software engineering. He is a member of ACM, IEEE, &lt;a href="http://www.syssec-project.eu/community/members/"&gt;SysSec&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://www.owasp.org/index.php/Greece"&gt;OWASP&lt;/a&gt;, and an official writer for the &lt;a href="http://xrds.acm.org/blog/?author=8"&gt;XRDS:Crossroads&lt;/a&gt; blog of ACM.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vasiliki - Efstathiou</title><link href="/vasiliki-efstathiou.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2007-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2007-01-08:vasiliki-efstathiou.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Vasiliki Efstathiou holds a PhD in Computer Science from University College London, an MSc in Computer Science from the same University and a BSc in Mathematics from the University of Crete. Her PhD thesis investigated automated theorem proving techniques for implementing computational argumentation based on classical logic. Her research interests lie in the wider area of knowledge representation and reasoning.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Konstantinos - Stroggylos</title><link href="/konstantinos-stroggylos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2005-11-10:konstantinos-stroggylos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Markos Gogoulos&lt;/em&gt; is a research associate of the &lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; group and a former member of the &lt;a href="http://www.islab.demokritos.gr"&gt;ISLAB group&lt;/a&gt; in N.C.S.R. Demokritos. He holds a Diploma in Information and Communication Systems Engineering from the University of the Aegean. His research interests include applied security and operating systems hardening, network attack analysis, operating systems and networking.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Panos (Panagiotis) - Louridas</title><link href="/panos-panagiotis-louridas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2005-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2005-01-01:panos-panagiotis-louridas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panos (Panagiotis) Louridas&lt;/em&gt; holds an MSc by Research and a PhD in Computation from the University of Manchester Institute of Science and Technology (UMIST). He is a consultant at the Greek Research &amp;amp; Technology Network, focusing on electronic infrastructures. Prior to that he has worked as a Software Engineer in the banking sector, developing applications using open source software, and as a consultant in various European projects. His research interests include Software Engineering, Software Design, and Security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Louridas is a member of the ACM, the IEEE, and the AAAS. He is the recipient of a cheque by Donald Knuth.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Georgios - Gousios</title><link href="/georgios-gousios.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2004-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2004-11-15:georgios-gousios.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Georgios Gousios&lt;/em&gt; holds an MSc with distinction from the University of Manchester, UK and a PhD from the Athens University of Economics and Business,GR, both on Software Engineering. He has worked as a researcher in several national and international research projects and provided consulting services in both multinational and emerging startup companies. He was the project manager, lead designer and top source code contributor of the SQO-OSS project, an FP6 funded project that produced novel tools for facilitating research in the field of software engineering. He has published more that 10 papers in various fields and also co-edited the "Beautiful Architectures" book (OReilly, 2009). His research interests include empirical software engineering, software architectures and systems level software. He is a member of the ACM, the IEEE, Usenix and the technical chamber of Greece.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Stefanos - Androutsellis-Theotokis</title><link href="/stefanos-androutsellis-theotokis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2003-11-14:stefanos-androutsellis-theotokis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Androutsellis-Theotokis was born in Athens, Greece, in 1970. He holds a B.Eng in Information Systems Engineering, an M.Sc. in Engineering and Physical Sciences in Medicine both from Imperial College (University of London, UK), an M.S.E. in Biomedical Engineering from Johns Hopkins University, MD, US, and a Ph.D. from the Athens University of Economics and Business. He has worked in the industry as a software analyst and developer and has been involved in several EU funded R&amp;amp;D projects. Dr. Androutsellis-Theotokis is a member of the Technical Chamber of Greece and the IEEE. His research interests include Information Security, Peer-to-Peer architectures and Software Engineering, and his current doctoral research concerns the design of transaction processing systems based on peer-to-peer architectures.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vasileios - Vlachos</title><link href="/vasileios-vlachos.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2003-11-14:vasileios-vlachos.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dr. Vasileios Vlachos was born in Athens, Greece, in 1976. He holds a Dipl.-El.-Eng. (Comp. Eng.) (Diploma of Engineering, a 5 date Degree which is equivalent to British and Greek MSc Degrees) in Electronic &amp;amp; Computer Engineering from Technical University of Crete , Greece and a MSc in Integrated Hardware and Software Systems from the Department of Computer Engineering and Informatics of the University of Patras , Greece. His Master's Thesis was completed at the Interuniversity MicroElectronics Center (IMEC), Leuven, Belgium. Dr. Vlachos also holds a Ph.D. degree in Information Systems Security (specialization on Computer Virology, Thesis title: Security Applications of Peer to Peer Networks) from the Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens University of Economics and Business (2007). He is a member of ISTLab/SENSE for the last 5 dates. During his studies he obtained a number of scholarships from several foundations and worked in several national and European projects. Dr. Vlachos is a member of IEEE, and IEEE Computer Society, member of the Technical Chamber of Greece, and the Hellenic Association of Computer Engineers. His research interests include: Computer Virology, Computer Epidemiology, Peer to Peer Networks and Open Source Software.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Vassilios - Karakoidas</title><link href="/vassilios-karakoidas.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2003-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2003-11-14:vassilios-karakoidas.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dr. Vassilios Karakoidas&lt;/em&gt; holds a BSc in Informatics (University of Piraeus), a MSc in Information Systems (Athens of Economics and Business) and a PhD in Programming Languages (Athens University of Economics and Business). He is now a member of &lt;a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/"&gt;ISTLab&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html"&gt;SENSE&lt;/a&gt; and a former member of the Health Informatics Laboratory at University of Piraeus. He has been involved in various research projects. The most recent are &lt;a href="../projects/p_gemini.html"&gt;GEMINI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="../projects/p_praxis.html"&gt;PRAXIS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="../projects/p_sqo-oss.html"&gt;SQO-OSS&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="../projects/p_tracer.html"&gt;TRACER&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="../projects/p_stereo.html"&gt;STEREO&lt;/a&gt; In 2008, he co-founded Wizhut, a software company that was involved with various software development projects. He was leading the design and the implementation effort of &lt;a href="http://www.warp.ly/"&gt;warp.ly&lt;/a&gt; mobile marketing platform. He worked part-time with the &lt;a href="http://www.totaleclipsegames.com/"&gt;Total Eclipse&lt;/a&gt; development team and he was the lead software architect at Emaginal AG. He is the author of a number of open-source and public-domain software packages and tools. His research interests include Software Engineering, Programming Languages, Operating Systems and Networking. He has published more than 25 scientific articles in refereed scientific journals and conferences.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Diomidis - Spinellis</title><link href="/diomidis-spinellis.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2002-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><author><name></name></author><id>tag:,2002-01-01:diomidis-spinellis.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diomidis Spinellis&lt;/strong&gt; is a Professor in the Department of Management Science and Technology at the Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece.  His research interests include software engineering, IT security, and  cloud systems engineering.  He has written two award-winning, widely-translated books: “&lt;em&gt;Code Reading&lt;/em&gt;” and “&lt;em&gt;Code Quality: The Open Source Perspective&lt;/em&gt;”.  Dr. Spinellis has also published more than 250 technical papers in journals and refereed conference proceedings, which have received more than 5000 citations.  He served for a decade as a member of the &lt;em&gt;IEEE Software&lt;/em&gt; editorial board, authoring the regular “Tools of the Trade” column.  He has contributed code that ships with Apple’s macOS and BSD Unix and is the developer of &lt;em&gt;CScout&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;UMLGraph&lt;/em&gt; and other open-source software packages, libraries, and tools.  He holds an MEng in Software Engineering and a PhD in Computer Science, both from Imperial College London.  Dr. Spinellis has served as an elected member of the IEEE Computer Society Board of Governors (2013–2015), and is a senior member of the ACM and the IEEE. From January 2015 he is serving as the Editor-in-Chief for IEEE Software.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>