<?xml version="1.0"?>
<group id="g_istlab" director="m_dds" contact="m_dds" maintainer="m_dds">
	<grouptitle>Information Systems Technology Laboratory</grouptitle>
	<shortname>ISTLab</shortname>
	<description>
<!-- 
<img src="../images/ote.jpg"/>
<br/><br/>
 -->
Welcome to the
<em>Information Systems Technology Laboratory</em> (ISTLab),
established at the
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr">Department of Management Science and Technology</a>
of the
<a href="http://www.aueb.gr">Athens University of Economics and Business</a>.
Here we explore, research, create, formulate, and integrate engineering
and management practices to increase the effectiveness of the information
systems and their realisation and adoption process.
To reach our goal we follow a number of interrelated paths.
<ul>
<li> Software: programming languages, software engineering tools, and open source software</li> <!-- SENSE -->
<li> Management of computing information systems: security and protection</li> <!-- SENSE -->
<li> IT as change enabler in companies, public organizations (e-government)
and inter-organizational networks </li> <!-- IRIS -->
<li> Social, political and ethical issues in information systems analysis,
development and adoption</li> <!-- IRIS -->
<li> Social and organizational dimensions of ICTs: virtual communities,
e-Government, electronic collaboration, and inter-organizational
networks</li> <!-- OIS -->
<li> Design, management and evaluation of enterprise technolgies:
e-Learning, knowledge management, and enterprise resource planning
systems</li> <!-- OIS -->
<li>Mobile, Wireless, and Sensor-based Computing: Applications and Services, Business Models</li> <!-- WRC -->
<li>Pervasive and Ubiquitous Information Systems: Design, Analysis, and Technology Acceptance</li> <!-- WRC -->
</ul>
<em>ISTLab</em> consists of four federated research groups.
<ul>
<li><a href="g_iris-details.html">IRIS</a>: Interdisciplinary Research on the Information Society, headed by <a href="../members/m_pouloudi.html">Nancy Pouloudi</a></li>
<li><a href="g_ois-details.html">OIS</a>: Organizational Information Systems, headed by <a href="../members/m_akp.html">Angeliki Poulymenakou</a></li>
<li><a href="g_sense-details.html">SENSE</a>: Software Engineering and Security, headed by <a href="../members/m_dds.html">Diomidis Spinellis</a></li>
<li><a href="g_wrc-details.html">WRC</a>: Wireless Research Center, headed by <a href="../members/m_giaglis.html">George Giaglis</a></li>
</ul>
</description>
	<rel_link>
		<a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/">Home</a>
	</rel_link>
	<!-- <logo>../images/istlab-m.jpg</logo>  -->
	<color>#8B9DC3</color>
</group>
