<?xml version="1.0"?>
<group id="g_swise" director="m_mdl" contact="m_mdl" maintainer="m_nkorf">
	<grouptitle>Semantic Web Enabled Information Systems</grouptitle>
	<shortname>S-WiSE</shortname>
	<description>
	<p>Semantic Web poses new challenges to Information Systems. A first comment concerning the current situation is that the field of SW is dominated by rather technical approaches where there is a lack of multidisciplinary contributions. From this perspective SEMIS θνιτ is attempting to fill this gap, with a special emphasis to be paid on Information systems. SEMIS aims to develop an extensive web of relations with several critical stakeholders. We distinguish six specific stakeholders that can gain critical value from the operation of SEMIS and its services: Academia, IS students, IT Industry, Public Bodies, Consultants, Standards Communities and several others. The central positioning of SEMIS in this web implies its critical role for the knowledge transfer. In other words all the research and services provided by SEMIS will have a clear orientation in knowledge creation and diffusion concerning the issues of Semantic Web in the IS research Community. Our main distinction is that semantic web is not treated as a technological evolution but we concentrate on the translation of SW within the IS research community. </p>
<p>In the Knowledge Society the exploitation of knowledge requires integration, intelligence, flexibility as well as accuracy and reference layers that are held together by a simple and ultimate goal: To utilize available technologies towards the “effective” knowledge representation and retrieval. But this fact is the basis of Information Systems: From an ontology perspective we develop conceptualizations and from these we build systems, services and practices that require an effective mix of information technology, processes, people and applications. The scope of SEMIS is to analyze the Semantic Web as an indissoluble whole of Technologies, Frameworks, Concepts and Practices that enable tools and services capable of supporting new innovative, effective and feasible information systems. </p>

<p>Figure 1, provides a graphical overview of the overall scope of SEMIS. Three areas are in a continuous interchange and provide value through dynamic flows and exchanges, namely the <strong>Information Systems Discipline </strong>, the <strong>IS Research Streams </strong> and the emerging <strong>Knowledge Society </strong>. </p>


<p><strong>Figure 1. The overall scope of the SEMIS </strong></p>

<p><img width="576" height="360" alt="Figure 1" src=""></img></p>
<p>The inner circle provides a main research objective for our unit. The extensive discussion of issues and the production of new knowledge is related to the semantic web implications in main IS research streams such as E-business, Knowledge Management, E-learning, Business Intelligence, Organizational Learning, Agents, Adaptive Systems, Enterprise Application Integration, E-government, Decision Making, HCI, Multimedia etc. </p>
<p>The outer circle represents another interesting aspect of SEMIS overall scope. Our vision for the cultivation of the Semantic Web vision in IS, is closely related to the so-called Knowledge Society, where transparent technology provides new tools, services for the citizens, learners, disabled people as well as for businesses, organizations and government. </p>
<p>From these perspectives several more pillars outline the scope of SEMIS: </p>
<p>&#149; Presentation of new semantic web enabled tools depicting the power and the capabilities of the Semantic Web. </p>
<p>&#149; Sectoral /Industry Analysis of Semantic Web enabled IS (in Tourism, Knowledge Intensive Organizations, Commerce, etc). </p>
<p>&#149; Discussion of innovative training activities concerning SW (community building, knowledge transfer) as well as thorough discussion on the critical theme for the inclusion of SW in IS curricula. </p>
<p>&#149; Forum for epistemological, societal and cultural issues that are affected by the Semantic Web. </p>
<p>&#149;Discussion of leading edge research in knowledge representation and retrieval on five levels: Artifact, Individual, Team, Organization, Network </p>
<p>The above description indicates the multidisciplinary flavor of SEMIS unit. We don't believe that the SW is a solid AI issue nor that it is a “Database”-driven phenomenon. In our perception, the Semantic Web is a milestone on the road towards the ultimate human quest for efficient knowledge heritage. From philosophy we derive the axioms of dialectic and we will work hard to develop a multidisciplinary and evolutionary journal of high quality. </p>

<p><strong>Research Streams </strong></p>
<ul>
  <li>Semantic Web Issues, Challenges and Implications in each of the IS research streams </li>
  <li>New Semantic Web enabled Tools for the citizen/ learner/ organization/ business </li>
  <li>New Semantic Web enabled Business Models </li>
  <li>New Semantic Web enabled Information systems and knowledge repositories </li>
  <li>Intelligent Systems </li>
  <li>Standards </li>
  <li>Semantic enabled business intelligence </li>
  <li>Enterprise Application Integration </li>
  <li>Metadata-driven (bottom-up) versus ontology-driven (top-down) SW development </li>
  <li>Strategies for Knowledge Management </li>
  <li>IT-enabled Knowledge Management Interventions </li>
  <li>E-Learning Technology and Adaptive Hypermedia </li>
  <li>Reusable Learning Object Engineering </li>
  <li>Web Services and Semantic Interoperability Frameworks </li>
  <li>Ontology Engineering </li>
  <li>Intelligent Agent Interfaces for Electronic Commerce </li>
  <li>Semantic Annotations and Information Seeking Behavior </li>
  <li>Web-metrics and Bibliometric Research on the Web </li>
  <li>Community Social Network Analysis and Engineering </li>
  <li>Cultural Heritage Management using Semantic Web Technology </li>
  <li>Information Dissemination with Peer-to-peer and Grid Computing </li>
  <li>Intelligent Agent Interfaces for Electronic Commerce </li>
  <li>Web-metrics and Bibliometric Research on the Web</li>
</ul>

	</description>
<color>#B5C3DC</color>
</group>

