<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_akostaki" group="g_istlab g_ois" joined="20141212">
	<givenname>Aggeliki</givenname>
	<surname>Kostaki</surname>
	<memb_title>Ms.</memb_title>
	<email>aggkostaki@aueb.gr</email>
	<web_site>https://gr.linkedin.com/in/aggeliki-kostaki-03374931</web_site>
	<office_phone>+30 210 8203466</office_phone>
	<!-- <mobile_phone></mobile_phone> -->
	<!--fax>+30 2108203370</fax> -->
	<!-- <alumnus/>--><!-- Optional -->
	<office_address>
		12 Derigny St., 7th floor
	</office_address>
	<postal_address>
		76 Patission str,
		104 34,
		Athens, Greece
	</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/AggKostaki.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
			<p>Aggeliki Kostaki is a PhD Candidate at Athens University of Economics and Business, in the Department of Management Science and Technology. Aggeliki has joined <a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/">ISTLab</a>/<a href="../groups/g_ois-details.html">OIS</a> in 2011. She holds a first degree in Financial Services (Technological Educational Institute of Piraeus), an MSc in Banking and Finance and an MSc in Human Resources Management (both from Athens University of Economics and Business). She has over 30 years of solid multilevel experience in IT applications and since the 90’s she has participated in several SAP projects (2007-2010 as a Deputy Project Manager).  Aggeliki is an SAP Certified Application Associate – Human Capital Management with SAP ERP 6.0 EHP, and she is a (LAEK) certified instructor with over a ten-year teaching experience.</p>
			<p> She is now a researcher of IST Lab-OIS and her main interests lay in the field of Organizational Reform, Change Management, Business Process Analysis, ICTs and IT applications.  She runs SAP and ARIS seminars for undergraduate and postgraduate students and she supports undergraduates’ assignments related to the implementation of e-learning courses via the moodle platform.</p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_akp" startdate="20130703">
    <phd-title>Organizational Reform and ICTs</phd-title>
    <phd-summary></phd-summary>
  </phd-info>
</member>
