<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<member id="m_akp" group="g_istlab g_ois" joined="20020101">
	<givenname>Angeliki</givenname>
	<surname>Poulymenakou</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>akp@aueb.gr</email>
	<office_phone>+30 210 8203466</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203756</fax>
	<office_address>12 Derigny St., 7th floor</office_address>
	<postal_address>76 Patission St., GR104 34, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
		Angeliki Poulymenakou is Associate Professor in the Department of Management Science &amp; Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business. Prior to this, she has served as Lecturer in Information Systems at the Information Systems Department of the London School of Economics and Political Science. She holds a first degree in Mathematics (University of Athens), and MSc and PhD degrees in Information Systems both from the London School of Economics and Political Science. Her research interests over the years have addressed advanced knowledge analysis and management methods (PhD), inter-organisational networks, IT enabled organisational change and new methods of work, business processes level implications of ERP, e-learning particularly in workplace contexts, e-government (studies in Brazil and Greece), and implications of digital entrepreneurship (China). She has published 25 papers in international journals, 50 papers in peer reviewed international conferences and two books (by Springer Berlin and Kluwer Academic Publishers). Currently she serves on the editorial board of three international journals, while she has served on the program committee and as associate editor for international information systems conferences for multiple years (ICIS, ECIS, IFIP). She has been program co-chair and organising chair for the IFIP WG 8.2 &amp; 9.4 conference (Athens, 2003), program chair for MCIS (Athens, 2009) and programme and organising chair for IFIP WG 9.5 (Athens, 2009). She has acted as research coordinator in 20 EU and national funded Research and Development projects most of them involving collaboration with academic and industrial partners across Europe. Since 2001 she is the Director of the Organisational Information Systems Research Group first in the ELTRUN and then in the ISTLab of the Department of Management Science and Technology of the AUEB.
		</p>
	</shortcv>
</member>
