<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_akp" group="g_eltrun g_ois">
	<givenname>Angeliki</givenname>
	<surname>Poulymenakou</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>akp@aueb.gr</email>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203754</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203756</fax>
	<office_address>1 Derigni St.</office_address>
	<postal_address>76 Patission St., GR104 34, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<shortcv>
Dr. ANGELIKI POULYMENAKOU is Assistant Professor in Information Systems Management. Prior to that she has served as lecturer in Information Systems in the Informatics Department of the Athens School of Economics and Business and in the Information Systems Department of the London School of Economics and Political Science. She holds a first degree in Mathematics (Athens), and MSc and PhD degrees in Information Systems (London School of Economics). Her current research interests focus information technology enabled change and particularly on the study of technological intervention in the areas of organisational learning and knowledge management, and on the study of dynamic organisational networks from an Information Systems perspective.
She is currently the scientific coordinator of European funded projects in socio-economic research within the IST programme in the areas of organisational networks and learning. Over the past years she has participated in over 15 ESPIT, IST, and Greek government funded research projects. More recently she has offered consultancy work to the European Commission, DG Information Society (on the socio-economic impact of electronic commerce, the emergence of new organisational forms, the evaluation of proposals and projects on related issues in FP5), as well as to the Greek Government (Ministries of Development and of Employment on e-Business and the impact of the Information Society respectively). She is a member of the co-ordinating committee of the Greek e-business forum (Ministry of Development).
Her several publications in international journals and conferences draw from the full range of activities outlined above. She has served as a member of the scientific committee of four international conferences in information systems (ICIS, ECIS, IFIP) and has acted as a referee in several international journals in the field. In 2003 she chaired the organisation of the IFIP joint WG8.2 and 9.4 Conference on Information Systems and Globalisation, in Athens.
	</shortcv>
</member>
