<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_alextsiaousis" group="g_istlab g_wrc" joined="20050201">
	<givenname>Alexandros</givenname>
	<surname>Tsiaousis</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>tsiaousis@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=Tsiaousis</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203855</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203854</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 103</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/alex.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
<p>Alexandros Tsiaousis holds a Bachelor Degree in International and European Economic and Political Studies from the University of Macedonia, Greece. His Bachelor dissertation regarded: The multi-dimensional transition from Geopolitics to Geoconomy in Europe, He has also been awarded with an MSc in Information Technology from the University of Glasgow (UK). His MSc dissertation was: GLAP: An MSc IT Material Search engine for MSc students. </p>
<p>Alexandros Tsiaousis received his PhD titled: "Usability evaluation of mobile applications in context of use" in the area of mobile Human Computer Interaction (HCI) at the Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens University of Economics and Business (GR). </p>
<p>His main interests lie in the area of the latest developments in 4G mobile phones and particularly in the mobile web with a special interest for Augmented Reality applications.</p>
<p>He has more than 5 years of professional and research experience in wireless - mobile - voice technology projects and an extensive experience as project manager in international web projects.</p>
      </p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_giaglis" startdate="20050201">
				<phd-title>The impact of context of use on Mobile Applications Usability</phd-title>
				<phd-summary>
				With the rapid advances of mobile technology and applications, effective usability testing becomes increasingly important for the design, development, and deployment of successful mobile applications. 
				However, due to unique features of mobile devices, limited bandwidth, unreliability of wireless networks, as well as other changing mobile context (e.g., location), traditional guidelines and methods used in usability testing of desktop applications may not be directly applicable to mobile applications. 
				Therefore, it is essential to develop and adopt appropriate methodologies and tools to evaluate the usability of mobile applications in their context of use. 
				This research highlights major research questions and issues in this field, and attempts to analyse the impact of context on mobile usability by employing applicable usability evaluation methods. 
				</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
