<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_androutsellis" group="g_istlab g_sense" joined="20031114">
	<givenname>Stefanos</givenname>
	<surname>Androutsellis-Theotokis</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>stheotok@aueb.gr</email>
	<web_site>http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~path/</web_site>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203370</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203664</fax>
	<office_address>76 Patission Str.</office_address>
	<postal_address>76 Patission Str., 10434, Athens, 
Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_androutsellis.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
	Mr. Androutsellis-Theotokis was born in Athens, Greece, in 1970. He holds a B.Eng in Information Systems Engineering, an M.Sc. in Engineering and Physical Sciences in Medicine both from Imperial College (University of London, UK), an M.S.E. in Biomedical Engineering from Johns Hopkins University, MD, US, and
a PhD from the Athens University of Economics and Business.
	He has worked in the industry as a software analyst and developer and has been involved in several EU funded R&amp;D projects. Mr. Androutsellis-Theotokis is a member of the Technical Chamber of Greece and the IEEE. His research interests include Information Security, Peer-to-Peer architectures and Software Engineering, and his current doctoral research concerns the design of transaction processing systems based on peer-to-peer architectures. 
      </p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_dds" startdate="20031114" enddate="20090714">
		<phd-title>Performing peer-to-peer e-business transactions</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
			Distributed computer architectures labeled "peer-to-peer" are designed for the sharing of computer resources by direct exchange, rather than requiring the intermediation or support of a centralized server or authority, and are characterized by their ability to adapt to failures and accommodate transient populations of nodes while maintaining acceptable connectivity and performance. On-line business transaction processing systems have so far been based on centralized or client-server architectures. Our aim is to propose solutions that will allow such systems to be performed based on peer-to-peer architectures. We focus on non-functional characteristics of peer-to-peer systems such as security, scalability, performance, fairness, and resource management potential, and we study current peer-to-peer systems and infrastructure technologies.
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
