<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<member id="m_apaparg" group="g_istlab g_ois" joined="20021014">
	<givenname>Anthony</givenname>
	<surname>Papargyris</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>apaparg@aueb.gr</email>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203755</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203756</fax>
	<office_address>1 Derigni St.</office_address>
	<postal_address>76 Patission St., GR104 34, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_apaparg.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
		Dr. Anthony Paprgyris is a researcher in the Athens University of Economics and Business, at the Department of Management Science and Technology. He holds a first degree in Business Computing (Teesside, UK), and an MSc degree in Information Systems (AUEB). Since 2001, he is now a member of <a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/">ISTLab</a>/<a href="../groups/g_ois-details.html">OIS</a>. His current research is focussing on collective action and meaning construction, virtual communities, and learning. His general research interests are in online interactive learning games, philosophy of science and Information Systems, and Knowledge Management.
		</p>
		</shortcv>
		<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_akp" startdate="20021014" enddate="20100615">
		<phd-title>
The Constitution of Collective Memory in Massive Multiplayer On-Line Game Virtual Communities:
Conceptual Foundations and Design Implications for Collective Memory Systems
		</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
		<p>
		The virtual game worlds of Massive Multiplayer On-Line Games (MMOGs) have attracted much attention over the years, mainly due to their capacities for supporting educational or business related activities. Active research on organisational and Information Systems studies and Knowledge Management strongly suggests the importance of communities in the processes of knowledge sharing and organizational/collective memory constitution. However, the lack of studies on massive non-organizational communities in the virtual is evident. More specifically, little is known on the relation of virtuality to collective action, to practices of knowledge sharing, and to collective memory constitution.
		</p>
		<p>
The starting point of this research is the argument that MMOGs are community building arenas. These communities of players are virtual in nature but due to the sandbox type and task accomplishment scenario of the game, they are in continuous mobilization collectively negotiating the diverse meanings of virtuality and renovating their habitualized practices of knowledge sharing. In this vein, the research interest in this thesis is on how virtuality shapes knowledge sharing practices. The research focuses especially on the constitution of collective memory in virtual communities. As a result, the overall research aim in this dissertation is to address the following: “how do virtual communities share their collective knowledge and constitute their collective memory?”.
		</p>
		<p>
To this end, the objective of this thesis is to explore the dynamics of virtuality in relation to the capacities of virtual communities in the virtual game worlds for collective memory constitution. The research annotates the transformative character of the virtual, as providing the capability for the renovation of habitualised practices. The thesis of this research is that collective memory is the collective action of remembering and forgetting, virtuality is the experience of the virtual, and hence collective memory constitution in the virtual warrants a fresh conceptual foundation as well as a reconsideration of design options for collective memory systems.
		</p>
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
