<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_bkarak" group="g_istlab g_sense">
	<givenname>Vassilios</givenname>
	<surname>Karakoidas</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>bkarak@aueb.gr</email>
	<web_site>http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~bkarak/</web_site>	
	<office_phone>+30 2108203370</office_phone>
	<photo>../images/m_bkarak.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<i>Vassilios Karakoidas</i> is a PhD candidate in Athens University of Economics and Business at the Department of Management Science and Technology. He holds an BSc in Computer Science (University of Piraeus) and  an MSc in Information Systems (Athens University of Economics and Business). He is former member of the Health Informatics laboratory at University of Piraeus. He is now a member of <a href="http://www.eltrun.gr/">ELTRUN</a>/<a href="../groups/g_sense-details.html">SENSE</a> and has been involved in various research projects. The most recent are <a href="../projects/p_gemini.html">GEMINI</a>, <a href="../projects/p_praxis.html">PRAXIS</a> and <a href="../projects/p_sqo-oss.html">SQO-OSS</a>. His research interests include Software Engineering, Programming Languages, Operating Systems and Networking. He is an author of a number of open-source and public-domain software packages and tools.
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_dds" startdate="20031114">
		<phd-title>Integrating Domain-Specific Languages with General-Purpose Languages</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
			Domain-specific languages (DSL) are small, usually declarative languages that focus on o specific problem domain. SQL and regular expressions are two of the most common DSL's. General purpose languages (GPL) such as C, C++ and Java are covering a wider application domain, but lack expressive power when applicable to specific problems. Usually DSL's are implemented as external libraries when used by GPL's and the compiler is unaware of the DSL syntax and data types, creating a series of problems in the software development process. Our approach attempts to fill this scientific gap, and create a compiler framework that will be DSL aware.
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>