<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_borotis" group="g_istlab g_ois">
	<givenname>Spiros</givenname>
	<surname>Borotis</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>borotis@aueb.gr</email>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203755</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203756</fax>
	<office_address>1 Derigni St.</office_address>
	<postal_address>76 Patission St., GR104 34, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
		Mr. SPIROS BOROTIS was born in Athens, Greece, in 1976. He holds a B.Sc. in Mathematics from University of Patras (2000), and a M.Sc. in Information Systems from Athens University of Economics and Business (2002). From October 2002 he is a PhD Candidate in Athens University of Economics and Business. In 2001 he joined <a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/">ISTLab</a>/<a href="../groups/g_ois-details.html">OIS</a>, and since then he worked as a researcher in projects funded by the General Secretariat for Research and Technology and the European Union. He also participated in the organization of the IFIP Conference 'IS Perspectives and Challenges in the Context of Globalization' (Athens, June 2003), as the chief local organizing committee officer and overall responsible of proceedings' editing. From March 2003, he works as the primary researcher of a project funded by Hellenic General Secretariat for Research and Technology, which focuses in the Analyzing of Training Needs in Knowledge Intensive Organizations, during the Adoption of KM and e-Learning Systems. His currente research interests focus in the identification of training needs, e-Learning strategies, Human Resource Development, and Information Systems.
		</p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_akp" startdate="20031114">
		<phd-title>Development of a methodological framework for e-Learning adoption in the workplace</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
		<p>
		e-Learning efforts are considered to be significant corporate investments, which focus on human resource development and on the achievement of potential benefits. Initial research indicated:
		</p>
		<ul>
		<li>Lack of training needs assessment which provides the instructional objectivesfor the learning process.</li>
		<li>High drop-out rates or failures in e-Learning adoption, due to inadequate readiness for adoption on behalf of the organizations.</li>
		<li>Deficiencies in establishing the link between the adoption of e-Learning interventions and business strategy, human resources, infrastructures, internal training process and existing learning culture.</li>
		</ul>
		<p>
		This research is held in the intersection of human resource development, management, and information systems. It aims at developing a methodological framework which will facilitate organizations in adopting and empowering on e-Learning programs. The framework will be based on the business strategy, needs analysis, infrastructures, culture and training process.
		</p>
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
