<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_dimkar" group="g_istlab g_wrc" joined="20060102">
	<givenname>Dr. Dimitrios</givenname>
	<surname>Karaiskos</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>dimkar@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=Karaiskos</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203855</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203854</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Office 103</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/dimkar.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
<p>Dimitrios Karaiskos is a Research Fellow at the WRC of the
Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens
University of Economics and Business (AUEB).</p>

<p>He holds a BSc Degree in Informatics and Telecommunications
from the National and Kapodistrian University of Athens,
Greece and an MSc in Information Systems from the Athens
University of Economics and Business, Greece. His doctoral
dissertation investigates user acceptance of pervasive
information systems taking into account technology-specific
traits, human behaviour, physical and social environment. His
work has been presented in several academic conferences and
published in International Journal of Mobile Computing, Journal
of Information Technology and several book chapters.</p>

<p>His main research interests lie in the area of pervasive
information systems and technology acceptance. Mainly, he
is studying acceptance of pervasive systems in the context of
promotion and exploitation of cultural heritage. Moreover, he
is interested in the design and implementation of pervasive
services involving mobile and wireless technologies. He is also
investigating usage trends and perceptions regarding mobile
internet and data services through his participation in the
Worldwide Mobile Data Services Survey.</p>

<p>He uses analytical tools such as variance and covariance-based
Structural Equation Modeling (SEM) and survey and experimental
design as research methodologies. Finally, he has great experience in
software development on both desktop and mobile devices in various
platforms and programming languages.</p>
	
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_giaglis" startdate="20060301">
	<phd-title>A Predictive Model for the Acceptance of Pervasive Information Systems by Individuals</phd-title>
	<phd-summary>My research efforts lie in the intersection among pervasive/ubiquitous computing and behavioral prediction models, investigating factors affecting the acceptance and use of pervasive/ubiquitous computing by individuals taking into account the technology-specific traits, the human behavior, and the physical and social environment.
	Moreover, Pervasive Information Systems (PIS) constitute the resurgent class of Information Systems (IS) due to the new attributes that pervasive/ubiquitous computing, the underlying technology, introduce. PIS differentiate themselves from traditional IS as they are characterized mainly by the embedment of technology into the physical environment, the effortless interactivity through natural interfaces, the seamless mobility of devices and services and the proactive support of users. These new elements of PIS create a hiatus among the existing technology acceptance models which were developed and tested under the focus of IS. 
	Therefore, my doctoral research goal is to define the factors that will meet the PIS novel attributes and provide a robust acceptance model for predicting PIS adoption and use by individuals.
	</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
