<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_drosos" group="g_istlab g_wrc">
	<givenname>Dimitris</givenname>
	<surname>Drossos</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>drosos@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=Drossos</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203855</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203854</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 103</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_drosos.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
	<p>
	  Dimitris Drossos holds a Bachelor Degree in Computer Science from the University of Crete and an MSc with Distinction in E-commerce from the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB). Currently, he is a PhD student in the Department of Management Science and Technology at AUEB.
	  Mobile marketing and advertising effectiveness are his central points of research and other interests focus on m-commerce technologies and services.
	  He is also Research Officer in ISTLab/WRC, where he is involved in several European and National research projects.
	  In the past he worked in several companies with diverse research domains including Hellenic National Meteorological Service, University of Crete net (UCnet), IP Datacom &amp; Services Ericsson Stockholm, Atlantis Group Univ. of Crete, and Foundation for Research and Technology - Hellas (ICS-FORTH).
      </p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_giaglis" startdate="20030301">
			<phd-title>Mobile Advertising Effectiveness</phd-title>
			<phd-summary>
				The present research belongs to the field of mobile advertising. 
				To date there is no established theory available as the case of traditional advertising. 
				Therefore, the principles of traditional and interactive advertising served as foundations for this study. 
				Given that little is known regarding the factors that may influence the effectiveness of a mobile advertising campaign the research design employed in this study includes: (a) literature review, (b) an exploratory field study, and (c) a screening experiment. 
				The outcome of this process was tested through a confirmatory field experiment with 800 participants. 
			</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
