<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_giaglis" group="g_eltrun g_wrc">
	<givenname>George</givenname>
	<surname>Giaglis</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>giagli@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=Giaglhs</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203682</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203685</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Office 907</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<!--<photo>../images/spi.jpg</photo>-->
	<shortcv>
		<p>
	   George M. Giaglis is Assistant Professor of eBusiness at the Department of Management
	   Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece.
	   He has also held full-time academic posts in Brunel University (UK) and the
	   University of the Aegean (Greece), while he has been a visiting professor in
	   universities such as the University of London, Nottingham Trent University, and
	   Henley Management College.</p>

	   <p>His main teaching and research interests lie in the areas of eBusiness (emphasising
	   on mobile and wireless applications and services), technology-enabled business
	   process redesign, business process modelling and re-engineering, information
	   management, and information systems evaluation.</p>

	   <p>He has published more than 50 research articles in leading journals and
	   international conferences, including the Information Systems Journal, the
	   International Journal of Electronic Commerce, and the International Journal of
	   Information Management. He is a member of the editorial board of the
	   International Journal of Mobile Communications and the Logistics Information
	   Management Journal. He is the permanent secretary of the International
	   Conference on Mobile Business, where he has also served as Research Track
	   Chair, and permanent Track Co-Chair in the European Simulation Symposium. He
	   has also acted as guest-editor in journals such as the International Journal of
	   Mobile Communications, the Business Process Management Journal, and the
	   International Journal of Flexible Manufacturing Systems. He has also been a
	   member of the organising committee of various international conferences
	   (including the European Conference on Information Systems Evaluation, the
	   International Conference on Business Process Modelling, and the Hawaiian
	   International Conference on Systems Sciences).</p>

	   <p>Since 2001, he is the Director of the ELTRUN Wireless Research Group (ELTRUN/WRC)
	   hosted by the Athens University of Economics and Business. The group pursues
	   research in innovative mBusiness models, assessment of new mobile/wireless
	   technologies, applications and services development, and others. The group
	   operates one the most well known portals on mBusiness, namely Mobiforum (<a
	   href="http://www.mobiforum.org/">www.mobiforum.org</a>).
      </p>
	</shortcv>
</member>
