<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_ikaliam" group="g_istlab g_iris" joined="20041103">
	<givenname>Eirini</givenname>
	<surname>Kalliamvakou</surname>
	<memb_title>Ms.</memb_title>
	<email>ikaliam@aueb.gr</email>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203870</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203664</fax>
	<office_address>47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str.</office_address>
	<postal_address>Office 205, 47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str., GR-113 62 Athens, Greece</postal_address>
<photo>../images/m_ikaliam.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p><b>Eirini Kalliamvakou </b> is a research assistant at the Athens University of Economics and Business in ISTLaband is currently working in the GUIDE project (funded by the EU). She has also been accepted as a PhD candidate in November 2004 in the Department of Management Science and Technology at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB). Eirini holds a Bachelor in Economics from the University of Athens and an MSc in Decision Sciences (specialization in e-Business) from the Athens University of Economics and Business. Her research interests concern the evolution of open source software development communities and their social network representation, topology and analysis. At the same time she is involved with the digital identity of a citizen in the eGovernment environment (her work within the project).
</p>

	</shortcv>
<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_pouloudi" startdate="20041103">
		<phd-title>Investigation of the topology of open source software developer networks: Properties and implications</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
Open Source Software (OSS) has received growing attention due to the diversified characteristics of its development linked also with its noticeable adoption and quality. One key element that enables OSS's dynamic evolution is the internal organization of dispersed developers into effective teams that produce the output of the process. This thesis investigates the topology of social networks of collaboration between developers within OSS projects and the properties that lead to it.     
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
