<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_ilias.kastritis" group="g_istlab g_iris">
	<givenname>Ilias</givenname>
	<surname>Kastritis</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>ilias.kastritis@infosoc.gr</email>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203870</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203664</fax>
	<alumnus/>
	<office_address>47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str.</office_address>
	<postal_address>Office 205, 47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str., GR-113 62 Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	
	
<shortcv>
		<p>
<b>Ilias Kastritis</b> is currently working for the Information Society Operational Programme with management &amp; appraisal responsibilities of –mainly- e-Government projects, having been a Management Consultant with Ernst&amp;Young Consulting practice for 5 years, with a focus in IT transformation, performance management, impact analysis, e-Business- e-Government strategic planning, architectures and policies. His working experience includes business analysis, process redesign, business plans, ERP implementations, e-Learning technologies in industries such as banking, shipping, healthcare and the public sector. He also had business development responsibilities for a joint e-learning venture. He holds an MSc in Information Technology, Management and Organizational Change by Lancaster University with a first degree in Mathematics. He has lecturing experience in domains such as Scenario Planning Process, Information Systems and Process Reengineering. As a Research Associate he joined eLTRUN research group in 1997, when among other activities, he designed an integrated learning program for major public organisation. Recently (end of 2003), he re-joined, by entering the IRIS research group, as a phD candidate, exploring the issues of IT Leadership and its role - performance impact in e-Governance frameworks and policies.
</p>

	</shortcv>
<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_pouloudi" startdate="">
		<phd-title>IT leadership in eGovernment</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
			
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
