<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_isideris" group="g_istlab g_iris">
	<givenname>Ioannis</givenname>
	<surname>Sideris</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>isideris@hol.gr</email>
	<!--<office_phone>+30 2108203870</office_phone>--> <alumnus/>
<photo>../images/m_isideris.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
<b>Mr. Ioannis Sideris</b> holds a Bachelor degree in Business Administration from the Athens University of Economics and Business and a Masters degree in Information Systems from the London School of Economics and Political Science. From 2000 to 2001, upon completion of his military services, he worked as a consultant at PricewaterhouseCoopers. He was the IT Manager responsible for the designing, installation and operation of a Quality Measurement System for the Hellenic Post Office, as well as a Human Resource Assistant Manager for the same period. </p>

<p>From 2001 to 2003 he held the position of a Research Officer at the Athens University of Economics and Business in ELTRUN (the e-Business Center). His research focused on strategic planning in the context of developing a Scenario Planning Methodology for high-tech markets with applications to Mobile Commerce. He was involved in the MobiCom IST Project, whose aim was the development of scenarios of the evolution of Mobile Commerce. He was responsible for the research on Scenario Planning Methodology in order to explore the evolution of market structures and dynamics, key players, technology architectures, consumer behaviour, new products and services. Since September 2003 he has been collaborating with ELTRUN and ISTLAB/IRIS as an external Research Associate.</p>

<p>Since September 2003 he has been leading the I. Sideris Publishing House, which was established in 1897. In September 2006 he founded Fast Forward Research and Design, a design, consulting and strategy firm. Since January 2006, he has been presiding over the 7th Permanent Committee of Experts at the Greek Ministry of Development, responsible for the allocation and administration of Information Technology resources. Since November 2006 he has been serving as representative of the Greek Ministry of Mercantile Marine to the board of the Poseidon Institute, an institution aiming to further educate workers in the shipping industry.
</p>

	</shortcv>
</member>
