<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_kdiamanti" group="g_istlab g_iris" joined="20020101">
	<givenname>Korina</givenname>
	<surname>Diamanti</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>kdiamanti@gmail.com</email>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203870</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203664</fax>
	<office_address>47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str.</office_address>
	<postal_address>Office 205, 47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str., GR-113 62 Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_kdiamanti.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
<b>Dr. Korina Diamanti</b> holds a PhD in knowledge and best practice transfer through benchmarking from the Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens University of Economics and Business (2009), an MSc in Financial Management (1999) and a BA (Hons) in Business Administration (1997) from Middlesex University Business School (London, UK). She speaks fluently Greek (native), English and very good French. During her undergraduate studies she was an exchange student for one year at EPSCI-ESSEC University, in Paris, France. Her PhD research contributes to (1) extending research on knowledge transfer through benchmarking, (2) exploring the transfer of knowledge and best practices in benchmarking through a qualitative study of multiple case studies in two public organizations, (3) examining how different types of knowledge are transferred in benchmarking, (4) exploring how the use of certain media assists the transfer of different types of knowledge on best practices, by applying media richness theory in benchmarking, (5) identifying an additional step in knowledge transfer in the benchmarking process and highlighting its importance as it precedes the decision making process on what to adopt, (6) creating a theoretical framework for benchmarking through the association of benchmarking types and the network ties that are created between the partners with the weak ties theory, (7) providing evidence that in cooperative benchmarking weak ties are created between the benchmarking partners, while in competitive benchmarking the ties are absent, supporting the association of different benchmarking types with the weak ties theory thus. 

Korina Diamanti has worked as (a) asset management assistant at a stock-brokerage firm in Athens,  (b) project manager and researcher at the laboratories of ELTRUN, the e-Business Center and ISTLab, Information Systems Technology Laboratory of the Department of Management Science &amp; Technology of Athens University of Economics &amp; Business, (c) business consultant at the Centre of Business and Technological Development of West Greece, (d) while she is currently employed at the Chamber of Commerce and Industry of Aitoloakarnania. Her research interests concern strategic management, change management, benchmarking, knowledge management, media richness and the use of Information and Communication Technologies (ICT) for the transfer of knowledge and best practices. 

		</p>
	</shortcv>
<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_pouloudi" startdate="20030301">
		<phd-title>Virtual benchmarking in network organizations</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
			
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
