<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_kfouskas" group="g_istlab g_wrc" joined="20021101">
	<givenname>Kostas</givenname>
	<surname>Fouskas</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>kfouskas@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=Fouskas</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203855</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203854</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 103</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_fouskas.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
	<p>Konstantinos Fouskas is a PhD candidate at the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece. 
	   He achieved a Bachelor Degree (BSc) on Business Administration with specialization on Accounting and Financial Administration from the department of Business Administration of Athens University of Economic and Business in 2000 
	   and a Master of Science (MSc) on Decision Sciences with specialization in e-Commerce from the Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens University of Economic and Business in 2001.
	</p>
        <p>His main research interests lie in the areas of mBusiness (emphasising on mobile and wireless industry evolution), competitive business strategy (emphasising on competitive reactions, competitive decision making and market analysis) 
           and the use of business games as a teaching aid.
        </p>
        <p>His PhD research examines the influence of managerial perceptions of both competitive environment and organizational capabilities on competitive reaction characteristics (speed, intensity etc) and marketing instruments used (price reduction, new product introduction etc). 
           Furthermore he examines the link between competitive reaction characteristics and firm performance.
        </p>
        <p>He has seven years working experience (1994-2000) in the private sector in accounting and financial analysis positions in various organizations, having an accounting licence from the Economic Chambers of Greece. 
        </p>
        <p>He has been a member of Eltrun Research Center during 2000-2001 and since 2001 he has been an active member of Wireless Research Center (WRC).
        </p>
      	</shortcv>
      	<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_giaglis" startdate="20021101">
				<phd-title>Examining managerial perceptions of competitive environment and organizational capabilities as antecedents of firms competitive reactions and performance</phd-title>
				<phd-summary>
					This thesis examines influences on competitive reaction characteristics and their role in shaping firm performance. 
					Initially it studies the influence of perceived competitive environment and organizational capabilities in competitive reaction characteristics in terms of speed, intensity and innovation, as well as preferences in competitive instruments used. 
					Next, it tries to asses the relation of these characteristics with firm performance under the moderating effects of the competitive environment. 
					The above are achieved though quantitative (survey) research and qualitative research (case studies). The expected contribution will be a fresh perspective on the field of competitive dynamics though an examination of managerial thinking when taking competitive response decisions and is effects on profitability.  
				</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
