<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_kfouskas" group="g_istlab g_wrc" joined="20021101">
	<givenname>Kostas</givenname>
	<surname>Fouskas</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>kfouskas@uom.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=Fouskas</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203855</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203854</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 103</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_fouskasnew.jpg</photo>
	<alumnus/>
	<shortcv>
Dr Konstanstinos Fouskas is currently a lecturer at the department of Technology
Management in University of Macedonia, Greece at the position of Innovation for new
products and services. Kostas holds a PhD in Strategic Management, and an MSc in
Decision Sciences specialized in eBusiness. He has extensive research experience
in numerous innovative European research projects as project manager and more
than ten years working experience in consulting, accounting and financial analysis
in private and public sector organizations. He has published several research
papers on scientific journals and conferences and has been a reviewer for scientific
journals and international conferences. His main research interests lie in the areas of
strategic management, including the effects of competitive dynamics on innovation
and eBusiness including the application of innovative services such as electronic
invoicing and social media advertising.
      	</shortcv>
      	<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_giaglis" startdate="20021101" enddate="20080221">
				<phd-title>Examining managerial perceptions of competitive environment and organizational capabilities as antecedents of firms competitive reactions and performance</phd-title>
				<phd-summary>
					This thesis examines influences on competitive reaction characteristics and their role in shaping firm performance. 
					Initially it studies the influence of perceived competitive environment and organizational capabilities in competitive reaction characteristics in terms of speed, intensity and innovation, as well as preferences in competitive instruments used. 
					Next, it tries to asses the relation of these characteristics with firm performance under the moderating effects of the competitive environment. 
					The above are achieved though quantitative (survey) research and qualitative research (case studies). The expected contribution will be a fresh perspective on the field of competitive dynamics though an examination of managerial thinking when taking competitive response decisions and is effects on profitability.  
				</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
