<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_kfouskas" group="g_eltrun g_wrc">
	<givenname>Kostas</givenname>
	<surname>Fouskas</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>kfouskas@aueb.gr</email>
	<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=Fouskas</web_site>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203870</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203871</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 205</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_fouskas.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
	   Konstantinos Fouskas is a full time researcher and PhD candidate at the Department of
	   Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and
	   Business, Greece. He achieved a Bachelor Degree (BSc) on Business Administration with
	   specialization on Accounting and Financial Administration from the department
	   of Business Administration of Athens University of Economic and Business in
	   2000 and a Master of Science (MSc) on Decision Sciences with specialization in
	   e-Commerce from the Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens
	   University of Economic and Business in 2001. </p>

	   <p>
	   His main research interests lie in the areas of mBusiness (emphasising on mobile
	   and wireless industry evolution), competitive business strategy (emphasising on
	   strategic decision making and market analysis) and the use of business games as
	   a teaching aid. Moreover he is teaching assistant in the course of Simulation
	   and Decision support systems at the Department of Management Science and Technology
	   of the Athens University of Economics and Business. </p>

	   <p>
	   He has seven years working experience (1994 - 2000) in the private sector in
	   accounting and financial analysis positions in various organizations, having an
	   accounting licence from the Economic Champers of Greece. Since 2000 he is
	   employed in the Hellenic Electronic Trading Research Unit (ELTRUN),
	   working in mBusiness related projects. From 2001 he is an active member of the ELTRUN
	   Wireless Research Group (ELTRUN/WRC).
      </p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_giaglis" startdate="20031114">
		<phd-title>Factors influencing the effectiveness of Competitor Analysis</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
			Competitor analysis is becoming an increasingly important task for organizations in today’s competitive landscape. The efficient analysis of competitors is vital for organizations success and in several occasions critical for its survival. However managers tend to be myopic when recognizing rivals, and inefficient in analyzing them. To this end, this thesis will try to identify factors influencing competitor analysis effectiveness, examine their influence and try to raise conclusions correlating the competitive decision process to common mistakes in competitive analysis. This will be held though an analytical process, examining environmental and organizational effects on the competitive analysis process characteristics and the process characteristics in relation to the process effectiveness. The results will better help us understand the process by which organizations choose to watch competitive others by identifying key points in the process that have to be taken into consideration.
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
