<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_krasos" group="g_istlab g_iris" joined="Required">
	<givenname>Ioannis</givenname>
	<surname>Krasonikolakis</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>krasos@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>Optional</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>210 8203731</office_phone>
	<!--<mobile_phone></mobile_phone>-->
	<fax>210 8203731</fax>
	<!--<alumnus/>-->
	<office_address>80 Patission Str</office_address>
	<postal_address>3rd floor, 80 Patission Str, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_krasos.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
	    Mr. Ioannis G. Krasonikolakis holds a Master in Information Systems and a B.Sc. in Informatics both issued from Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB). He is currently a Ph.D. student in Athens University of Economics and Business working on his thesis " Virtual Reality Internet Retailing: Experimental Examination of Interactive Shopping Interface – Store Atmosphere Effects on User-Consumer Behaviour ". He is a member of Eltrun - Imes research group operated at the Research Center at AUEB. His main research interests are virtual reality retailing, store atmosphere and consumer behaviour.
	    He is currently working in the Technological Education Institute of Piraeus as an adjunct coordinator in the Department of Accounting and in the Department of Business Administration and has teaching experience in sections such as Object-Oriented programming, Marketing and Economics. Previously, he has worked as an assistant consultant in Planning S.A. in the Grocery Retailing sector. Also, he has worked as a programmer in Siemens S.A. in the Software Department.
His research interest evolve around interactive marketing, virtual reality retailing, consumer behavior in ubiquitous environments and store atmosphere in virtual reality.
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="0" 
			  supervisor="m_pouloudi" 
			  supervisor-external="Adam Vrechopoulos"
		  	startdate=""
			  enddate="Optional"> <!-- Optional -->
		<phd-title>Virtual Reality Internet Retailing: Experimental Examination of Interactive Shopping Interface – Store Atmosphere Effects on User-Consumer Behaviour</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
			Required
			<!-- XHTML -->
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
