<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_mbina" group="g_istlab g_wrc" joined="20040301">
	<givenname>Mary</givenname>
	<surname>Bina</surname>
	<memb_title>Mrs.</memb_title>
	<email>mbina@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=%20Bina</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203855</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203854</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 103</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/mbina.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
	Mary Bina is a graduate from the department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science of the National Technical University of Athens. During her studies, she specialized in the area of Telecommunications an in particular in Wireless and Mobile Communications Networks and Digital Communications. Following her studies, she was admitted first in the Decision Sciences Graduate Program (E-commerce specialization) of the Athens University of Economics and Business. There, she got involved in various projects in the areas of Information Systems, E-commerce and Mobile Business applications. Her Master Thesis concerning the transformation of an existing e-business model into the mobile environment excelled among the other projects of the program. Currently she works in preparing her Doctoral Thesis in the area of Mobile Business and is also involved in research projects.  Her research interests concern wireless communities, the adoption of mobile data services, emerging mobile and wireless business models, and telecommunications policy.
	She is also a member of the Technical Chamber of Greece.
      </p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_giaglis" startdate="20040301">
			<phd-title>A Socio-Economic Perspective in Community-based WLANs Research</phd-title>
			<phd-summary>
				This phD research attempts a two-fold approach of Community-based WLANs: 
				<ul><li>Study the motives that trigger the initialization and further development of a Community WLAN project
				</li><li>Investigate the growth and evolution patterns followed by Community WLANs  
				</li></ul>In doing so, it refers to the theory of collective action and private provision of public goods. The expected contribution will be an assessment of the long-term survivability of the community model and the nature of the mechanisms to foster it. 

			</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
