<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_mdl" group="g_istlab g_iris">
	<givenname>Miltiadis</givenname>
	<surname>Lytras</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>mdl@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<office_phone>+30 2108203870</office_phone>--> <alumnus/>

<photo>../images/m_mdl.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
<b>Dr Miltiadis Lytras</b> holds a PhD degree in Information Systems (Semantic Web for Knowledge Management and Technology Enhanced Learning) from the Department of Management Science and Technology, AUEB (2004), an MBA from the AUEB (1998) and a B.Sc. Degree in Informatics from AUEB (1995).
</p>
<p>Miltiadis is the Editor in Chief of the International Journal of Knowledge and Learning <a href="(http://www.inderscience.com/ijkl)">http://www.inderscience.com/ijkl</a> as well as the Editor in Chief of International Journal of Teaching and Case Studies <a href="(http://www.inderscience.com/ijtcs)">http://www.inderscience.com/ijtcs</a>. He serves also as the Co-Editor in Chief of the International Journal on Semantic Web and Information Systems, <a href="(http://www.idea-group.com/ijswis)">http://www.idea-group.com/ijswis</a>. Recently he undertook the co-editing responsibility of the International Journal of Social and Humanistic Computing <a href="(http://www.inderscience.com/ijshc)">http://www.inderscience.com/ijshc</a> as well  as the International Journal of Entertainment Technology and Management, <a href="(http://www.inderscience.com/ijenttm)">http://www.inderscience.com/ijenttm</a>
</p>

<p>Miltiadis serves as the Editor in Chief of 'Knowledge and Learning Society Book Series', <a href="(http://www.idea-group.com/requests/details.asp?ID=121)">http://www.idea-group.com/requests/details.asp?ID=121</a>, as well as the Editor of the 'Advances on Semantic Web and Information Systems Book Series', in IDEA Group publishing. 
</p>

<p>Dr. Miltiadis Lytras is currently an Assistant Professor (407-80) in the Computer Engineering and Informatics Department-CEID (University of Patras), and in Department of Library Science and Information Systems (ATEI Athens). His research focuses on semantic web, knowledge management and e-learning, with more than 80 publications in these areas. He has co-edited and co-edits, 25 special issues in International Journals (Like IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering, IEEE Internet Computing, IEEE Transactions on Education, Journal of Knowledge Management,  British Journal on Educational Technology, Computers in Human Behavior, Education Technology and Society, etc) and has authored/edited 12 books.
</p>
<p>He is the founder and officer of the Semantic Web and Information Systems Special Interest Group in the Association for Information Systems <a href="(http://www.sigsemis.org)">http://www.sigsemis.org</a> as well as the co-founder of AIS SIG on Reusable Learning Objects and Learning Design <a href="(http://www.sigrlo.org)">http://www.sigrlo.org</a>. He serves as the Editor in Chief of 9 international journals while he is associate editor or editorial board member in seven more. He has participated in 20 R&amp;D projects and currently he serves as member of the Scientific Advisory Board of ELEGI Project, <a href="(http://www.elegi.org)">http://www.elegi.org</a>. Finally Dr. Miltiadis Lytras is the President of the OPEN RESEARCH SOCIETY, Non-Government Organization, aiming to promote the vision of the Knowledge Society worldwide.
</p>

	</shortcv>
</member>
