<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_mdl" group="g_eltrun g_iris">
	<givenname>Miltiadis</givenname>
	<surname>Lytras</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>mdl@aueb.gr</email>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203663</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203664</fax>
	<office_address>47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str.</office_address>
	<postal_address>Office 801, 47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str., GR-113 62 Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
<b>Mr Miltiadis Lytras</b> is a PhD student in the Department of Management Science and Technology at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), Greece. He holds a first degree in Informatics (AUEB, Greece), an MBA degree (AUEB) as well as a postgraduate diploma in Adults Learning (Selete Patras). His research focuses on e-learning, knowledge management and semantic web with more than 35 publications in these areas. He is guest co-editing a special issue in International Journal of Distance Education Technologies with the special theme 'Knowledge Management Technologies for E-learning as well as one in IEEE Educational Technology and Society Journal with the theme 'Ontologies and the Semantic Web for E-learning' (with Gerd Wagner, Paloma Diaz, Demetrios Sampson, Lisa Neal). He has published in Greece the book 'Knowledge Management and E-learning', while he co-edits with Professor Ambjorn Naeve the book 'Intelligent Learning Infrastructures for Knowledge Intensive Organizations: A semantic Web Perspective'. In early 2005 he will publish the authored book 'Knowledge Management Strategies: Applied Technologies Handbook' in IDEA Group. He is the founder of the Semantic Web and Information Systems Special Interest Group in Association for Information Systems and he serves on the SIG Board (www.sigsemis.org). He has been a program committee member in 8 international conferences and he serves in the editorial board of two international journals. His teaching experience especially in adults seminars exceeds 3500 hours in themes like e-business, Information Systems, Knowledge Management, E-learning, IT skills and management. He has participated in fifteen Greek and European funded projects. Miltiadis can be reached by e-mail at <a href="mdl@aueb.gr">mdl@aueb.gr</a>
</p>

	</shortcv>
</member>
