<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_nikas" group="g_istlab g_ois">
	<givenname>Athanasios</givenname>
	<surname>Nikas</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>nikas@aueb.gr</email>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203755</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203756</fax>
	<office_address>1 Derigni St.</office_address>
	<postal_address>76 Patission St., GR104 34, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
		Mr. Athanasios Nikas is a candidate Ph.D. researcher in the Department of Management Science and Technology at the Athens University of Economics and Business. He holds a bachelor's degree from the Department of Financial and Banking Management at the University of Piraeus (2000) in Greece and a Master's degree in the Analysis, Design and Management of Information Systems obtained at the London School of Economics and Political Science (2001). Currently, he works as a research officer and as a financial director of the <a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/">ISTLab</a>/<a href="../groups/g_ois-details.html">OIS</a>.  He has a broad research and project management experience stemming from his full involvement in the EU project DOMINO IST-2000-29545 (Dynamic Organisational Management for Inter-firm Network Orchestrations while also in 2003 and 2005 he accumulated a consulting experience by working as an organizer and rapporteur in the Working Group E3 and H2 of the Greek eBusiness Forum (www.ebusinessfotum.gr) initiative organized by the Hellenic Republic Ministry of Development. Finally, it is worth mentioning that his PhD research is funded from the Hellenic Republic Ministry of Education under the HRAKLEITOS scholarships programme.
		</p>
</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_akp" startdate="20020123">
		<phd-title>The adoption of collaborative technologies in project based teams: Investigating the role of collaboration intensity in individuals' perceptions and beliefs</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
		<p>
		 The research interest is focusing on studying the social and organisational dynamics which underlie recent technological and work developments in networked organisations. In the effort of investigating factors affecting the intention to adopt collaborative technologies in project based organizations for improving project management and coordination it is interesting to study: 'How best to develop a research framework that organizes and guides research efforts as well as offering insights to management practice. This effort is based on investigating the influence of collaboration intensity of team members on their attitudes and beliefs regarding the adoption of collaborative technologies in project work'. Further, the research challenge is to study the social and organisational dynamics which underlie recent technological and work developments in project based organizational settings. Finally, the empirical data of my study are extracted from both qualitative (case study) and quantitative methods (survey analysis) by applying structural equation modelling techniques.
		</p>
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>