<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_nikas" group="g_istlab g_ois">
	<givenname>Athanasios</givenname>
	<surname>Nikas</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>nikas@aueb.gr</email>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203755</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203756</fax>
	<office_address>1 Derigni St.</office_address>
	<postal_address>76 Patission St., GR104 34, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
		Mr. ATHANASIOS NIKAS was born in 1976 in Greece. He holds a bachelor's degree from the Department of Financial and Banking Management at the University of Piraeus (2000) in Greece and a Master's degree in the Analysis, Design and Management of Information Systems obtained at the London School of Economics and Political Science (2001). Since 2002, he is a candidate Ph.D. researcher in the Department of Management Science and Technology at the Athens University of Economics and Business. His research interest is focusing on studying the social and organisational dynamics which underlie recent technological and work developments in networked organisations. Currently, he works as a research officer in <a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/">ISTLab</a>/<a href="../groups/g_ois-details.html">OIS</a>. He has a broad research and project management experience stemming from his full involvement in the EU project DOMINO IST-2000-29545 (Dynamic Organisational Management for Inter-firm Network Orchestrations (www.ist-domino.net) while also in 2003 he accumulated a consulting experience by working as an organizer and rapporteur in the Working Group E3 of the Greek eBusiness Forum (www.ebusinessfotum.gr) initiative organized by the Hellenic Republic Ministry of Development. Finally, it is worth mentioning that his PhD research is funded from the Hellenic Republic Ministry of Education under the HRAKLEITOS scholarships programme.
		</p>
</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="0" supervisor="m_akp" startdate="20031014">
		<phd-title>Networked Information Infrastructures</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
		<p>
		Changes in technologies and market structures have shifted competition between organizations to a global level. This has resulted in the need for new organizational structures. Traditional organizational structures are not appropriate for the new business trends because they evolved in response to different and older competitive eras. In the information era, a responsive IT infrastructure is crucial to the flexibility and constantly changing needs of a business organization. It seems that in this very difficult and competitive environment the only change is constants and uncertainty. This turbulent business environment is forcing organizations to re-evaluate totally their processes and structures, indicating an increasing need for networking and cooperative arrangements.
		</p>
		<p>
		The proposed research seeks to identify and understand impacts in business and work practices in a network organizational setting created specifically by the introduction of new information system supporting collaboration and information resource sharing. This information system is leading to the creation of a network information infrastructure. Specifically, we will focus on particular management issues emerging at a network and single-firm level through the creation of a network information infrastructure.
		</p>
		<p>
		A major concern among information systems (IS) practitioners today is: 'How best to leverage information technology (IT) capabilities to restructure business relationships across networked organizations to obtain firm-level strategic advantage', while a corresponding question for IS researchers is: 'How best to develop a research framework that organizes and guides research efforts as well as offering insights to management practice, and specifically in managing relations, based on information sharing'. In this context, in our research we are interested in researching the implications that a common information infrastructure creates, in terms of: 'how it affects pre-existing work-practices within/between networked organizations as they explicitly leverage network IT capabilities. Our research challenge is to study the social and organisational dynamics which underlie recent technological and work developments in networked organisations. 
		</p>
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>