<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_nmylonop" group="g_istlab g_wrc">
	<givenname>Nikolaos</givenname>
	<surname>Mylonopoulos</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>nmylonop@alba.edu.gr</email>
	<web_site>http://www.alba.edu.gr/faculty/Pages/Mylonopoulos.aspx</web_site>
	<!--<office_phone></office_phone>-->
	<!--<mobile_phone>+30 2108203685</mobile_phone>-->
	<alumnus/>
	<!--<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 901</office_address>-->
	<!--<postal_address>Patision 76, GR-104 34 Athens, Greece</postal_address>-->
	<photo>http://www.alba.edu.gr/faculty/PublishingImages/nikosmylonopoulos.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
<p>Dr. Mylonopoulos has teaching and research interests in the areas of Information Systems Management, Electronic Business and Mobile Commerce. He has taught at Loughborough University Business School, Warwick Business School, Birkbeck College (University of London), Bordeaux School of Management and the Athens University of Economics and Business. Since 2001 he is Visiting Professor of Electronic Business at the Bordeaux School of Management, France.</p>

<p>His research emphasizes on the management and economics of Information Systems in organizations and society. Among others, recent topics of interest include the strategic outsourcing of information technology services and the economic analysis of mobile commerce business models. His work has been published in international refereed journals and conferences, including the International Transactions in OR, the Communications of the ACM, and the International Journal of Electronic Commerce.</p>

<p>He has served as guest editor for the British Journal of Management, the Journal of the OR Society and the Journal of Knowledge and Process Management and is co-editor of the International Journal of Information Technology Education. Recently he co-organised the Third European Conference on Organizational Knowledge, Learning and Capabilities and was Program Chair of the First International Conference on Mobile Business.</p>

<p>Dr. Mylonopoulos has been actively involved in over ten national and European funded research projects in the areas of telematics, electronic business, mobile commerce and recently eBusiness in Eastern Europe. He has served on various national advisory boards and committees and has consulted large organizations.</p>

<p>Dr Mylonopoulos is a member of the Association for Information Systems, the UK Academy for Information Systems, the Information Resource Management Association and the Greek Computer Society.</p>
	</shortcv>
</member>
