<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_pkour" group="g_eltrun g_wrc">
	<givenname>Panos</givenname>
	<surname>Kourouthanassis</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>pkour@aueb.gr</email>
	<web_site>http://www.eltrun.gr/wrc/WRC_pkour_v1.html</web_site>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203663</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203664</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 801</office_address>
	<postal_address>Patision 76, GR-104 34 Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<!--<photo>../images/spi.jpg</photo>-->
	<shortcv>
Panos Kourouthanassis has graduated from the Athens University of Economics and Business, 
Department of Informatics. He holds a Masters Degree in Decision Sciences and he is 
currently completing his PhD thesis on designing pervasive information systems. 
Mr. Panos Kourouthanassis has extensive research experience. Since 1996, he is a Research 
Officer in ELTRUN research group (hosted within the Athens University of Economics and Business) 
which is actively involved in the area of eBusiness. For the past years, he has been involved in 
numerous leading edge European research projects as information systems analyst or project manager.
<br /><br />
His main research interests lie in the areas of eBusiness (emphasising on mobile and wireless 
applications and services), ubiquitous computing, software engineering, and information systems 
design. He has already co-organised a dedicated workshop and a research track on ubiquitous 
commerce on leading International Conferences focused on ubiquitous computing. His research work 
on the proposition of innovative wireless information systems for the retail sector enhancing 
consumers shopping experience received the Gold Award in the 4th ECR Student Award programme. 
Since 2002 he participates as Research Officer in the ELTRUN Wireless Research Group (ELTRUN/WRC) 
which pursues research in innovative mBusiness models, assessment of new mobile/wireless technologies, 
applications and services development, and others.
	</shortcv>
</member>
