<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_pkour" group="g_istlab g_wrc">
	<givenname>Dr. Panos</givenname>
	<surname>Kourouthanassis</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>pkour@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=Kourouthanassis</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203855</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203854</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 103</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<!--<photo>../images/spi.jpg</photo>-->
	<shortcv>
	   <p>Dr. Panos E. Kourouthanassis holds a PhD in Information Systems and an MSc in Decision Sciences specialised in eBusiness. He is currently adjunct lecturer at the University of the Aegean and senior research officer at the Wireless Research Center of the Athens University of Economics and Business.
	   He is also co-editor of an edited volume on Pervasive Information Systems and member of the executive board of the AIS special interest group on Mobile and Ubiquitous Information Systems (SIGMUBIS).</p>

	   <p>Dr. Kourouthanassis has extensive research experience. For the past ten years, he has been involved in numerous leading edge European research projects as project manager. He has published over 20 research papers on scientific journals and European conferences. His main research interests lie in the areas of eBusiness (emphasising on mobile and wireless applications and services), pervasive and ubiquitous computing, software engineering, and information systems design.</p>
           <p>Dr. Kourouthanassis has co-organised dedicated workshops and research tracks on pervasive and ubiquitous computing on leading International Conferences.
	   His research work on the proposition of innovative wireless information systems for the retail sector that enhance consumers' shopping experience received the Gold Award in the 4th ECR Student Award programme. He is a member of ECR Europe (Academics), the International Society of Logistics (SOLE), and the Association for Information Systems (AIS).</p>	
	</shortcv>
</member>
