<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_pmichael" group="g_istlab">
	<givenname>Georgios P.</givenname>
	<surname>Papamichail</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>pmichael@aueb.gr</email>
	<web_site>http://dmst.aueb.gr/pmichael/</web_site>
	<!--<office_phone>+30 2108203654</office_phone>-->
	<!--<mobile_phone>+30 2108203685</mobile_phone>-->
	<alumnus/>
	<!--<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 901</office_address>-->
	<!--<postal_address>Patision 76, GR-104 34 Athens, Greece</postal_address>-->
<!--	<photo></photo>-->
	<shortcv>
<p>
Georgios P.Papamichail (professional name George Papamichail) is Adjunct Assistant Professor in Information Systems at the Department of Management Science and Technology at the Athens University of Economics and Business. He received his Ph.D from the Department of Informatics at the same University and his B.Sc in Computer Engineering and Informatics from the University of Patras. Currently he acts as a senior researcher of the Eltrun (The E-Business Center) at the Athens University of Economics and Business. His main research interests lie in web information systems and algorithms for decision making. These topics provide powerful methods in dealing with problems arising in a wide range of areas. He has more than 20 publications, in areas ranging from group decision making methodologies ( e.g., distributed decision making, mediated group memory) to the applied (e.g., computational geometry, fuzzy clustering, technology transfer and Internet computing).
He enjoys teaching and, in particular, a good part of his efforts aims at helping young people to get acquainted with information system concepts. Currently he teaches information and modern database management systems, e-commerce, programming languages and algorithms. In 2002 he received a teaching award from the Department of Management Science and Technology, Athens University of Economics and Business. 
</p>
<p>For more information please visit his	
<a href="http://dmst.aueb.gr/pmichael/">personal web page</a>
</p>
	</shortcv>
</member>
