<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_pouloudi" group="g_eltrun g_iris">
	<givenname>Nancy</givenname>
	<surname>Pouloudi</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>pouloudi@aueb.gr</email>
	<web_site>http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~pouloudi/</web_site>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203687</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203685</fax>
	<office_address>47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str.</office_address>
	<postal_address>Office 907, 47A Evelpidon &amp; 33 Lefkados Str., GR-113 62 Athens, Greece</postal_address>
<photo>../images/m_pouloudi.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
<b>Dr Athanasia (Nancy) Pouloudi</b> is an Assistant Professor in the Department of Management Science and Technology at the Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB), Greece. She holds a first degree in Informatics (AUEB, Greece), and an MSc and PhD degree in Information Systems (London School of Economics, UK). Her research focuses on strategic and social issues in information systems, specialising in electronic commerce, knowledge management and stakeholder issues with more than 70 publications in these areas. She is Associate Editor of the European Journal of Information Systems, member of the Editorial Board of the Journal of Electronic Commerce in Organizations and the International Journal of Society, Information, Communication and Ethics and has served as Programme Committee member in several international conferences. She has taught information systems at Brunel University (as lecturer) and the London School of Economics (as teaching assistant) and held visiting positions at Erasmus University (The Netherlands), the University of Hawai (USA) and the Athens Laboratory of Business Administration (Greece). She has acted as scientific coordinator for AUEB in a number European Projects. She is co-director of the 7th ETHICOMP conference and track chair for e-work and virtual organisations in the European Conference on Information Systems 2004. Nancy can be reached by e-mail at pouloudi@aueb.gr or through her home page at <a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~pouloudi/">http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~pouloudi/</a>.

</p>

	</shortcv>
</member>
