<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_pz" group="g_istlab g_ois" joined="20011014">
	<givenname>Panagiotis </givenname>
	<surname>Zaharias</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>pz@aueb.gr</email>
	<web_site>http://www.eltrun.gr/cvs/Zaharias_Panagiotis.pdf</web_site>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203755</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203756</fax>
	<office_address>1 Derigni St.</office_address>
	<postal_address>76 Patission St., GR104 34, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
		Dr. Panagiotis Zaharias holds a first degree in Informatics from the Department of Informatics in Athens University of Economics and Business (1998), and a Masters degree in Information Systems from the MSc. Program in Information Systems in Athens University of Economics and Business (2000). He also holds a Ph.D. degree in Information Systems (specialization on Human Computer Interaction, thesis title: A Usability Evaluation Method of E-learning Courses) from the Department of Management Science and Technology of Athens University of Economics and Business (2004). His main research interests are focused on user-centred design, usability evaluation and e-Learning design. Panagiotis has an extensive research experience. He has participated in various European and National-based research projects. He has published more than 20 papers in scientific journals and conference proceedings. He has also co-organised dedicated research tracks on usability and e-learning design in leading International Conferences focused on human-computer interaction. Panagiotis is a member of ACM Special Interest Group on Human-Computer Interaction (SIGCHI) and AACE (Association for the Advancement of Computing in Education) organization. He has been a member of <a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/">ISTLab</a> for 10 years and now he is a research associate of <a href="../groups/g_ois-details.html">OIS</a> where he is undertaking research and e-learning consulting projects. Dr. Panagiotis Zaharias is currently a Lecturer (407/80) at the Department of Product and Systems Design Engineering of the University of the Aegean, Greece.
		</p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_akp" startdate="20011014">
		<phd-title>
		A Usability Evaluation Method for E-Learning Courses
		</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
		A Usability Evaluation Method for E-Learning Courses
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
