<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_vlachos" group="g_istlab g_sense">
	<givenname>Vasileios</givenname>
	<surname>Vlachos</surname>
	<memb_title>Dr.</memb_title>
	<email>vbill@aueb.gr</email>
	<web_site>http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~vbill/</web_site>
	<office_phone>+30 2108203370</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203664</fax>
	<office_address>76 Patission Str.</office_address>
	<postal_address>76 Patission Str., 10434, Athens, 
Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_vlachos.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
Vasileios Vlachos holds a Dipl. Eng. in Electronic &amp; Computer Engineering from 
the Technical University of Crete, Greece and a M.Sc. in Integrated Hardware 
and Software Systems from the Department of Computer Engineering and 
Informatics of the University of Patras, Greece. His Master's Thesis was 
completed at the Interuniversity MicroElectronics Center (IMEC), Leuven, 
Belgium. Since October 2002 he is pursuing his PhD Thesis at the Department of 
Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and 
Business, in the area of Computer Information Security. He has also been 
involved in various national and EU funded R&amp;D projects. Currently his work is funded by the Greek government under the "IRAKLITOS" program. Mr. Vlachos is a member of IEEE and IEEE Computer Society, member of the Technical Chamber of Greece and the Hellenic 
Linux Users Group. His research interests include: Computer Information 
Security, Telemetry, Low Power Computing and Real Time Operating Systems
      </p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_dds" startdate="20031114">
		<phd-title>Security applications of p2p networks</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
			Open networks are often insecure and provide an opportunity for viruses and DDOS activities to spread. To make such networks more resilient against these kind of threats, we propose the use of a peer-to-peer architecture whereby each peer is responsible for: (a) detecting whether a virus or worm is uncontrollably propagating through the network resulting in an epidemic; (b) automatically dispatching warnings and information to other peers of a security-focused group; and (c) taking specific precautions for protecting their host by automatically hardening their security measures during the epidemic. This can lead to auto-adaptive secure operating systems that automatically change the trust level of the services they provide.
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
