<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_vzeimp" group="g_istlab g_wrc" joined="20021101">
	<givenname>Vasileios</givenname>
	<surname>Zeimpekis</surname>
	<memb_title>Mr.</memb_title>
	<email>vzeimp@aueb.gr</email>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org/mobiforum/wrc_member.php?name=Zeimpekis</web_site>-->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203855</office_phone>
	<fax>+30 2108203854</fax>
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 103</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/vzeimp.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
Eur. Ing. Vasileios Zeimpekis is Adjunct Lecturer in the Department of Financial &amp; Management Engineering in the University of the Aegean, where he is also involved in a series of European and National research projects. He is also Scientific Associate in the Department of Management Science &amp; Technology at the Athens University of Economics and Business (GR). His interests focus on Road Transportation and Logistics with emphasis on wireless and mobile applications, location-based services, positioning techniques and telematics. He has published more than 30 papers and studies in scientific journals, international conferences and trade journals and has also been appointed as a Lecturer /Official Instructor in Master degrees courses and Executive Seminars. He acts also as an independent consultant and trainer in many private and public firms as well as in the Hellenic Ministry of Development. Vasileios acts as a reviewer in various Academic Journals as well as in General Secretariat of Research and Technology and the Hellenic Initiative <i>Information Society</i>, which operate under the supervision of the Hellenic Ministry of Development.</p>
		<p>
Vasileios, holds a BEng(Hons) in Telecommunications Engineering from the University of Essex, (UK). He has also been awarded with an MSc in Mobile &amp; Satellite Communications from the University of Surrey (UK) and an MSc with Distinction in Engineering Business Management from the University of Warwick (UK). Vasileios is currently completing his PhD in the area of Real-time Fleet Management Systems in Urban Distributions. </p>
<p>
Vasileios is Member of the European Technical Chamber (FEANI), of the Technical Chamber of Greece, of the Institute of Electrical &amp; Electronic Engineers (MIEEE), of the Institute of Electrical Engineers (MIEE), of the Hellenic Logistics Organisation (SOLE/EEL), of the Hellenic Management Association, and of the Institute of Operations Management.</p>
</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="1" supervisor="m_giaglis" startdate="20021101" enddate="20080218">
		<phd-title>Design and Evaluation of a Real-time Fleet Management System for Dynamic Incident Handling in Urban Freight Distributions</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>In urban freight movement a good, near-optimal, distribution plan is necessary but not sufficient for high performance distribution. This is mainly due to the probabilistic factors that urban movement depends on, such as high levels of traffic congestion, weather conditions, tight delivery time windows, vehicle breakdowns, unexpected events and so on. The aim of this PhD thesis is the design and evaluation of a real-time fleet management system that handles in a dyanmic way unexpected events during urban freight distribution so as to reduce delivery delays and increase customer service. 
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
