<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_xz" group="g_istlab g_iris" joined="20031114">
	<givenname>Xenia</givenname>
	<surname>Ziouvelou</surname>
	<memb_title>Ms.</memb_title>
	<email>xeniaziouvelou@hotmail.com</email>
	<shortcv>
		<p>
<b>Xenia Ziouvelou</b> holds a Ph.D. degree in Economics focusing on industrial organisation and strategic pricing in electronic markets and a Masters Degree in International Business from the Department of Economics of the Lancaster University (UK). She has also been awarded with a B.Sc in Business Administration, with specialization in Quality and Operations Management, from the American College of Greece. 
 
For more than three years Xenia held the position of a Research Officer at the Athens University of Economics and Business in the research center ELTRUN, the e-Business Center of the Department of Management Science and Technology. Her research focused on business modeling in the context of Electronic Commerce. Xenia worked as a Project Manager in the IST Project E-FACTORS, which aimed at determining factors of broad and sustainable adoption of new e-business models. Since September 2005, she is a member of the IRIS Research Group of the Information Systems Technology Laboratory (ISTLab) of the Athens University of Economics and Business, while she acts as an external expert for H+S Technology Solutions S.A.
 
Dr. Xenia Ziouvelou is currently a Teaching and Research Fellow at the Management of Business, Innovation and Technology (MBIT) program at Athens Information Technology (AIT). Her principal research interests are in Industrial Organisation analysis and Electronic Commerce as well as in Strategic Pricing, Business Modeling and Business Strategy in Technology Mediated Markets.
</p>
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="1" supervisor-external="Professor Robert Rothschild (Lancaster University)" startdate="20010514" enddate="20070315">
		<phd-title>Price Dynamics in Internet-Enabled Markets: A Multidimensional Analysis</phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
This thesis investigates the impact of technology on the nature of price competition. Specifically it examines 
rivalry and the level of friction in Internet retail markets using a multidimensional approach covering 
both macro and micro analytic perspectives of online price dynamics.
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
