<?xml version="1.0"?>
<member id="m_zamani" group="g_istlab g_wrc" joined="20090501">
	<givenname>Efpraxia</givenname>
	<surname>Zamani</surname>
	<memb_title>Ms.</memb_title>
	<email>ezamani@aueb.gr</email>
	<!-- <web_site>Optional</web_site> -->
	<office_phone>+30 2108203855</office_phone>
	<!-- <mobile_phone>Optional</mobile_phone> -->
	<fax>+30 2108203854</fax>
	<!-- <alumnus/> --> <!-- Optional -->
	<office_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, Room 103</office_address>
	<postal_address>Evelpidon 47-A &amp; Lefkados 33, 11362, Athens, Greece</postal_address>
	<photo>../images/m_zamani.jpg</photo>
	<shortcv>
	Efrpaxia Zamani holds a Bachelor Degree in Architecture from the
Faculty of Engineering, AUTH. She has been awarded with an MA
in Museum Studies from the University of Leicester and an MSc in
Finance &amp;  Management Engineering from the Aegean University.
She has received a scholarship from the Department of Financial &amp;
Management Engineering, Aegean University
Efpraxia is currently studying toward her PhD in Pervasive Information
Systems in the Department of Management Science and Technology
of Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece. Her main
research interests lie in the area of Pervasive Information Systems and
Adoption Theories.	
	</shortcv>
	<phd-info completed="0" 
			  supervisor="m_giaglis"
			  startdate="20090419">
		<phd-title>The role of Emotions and Aesthetics toward the adoption of Pervasive Information Systems Adoption </phd-title>
		<phd-summary>
			Pervasive Information Systems constitute an emerging class of Information Systems that are
embedded within our physical environment, constantly collecting information in the form of input
from the user and the environment itself so as to continuously readjust their function and implicitly
respond to user needs and requirements. However, research in the field of user acceptance and
adoption of Information Systems has been largely concerned with the cognitive aspect of usage,
focusing more on the predictive strength of factors such as Performance and Effort Expectancy.
These are elements that are no longer central to the context of use of Pervasive Information
Systems. The current study proposes a new research framework that has in its core the affective
qualities of Pervasive Information Systems and develops by exploring their impact on the user
Emotional State.
		
		</phd-summary>
	</phd-info>
</member>
