<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="p_e-factors" group="g_eltrun g_iris" scientific_coordinator="m_pouloudi" contact="m_pouloudi" international="yes" type="rtd" project_manager="m_xz">
	<shortname>e-Factors</shortname>
	<projtitle>E-factors: A thematic network in e-business models</projtitle>
	<startdate>20020301</startdate>
	<enddate>20030930</enddate>
	<web_site>http://www.e-factors.net/</web_site>
	<our_budget>266,850 EUR</our_budget>
	<total_budget>1,500,000 EUR</total_budget>
	<funding_agency>European Commission</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>IST</funding_programme>
	<project_code>IST-2001-34868</project_code>
	<partner>
		<shortname>University of Surrey</shortname>
		<country>UK</country>
		<web_site>http://www.surrey.ac.uk/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Copenhagen Business School</shortname>
		<country>DK</country>
		<web_site>http://www.cbs.dk/indexuk.html/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Athens Laboratory of Business Administration</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.alba.edu.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>University of Cologne</shortname>
		<country>DE</country>
		<web_site>http://www.uni-koeln.de/index.e.html</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Erasmus University</shortname>
		<country>NL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.e-circles.org/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Norwegian School of Economics &amp; Business Administration</shortname>
		<country>NO</country>
		<web_site>http://www.nhh.no/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>European Institute of Business Administration (INSEAD)</shortname>
		<country>FR</country>
<web_site>http://www.insead.fr/</web_site>
	</partner>
		<partner>
		<shortname>University of Jyvaskyla</shortname>
		<country>FIN</country>
<web_site>http://www.jyu.fi//</web_site>
	</partner>	
<partner>
		<shortname>INTRACOM </shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
<web_site>http://www.intracom.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
<partner>
		<shortname>FHG-FOKUS </shortname>
		<country>GE</country>
<web_site>http://www.fraunhofer.de/english/index.html</web_site>
	</partner>
<partner>
		<shortname>IBERINCO</shortname>
		<country>ES</country>
<web_site>http://www.iberinco.es/</web_site>
	</partner>
<partner>
		<shortname>Virtual Enterprises Architects BV </shortname>
		<country>NL</country>
<web_site>http://www.vearchitects.com/</web_site>
	</partner>

<partner>
		<shortname>Waterford Institute of Technology</shortname>
		<country>IRE</country>
<web_site>http://www.tssg.org/</web_site>
	</partner>
<partner>
		<shortname>Georgia State University</shortname>
		<country>USA</country>
<web_site>http://www.gsu.edu/gsuhome-v1/enhanced.html</web_site>
	</partner>
	<description>
<!--PROSOXI,afto einai 'Integrated project'kai oxi 'rtd'-PREPEI NA EISAXTHEI 1 KATHGORIA GIA INTEGRATED PROJECTS-->
<p><b>Objective:</b> The E-factors project has set up a thematic network dedicated to bringing together universities, research centres and practitioners with a common objective: to determine factors of broad and sustainable adoption of new business models based on e-Business practices and research expertise across Europe. The E-Factors network has actively sought to transfer skills and experiences with a view to generating strategic implications in the implementation of e-business models and disseminating this knowledge across Europe. 
</p>
<p>Objectives:
</p>
<ul>
<li>To collect, organise and disseminate experiences gained in individual projects on market opportunities and constraints.
</li> 
<li>To develop a list of common issues and ideas as to how individual project results (both in terms of findings and in terms of methods of research work adopted) can be combined and further developed to produce complementary results.
</li>
<li>To construct a report that the EU can use to formulate future strategic implications. Knowledge will be drawn from the expertise of leading universities and current IST projects conducting research in e-business models as well as their adoption and their socio-economic implications.
</li>
<li>To develop means, to support the dissemination of the combined knowledge of the thematic network participants to a broad range of stakeholders within Europe.
</li>
<li>To promote and guide further research and development in the area of e-business model adoption through the collaboration of academe and industry.
</li>
</ul>
<p>Work description:</p>
<p>E-Factors is scheduled to cover a period of 18 months. The work plan of E-Factors has been structured around 6 work-packages. WP1 was concerned with E-factors project management structure that glued together and co-ordinated all project activities. WP2 was concerned with setting up a Web-based infrastructure that allowed for collaborative work to be carried out between network participants and has also served as the project's prime dissemination medium, allowing the general public to have direct access to the project's findings and results. WP3 included all preliminary work directed towards the identification of priority thematic areas for e-business models adoption. The results of this work has fed into WP4, which examined a number of best business practice cases on e-business models drawn from the participants' experiences and expertise. This has in turn fed into WP5, which was concerned with selecting and combining available output from previous work conducted from current IST projects (that participate in the network) and contributed towards the development of education material in e-business models. Furthermore, drawing on the results of the previous work-packages this has lead to the production of a report on e-business models that suggests strategic implications for future adoption.
</p>
<p>Finally, the results of all the previous WPs will be combined by WP6 into a wide spectrum of activities aiming at disseminating the project's findings and raising public awareness about E-business models' adoption. Amongst these activities, a dedicated session on E-business models under the auspices of a major European Conference in E-commerce (Bled Conference 2003) has been organized. 
</p>
<b>Milestones:</b>
<p>Milestone I: Establishment of Thematic Network [Month 6];</p>
<p>Milestone II: Efficiency and Growth of Thematic Network [Month 14];</p> 
<p>Milestone III: Self Sustained Thematic Network [Month 18].</p>

	</description>
</project>
