<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="p_eprocurement" group="g_istlab g_wrc" scientific_coordinator="m_giaglis" contact="m_pkour" international="no" type="rtd" project_manager="m_pkour">
	<shortname>eProcurement</shortname>
	<projtitle>Development of an eBusiness platform for data exchange support between stores with headquarters and warehouses</projtitle>
	<startdate>20030401</startdate>
	<enddate>20040731</enddate>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobinet.gr</web_site>-->
	<!--<our_budget>328,627 EUR</our_budget>-->
	<!--<total_budget>3,493,834 EUR</total_budget>-->
	<funding_agency>General Secretariat of Research and Technology</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>Development of Industrial Research and Technology in New Businesses (PAVET-NE)</funding_programme>
	<!--<project_code>Action 8.3.6</project_code>-->
	<partner>
		<shortname>Information Systems Impact</shortname>
		<country>GR</country>
		<web_site>http://www.impact.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
			
	<!--<logo>../images/p_mexpress.gif</logo>-->
	<description>
 <p>

	    		The	project examines the prospects of innovative e-commerce technologies for the
				automation and integration of supply chain processes that play a pivotal role
				in retailing. Emphasis is given in the process of procurement. The main aim of
				the project is the design and implementation of a business and technological
				e-business solution/platform focusing on the improvement and support of the
				communication and exchange processes between the collaborative parties of a
				business group or between chain stores (stressing the process of procurement
				between the headquarters, the stores and the warehouse). Apart from the design
				and evaluation of a prototype system, a pilot operation of the platform will
				also take place in real-life situations.Research issues that will be tackled during the project comprise:
				algorithms for stock replenishment, implementation of methods for stock
				estimation with the use of statistical and econometrical algorithms, full
				integration with ERP systems, RFQs management, and integration with methods of
				triangular markets etc.
</p>
	</description>
</project>
