<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="p_eTransport" group="g_istlab g_wrc" scientific_coordinator="m_giaglis" contact="m_alextsiaousis" international="no" type="rtd" project_manager="m_alextsiaousis">
	<shortname>e-Transport</shortname>
	<projtitle>Development of a system that combines electronic tickets, customer loyalty and physical acess control services for transportation.</projtitle>
	<startdate>20060301</startdate>
	<enddate>20071130</enddate>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobinet.gr</web_site>-->
	<!--<our_budget>328,627 EUR</our_budget>-->
	<!--<total_budget>3,493,834 EUR</total_budget>-->
	<funding_agency>General Secretariat of Research and Technology</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>Operational Programme "Competitiveness" (EPAN)</funding_programme>
	<!--<project_code>Action 8.3.6</project_code>-->
	<partner>
		<shortname>Inform P. Lykos</shortname>
		<country>GR</country>
		<!--<web_site>http://www.voiceweb.gr/</web_site>-->
	</partner>
			
	<!--<logo>../images/p_mexpress.gif</logo>-->
	<description>
The project involves the  development of an integrated platform (e-transport) that provides the issue and reservation of electronic tickets. Tickets can be purchased from pre-defined kiosks through the use of smart cards.  
The platform increases customer loyalty and serves as an access control provider to ensure enhanced security levels, with the employment of Radio Frequency IDentification (RFID) and smart card technologies. 
The e-transport platform is constituted by three main parts:<ol>
<li>Core information system</li><li>
Smart cards</li><li>
Ticket Kiosks</li></ol>

The e-transport's advantages apply in several forms of transportation. In particular, the e-transport platform can be used in naval shipping, where companies can benefit from e-transport considering the frequent itineraries taking place daily. The same advantages apply in railway as well, especially in routes involving cabins. 
The end users of e-transport are not solely the aforementioned providers but most of all are the travelers that can benefit from the use of e-transport's services in terms of enhanced quality of service and security.


	</description>
</project>

