<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="p_mexpress" group="g_eltrun g_sense g_wrc" scientific_coordinator="m_dds" contact="m_dds" international="yes" type="rtd" project_manager="m_pateli">
	<shortname>mExpress</shortname>
	<projtitle>mobile in-EXhibition PRovision of Electronic Support Services</projtitle>
	<startdate>20020305</startdate>
	<enddate>20040401</enddate>
	<web_site>http://mexpress.intranet.gr/</web_site>
	<our_budget>328,627 EUR</our_budget>
	<total_budget>3,493,834 EUR</total_budget>
	<funding_agency>European Commission</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>IST</funding_programme>
	<project_code>IST-2001-33432</project_code>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Intracom</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.intracom.gr</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Ericsson</shortname>
		<country>DK</country>
		<web_site>http://www.ericsson.com/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>ELISA</shortname>
		<country>FIN</country>
		<web_site>http://www.elisa.com</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>POULIADIS</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.pouliadis.gr</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>SSF</shortname>
		<country>FIN</country>
		<web_site>http://www.ssf.fi/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>HUT</shortname>
		<country>FIN</country>
		<web_site>http://www.hut.fi</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>FFC</shortname>
		<country>FIN</country>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>ROTA</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.rota.gr</web_site>
	</partner>
	<logo>../images/p_mexpress.gif</logo>
	<description>
mEXPRESS aims to exploit the technological opportunities arising from
evolution in the areas of wireless networks and positioning mechanisms in
order to support and facilitate the professional exhibition industry in
a context-aware manner. It will contribute to the economic development of
the Community by providing means for efficient operation and interaction
in information-rich environments such as exhibitions, and significantly
enhancing promotional activities and business communications. The mEXPRESS
project will provide an integrated mediation platform (mEXPRESS Service
Provider) oriented to exhibition shows and events that will satisfy
three types of objectives:
	<ul>
			<li>Enhance and facilitate visitors experience in terms of interaction and functionality in an information-rich environment such as an exhibition show.</li>
			<li>Improve business communications and promotions within the exhibition and extend promotional effectiveness during and after the exhibition</li>
			<li>Assist and support exhibition management and operations by offering real-time location information of persons within the exhibition.</li>
		</ul>
	</description>
</project>
