<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="p_mobicom" group="g_eltrun g_wrc" scientific_coordinator="m_gjd" international="yes" type="rtd">
	<shortname>mobiCom</shortname>
	<projtitle>Evolution Scenarios for Emerging m-Commerce Services</projtitle>
	<startdate>20001201</startdate>
	<enddate>20011231</enddate>
	<web_site>http://www.mobiforum.org</web_site>
	<!--<our_budget>328,627 EUR</our_budget>-->
	<!--<total_budget>3,493,834 EUR</total_budget>-->
	<funding_agency>European Commission</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>IST</funding_programme>
	<!--<project_code>IST-2001-26239</project_code>-->
	<partner>
		<shortname>LRF</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<!--<web_site>http://www.aitek.it</web_site>-->
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Stet Hellas</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.telestet.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>COL</shortname>
		<country>D</country>
		<!--<web_site>http://www.ec3.at</web_site>-->
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>VPE</shortname>
		<country>D</country>
		<!--<web_site>http://www.fokus.fhg.de</web_site>-->
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Crediteform</shortname>
		<country>D</country>
		<!--<web_site>www.rand.org</web_site>-->
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>JyU</shortname>
		<country>FIN</country>
		<web_site>http://www.jyu.fi</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Sonera</shortname>
		<country>FIN</country>
		<web_site>http://www.sonera.fi</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>UoB</shortname>
		<country>UK</country>
		<web_site>http://www.brighton.ac.uk</web_site>
	</partner>
	<!--<logo>../images/p_mexpress.gif</logo>-->
	<description>
MobiCom aimed to explore the fundamental factors affecting the evolution of Mobile
e-Commerce, such as market structure, key players, technology
architectures, consumer behaviour, new products and services. Towards this
aim the following objectives were pursued:
<br />
<ul>
<li>
Identification of existing factors deriving from mobile communications and e-Commerce
industries, which enable or constrain the development of m-Commerce in
Europe.
</li>
<li>
Identification of new development trajectories emerging from the convergence of
mobile communications technologies and e-Commerce entrepreneurial
activities.
</li>
<li>
Description and specification of new business models and services as well as of
diffusion and adoption patterns in m-Commerce.
</li>
<li>
Preparation of guidelines on regulation and policy for facilitating the growth of m-Commerce.
</li>
<li>
Consensus building, dissemination and interaction of m-Commerce stakeholders
</li>
</ul>
<br />
MobiCom was divided into 3 phases. The first phase comprised an analysis of the
mobile communications and e-Commerce sectors, exhibiting the fundamental
characteristics of the two industries driving their evolution and growth.
The second phase assessed the industry convergence, technological
evolution and potential market growth in m-Commerce. New services and
applications were assessed against socio-economic factors affecting
their adoption and diffusion. Feasibility studies provided input on
the commercialisation process and market readiness. The third phase
involved a socio-economic analysis on the intensity of new market
evolution. To this end m-Commerce evolution scenarios were developed
with respect to critical issues that affect this process. Emphasis was
given to regulatory and policy issues, new methods of work, new market
 dynamics and new business models.
<br />
<br />
An interactive online platform, MobiForum, (<a href="http://www.mobiforum.org">http://www.mobiforum.org</a>) 
was set up to support
dissemination /exploitation. It provides a globally accessible central
point of reference for all developments in the project and in the area of
m-Commerce evolution in general and is used for consensus building
among m-Commerce stakeholders.
	</description>
</project>
