<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="p_mobinet" group="g_eltrun g_wrc" scientific_coordinator="m_giaglis" contact="m_kfouskas" international="no" type="training" project_manager="m_kfouskas">
	<shortname>MobiNet</shortname>
	<projtitle>Mobile-Human Network of Excellence in Mobile Business</projtitle>
	<startdate>20030501</startdate>
	<enddate>20050430</enddate>
	<web_site>http://www.mobinet.gr</web_site>
	<!--<our_budget>328,627 EUR</our_budget>-->
	<!--<total_budget>3,493,834 EUR</total_budget>-->
	<funding_agency>General Secretariat of Research and Technology</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>Competiteveness - Human Networks in R&amp;T</funding_programme>
	<!--<project_code>Action 8.3.6</project_code>-->
	<partner>
		<shortname>Aristotle University of Thessaloniki</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.auth.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>University of Crete - Atlantis</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.atlantis.uoc.gr</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Unisystems</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>www.unisystems.gr</web_site>
	</partner>
		
	<!--<logo>../images/p_mexpress.gif</logo>-->
	<description>
			<p>
			The	Human Network of Excellence in M-Business (MobiNet) embraces a network of
			cooperation between scientific and industrial partners whose basic aim is the
			dissemination of knowledge and the education of students and executives in the
			area of wireless technologies and corporate applications based on the use of
			mobile devices.</p>
			
			<p>
			The	creation of this network, aims in the synthesis of knowledge for the exchange
			and establishment of mBusiness teaching material. The main goal is the
			development of a complete teaching material portfolio, which will be used for
			the education and training of graduate or postgraduate students as well as
			business executives. This educational material could also be used at the end of
			the project as generic information in training and educational events that will
			be organized from time to time.</p>

			The	network will consist of 4 main axes:
            	<ul>
			<li>The organization of a double round of training seminars in 3 cities (Athens, Thessaloniki,
			and Heraklio) whose main goal will be the education of students and business
			executives in the area of wireless technologies and corporate applications
			based on the use of mobile devices. The fist phase of the seminar will include
			introductory coursed in M-Business where as the second one will focus on
			advanced Technological and Business Issues in M-Business.</li>

			<li>Placement for the graduate and postgraduate
			students in the Universities as well in the participating company of the
			project (Unisystems).</li>

			<li>The execution of an intra-organizational training programme for the executives
			of the participating firm (Unisystems).</li>

			<li>The organization of
			events for the public dissemination of the Network activities as well as of a
			web page for further on-line information about the Network progress and
			operation.</li></ul>
	</description>
</project>
