<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="p_mobileyouth" group="g_eltrun g_wrc" scientific_coordinator="m_giaglis" contact="m_drosos" international="no" type="dissemination" project_manager="m_drosos">
	<shortname>Mobile Youth</shortname>
	<projtitle>Mobile Youth</projtitle>
	<startdate>20031001</startdate>
	<enddate>20050331</enddate>
	<!--<web_site>http://www.mobinet.gr</web_site>-->
	<!--<our_budget>328,627 EUR</our_budget>-->
	<!--<total_budget>3,493,834 EUR</total_budget>-->
	<funding_agency>General Secretariat of Research and Technology</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>Electronic Business of Information Society</funding_programme>
	<!--<project_code>Action 8.3.6</project_code>-->
	<partner>
		<shortname>Lambrakis Research Foundation</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.lrf.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>ALBA</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://www.alba.gr</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>LEO BURNETT</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<!--<web_site>www.unisystems.gr</web_site>-->
	</partner>
		
	<!--<logo>../images/p_mexpress.gif</logo>-->
	<description>
The primary goal of this project is to
study the nature of adoption and social absorption of mobile technologies and
services in the segment with the highest usage and adoption rates, the youth.
This objective follows the argument that true mobile innovation will arise when
today's adolescents become working adults; this is because this is the most
adaptive user base that learns to assimilate new technologies in unique ways.
The work plan of the project consists of four phases:
<br />
<ul>
<li>Literature and Background</li>
<li>Field Studies and Surveys</li>
<li>Synthesis and Reporting</li>
<li>Exploitation and Diffusion</li>
</ul>
<br />
The contribution of this project is the
understanding of the continuous impacts of the mobile telephony and services in
respect to:
<br /><br />
<ul>
<li>
<b>Social Changes among teenagers.</b> In which way the mobile phone affects
the social relationships of the youngsters? Are there any correlations between
communication patterns and social networks? Which are the needs for
communication of the teenager and how the mobile phone facilitates the
communication process? Which is the role of the family? Does the mobile phone
increase the feeling of security and the level of independency? 
</li>
<li>
<b>Education and the school environment.</b> Do school rules inhibit the need for
communication? Which is the response of the teenager? Could the mobile
technology characteristics enhance the operational processes of schools? For
instance, with the Short Messaging Service the teachers could inform the
parents when their kids are absent or the pupils could be informed about their
grades.
</li>
<li>
<b>Business prospects and opportunities.</b> Companies participating in the mobile
industry should segment, analyze and target the youth market with a unique,
flexible and at a minimum cost product offering. Thus, the analysis of the
ocial behaviour and the communications usage patterns of the youngsters is a
valuable tool for all the actors in the mobile value chain. More than this, as
today's youth will be the professional mobile users of tomorrow, this study
will serve as a gauge of future demand patterns.
</li>
<li>
<b>Development of Descriptive Social
Interaction Scenarios.</b> (case
studies of how mobile technologies are being assimilated in the daily life of
adolescents).
</li>
</ul>
	</description>
</project>