<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="p_sqo-oss" group="g_istlab g_sense" scientific_coordinator="m_dds" 
contact="m_dds" international="yes" type="rtd" project_manager="m_gousios">
	<shortname>SQO-OSS</shortname>
	<projtitle>Source Quality Observatory for Open Source Software</projtitle>
	<startdate>20060901</startdate>
	<enddate>20081031</enddate>
	<web_site>http://www.sqo-oss.eu/</web_site>
	<our_budget>378000</our_budget>
	<total_budget>1638800</total_budget>
	<funding_agency>European Commission</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>FP6/IST</funding_programme>
	<project_code>IST-2005-33331</project_code>
	<partner>
		<shortname>DB-NET</shortname>
		<country>GR</country>
		<web_site>http://www.db-net.aueb.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>AUTH-PLASE</shortname>
		<country>GR</country>
		<web_site>http://plase.csd.auth.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>PROSYST</shortname>
		<country>DE</country>
		<web_site>http://www.prosyst.de</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>SIRIUS</shortname>
		<country>UK</country>
		<web_site>http://www.siriusit.co.uk</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>KDAB</shortname>
		<country>SE</country>
		<web_site>http://www.kdab.net/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>KDE</shortname>
		<country>DE</country>
		<web_site>http://www.kde.org</web_site>
	</partner>
	<logo>../images/sqo-oss.png</logo>
	<description>
What do we know about the quality of the software you are using?  A well-known conjecture  
in software engineering is that external quality characteristics are correlated to internal quality  
characteristics and thus the measurement of source code provides useful data for the  
assessment of its quality. Uniquely, open source software allows us to examine the actual  
code and perform white box testing and analysis of it. In most open source projects we can  
also access their version control system, mailing lists and issue databases.  We can use these  
data sources to extract quality indicators through techniques, such as data mining.  
SQO-OSS aims to increase the competitiveness of European software development SMEs  
through a holistic approach of software quality assessment, initially targeting open source  
software. The project seeks to use as many sources of quality indicators as possible so as to  
create a set of metrics that can be applied automatically to a software project’s repository in  
order to extract quantifiable measurements of its quality.  The project will deliver:

<ul>
<li>A plug-in based quality assessment platform, featuring a web and an IDE front-end.</li>
<li>An enhanced set of software metrics that will take into account quality indicators from data that is present in a project’s repository, but not yet used for quality assessment.</li>
<li>A publicly available league of open source software applications, categorised by their quality characteristics.</li>
<li>A methodology that will allow European SMEs to leverage the availability of quality-assessed open source software in the development of horizontal and vertical applications and the provision of value-added services.</li>
<li>Experience reports of how the tool’s application affected a large open source project</li>
</ul>

The project leverages existing tools and will also create new ones in an effort to build an
integrated quality assessment platform. The core will be released as open source software  
under the BSD licence to stimulate business interest around it.
	</description>
</project>
