<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="p_sqo-oss" group="g_eltrun g_sense" scientific_coordinator="m_dds" 
contact="m_dds" international="yes" type="rtd" project_manager="m_gousios">
	<shortname>SQO-OSS</shortname>
	<projtitle>Source Quality Observatory for Open Source Software</projtitle>
	<startdate>20060301</startdate>
	<enddate>20080301</enddate>
	<web_site>-</web_site>
	<our_budget>-</our_budget>
	<total_budget>-</total_budget>
	<funding_agency>European Commission</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>FP6/IST</funding_programme>
	<project_code>IST-2005-33331</project_code>
	<partner>
		<shortname>AUTH-PLASE</shortname>
		<country>EL</country>
		<web_site>http://plase.csd.auth.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>PROSYST</shortname>
		<country>D</country>
		<web_site>http://www.prosyst.de</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>SIRIUS</shortname>
		<country>UK</country>
		<web_site>http://www.siriusit.co.uk</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>KDAB</shortname>
		<country>SE</country>
		<web_site>http://www.kdab.net/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>KDE</shortname>
		<country>D</country>
		<web_site>http://www.kde.org</web_site>
	</partner>
	<!--<logo>../images/p_mexpress.gif</logo>-->
	<description>
<p>A well-known conjecture in software engineering is that external quality characteristics 
are correlated to internal quality characteristics and thus the measurement of source code
provides useful data for the assessment of its quality. Uniquely, OSS provides us the 
capability to examine the actual code and performing white box testing and analysis of it.
Most OSS projects provide access to their version control system and issue databases, 
enabling additional sources for the extraction of quality indicators.</p>

<p>We propose to increase the competitiveness of European software development SMEs
through a holistic approach of software quality assessment, initially targeting OSS.
We aim to use as many sources of quality indicators as possible so as to create a set 
of metrics that can automatically be applied to a software project's repository in order 
to extract quantifiable measurements of its quality. The project will deliver:</p>
<ul>
<li>A framework that will allow quality assessment plug-ins to be attached and 
that features web or graphical interfaces that enable the user to control it.</li>
<li>An enhanced set of software metrics that will take into account quality 
indicators present, but not yet considered, in the project's repository and 
design models.</li>
<li>A publicly available league of quality characteristics in OSS applications, 
generated by the project's software outcome. </li>
<li>A methodology that will allow European SMEs to leverage the availability of 
quality-assessed OSS in the development of horizontal and vertical applications.</li>
<li>Experience reports of how the tool's application affected a large OSS project.</li>
</ul>
The project will leverage existing tools and also create new ones in an effort 
to create an integrated quality assessment framework. The core will be released 
as OSS under the LGPL licence to stimulate business interest around it. 
  
	
	</description>
</project>
