<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<project id="p_tracer" group="g_istlab g_sense" contact="m_dimitro" scientific_coordinator="m_dds" international="no" type="rtd" project_manager="m_dimitro">
	<shortname>TRACER</shortname>
	<projtitle>Identifying software vulnerabilities and securing legacy systems</projtitle>
	<startdate>20110418</startdate>
	<enddate>20141118</enddate>
	<web_site>http://www.tracer-project.gr/</web_site>
	<our_budget>146020 euro</our_budget>
	<total_budget>546700 euro</total_budget>
	<funding_agency>European Regional Development Fund (ERDF) and national funds.  Operational Programme "Competitiveness and Entrepreneurship" (OPCE II), "Measure Cooperation" (Action I).</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>Synergasia</funding_programme>
	<project_code>09ΣΥΝ-72-942</project_code>
    <logo>../images/synergasia.png</logo>
	<partner>
		<shortname>PLASE Laboratory of the Department of Informatics of the Aristotle University of Thessaloniki</shortname>
		<country>GR</country>
		<web_site>http://sweng.csd.auth.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
    <partner>
		<shortname>Institute of Computer Science (ICS) of the Foundation for Research and Technology - Hellas (FORTH)</shortname>
		<country>GR</country>
		<web_site>http://www.ics.forth.gr/</web_site>
	</partner>
	<partner>
		<shortname>Singular Software S.A.</shortname>
		<country>GR</country>
		<web_site>http://www.singularsoftware.gr/index.asp</web_site>
	</partner>
	<description>
Legacy systems are likely to contain software vulnerabilities that can lead
to various security breaches. On the other hand, these systems contain valuable
information about the environment, the creation and the evolution of the
organization they support. For this reason, redesigning large systems in order
to be secure and compatible with new technologies is not a practical option,
since the information mentioned above could be lost. In addition the cost of replacing
such system and retrain its various users, could be prohibitive. In this project we
propose a framework that shields legacy systems based on two basic steps:
First, our framework analyzes the source code of the system to identify potential
software vulnerabilities and eliminates them. Then, depending on the previous
analysis the framework proposes solutions to protect
the system from the most common web-application attacks.
	</description>
</project>
