<?xml version="1.0"?>
<project id="winnovate_wrc" 
	 group="g_istlab g_wrc" 
	 scientific_coordinator="m_giaglis" 
	 contact="m_angelaki"
	 international="yes"
	 type="dissemination">
	 
	<shortname>WiNNOVATE</shortname>
	<projtitle>Mediterranean Wireless Innovation</projtitle>
	<startdate>20090501</startdate>
	<enddate>20111031</enddate>
	<web_site>http://www.winnovate.eu</web_site>
	<!-- <our_budget>Optional</our_budget>
	<total_budget>Optional</total_budget>
	<funding_agency>Optional</funding_agency>
	<funding_programme>Optional</funding_programme>
	<project_code>Optional</project_code> -->
	<!-- each project has zero or more <partner> tags -->
	<partner>
		<shortname>Prefecture of Larissa</shortname>
		<country>Greece</country>
		<web_site>http://www.larissa.gr</web_site>
	</partner>
        <partner>
                <shortname>Velez-Malaga Town Council</shortname>
                <country>Spain</country>
                <web_site>http://www.ayto-velezmalaga.es</web_site>
        </partner>
	 <partner>
                <shortname>TEDK Chiou</shortname>
                <country>Greece</country>
                <web_site>http://www.tedkchios.gr</web_site>
        </partner>
	 <partner>
                <shortname>Radio Labs</shortname>
                <country>Italy</country>
                <web_site>http://www.radiolabs.it</web_site>
        </partner>
	 <partner>
                <shortname>i2CAT</shortname>
                <country>Spain</country>
                <web_site>http://www.i2cat.net</web_site>
        </partner>
	 <partner>
                <shortname>Municipality of Genoa</shortname>
                <country>Italy</country>
                <web_site>http://www.comune.genova.it</web_site>
        </partner>
	 <partner>
                <shortname>Development Agency Sinergija</shortname>
                <country>Slovenia</country>
                <web_site>http://www.ra-sinergija.si</web_site>
        </partner>

	<logo>http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~koun/istlab-web/public_html/images/winnovate.png</logo>
	<description>
WiNNOVATE aims at strengthening the innovation capacity of regional and municipal authorities in Greece,
 Spain, Italy and Slovenia by transferring knowledge and best practices, as well as coordinating policies, 
on the introduction and proliferation of wireless applications and services for citizens, government, and 
economic development actors. More specifically, the project will leverage and cross-fertilize existing 
wireless infrastructures (local and metropolitan wireless networks), define and experiment pilot applications 
that will add value on these infrastructures for the benefit of end users, and propose policy interventions 
at the regional, national and transnational levels. We will define an operational toolkit positioning regions 
in terms of maturity and capacity levels for the introduction and use of innovative WiFi- and WiMAX-based 
applications and services and use this as a guiding vehicle for the gradual increase of wireless innovation 
potential for any given region in the Med space. We will jointly establish the specifications and pilot one 
wireless information service per region, delivering concrete results and acting as a proof-of-concept for the 
operational toolkit. The project's main outcomes will be: a reusable methodological approach for assessing and 
guiding regional authorities towards wireless innovation, working pilot applications at each participating region, 
evaluation of the lessons learnt by the pilots, and a set of policy recommendations.
	</description>
</project>
