<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page id="iris_Conferences" group="g_iris">
	<page_name>Conferences</page_name>
	<page_body>

<h1>
5th Mediterranean Conference on Information Systems (2010), 12-14 September 2010, Tel-Aviv-Yaffo, Israel
</h1>

<img src="../images/MCIS_10.jpg" alt="MCIS2010"/>

MCIS 2010 aims to:
- Inspire innovative and informative IS research that is relevant to the
social, economic, and cultural particularities of the Mediterranean Region
- Foster ground breaking IS research to improve the quality of life in the
Mediterranean Region through further development of the regional
knowledgebase and its emerging collaboration infrastructure
- Raise the visibility of IS-related research, education, policy, and
practice carried out in the Mediterranean Region
Link: www.mcis2010.org

<h1>
4th Mediterranean Conference on Information Systems (2009), 25-27 September 2009, Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece
</h1>

<img src="../images/MCIS_09.jpg" alt="MCIS2009"/>

The Mediterranean Conference on Information Systems (MCIS) aims to:
 1. encourage and inspire innovative and informative IS research that is
relevant to the social, economic and cultural particularities of the
Mediterranean region
 2. raise the visibility of IS-related research practice, education and
policy carried out in the Med. region
 3. bring together researchers, educators, policy makers and practitioners
originating from, or working in the region, thus engaging junior and more
experienced members of the Mediterranean IS community in a creative
dialogue.
The MCIS conference series is held under the auspices of the Association of
Information Systems (AIS). The Athens University of Economics and Business
(AUEB) and the Department of Management Science and Technology (DMST) are
honored to host the MCIS 2009 event in Athens, Greece. Aspiring to set-up an
inclusive, high quality IS conference with solid academic and practitioner
foundations, the MCIS 2009 organization invites papers, case studies, panels
and workshop proposals in a number of areas that are relevant to IS
Research, Education, Policy and Practice in the Mediterranean Region.

Link: www.mcis2009.org

<h1>
ETHICOMP 2004 INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE
</h1>

<img src="../images/ethicomp_1.jpg" alt="Ethicomp"/>

The IRIS-Eltrun group of the Department of Management Science and Technology of the Athens University of Economics and Business organized the Seventh ETHICOMP International Conference on the Social and Ethical Impacts of Information and Communication Technologies, in collaboration with the University of the Aegean, the Center for Computing and Social Responsibility of De Montford University and the Research Center on Computing and Society of Southern Connecticut State University. The conference was held on 14-16 April 2004, in Syros, Greece and considered the 'Challenges for the Citizen of the Information Society'. Further information on the conference is available at: 
<a href="http://www.ccsr.cse.dmu.ac.uk/conferences/ethicomp/ethicomp2004/
">http://www.ccsr.cse.dmu.ac.uk/conferences/ethicomp/ethicomp2004/
</a>.

	</page_body>
</page>
