<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page id="istlab-join" group="g_istlab">
	<page_name>Joining the Lab</page_name>
	<page_body>
We are always looking for brilliant people to join our growing
group.
New ISTLab members can join as
researchers, PhD candidates, research associates,
or research assistants.
<p>
ISTLab <b>researchers</b> are typically academic members of
the Athens University of Economics and Business or post-doctoral researchers working within the Lab.
</p>
<p>
<b>PhD candidates</b> joining are lab must be enrolled and active
in an academic PhD programme.
Twice a year the Department of Management Science and Technology
of the Athens University of Economics and Business
issues a call for new PhD candidates.
PhD candidates have a graduate and postgraduate
degree in Computer Science, Information Systems, or equivalent qualifications.
They have the opportunity to manage and work on a number of cutting
edge research initiatives.
</p>
<p>
<b>Research associates</b> have a degree 
(or are in their final year of study)
in Computer Science, Information Systems, or an equivalent programme.
They can participate in our research activities with a chance to
influence the future of Information Systems Technology.
</p>
<p>
We have also a limited number of open positions for
<b>research assistants</b>:
exceptional undergraduate students who wish to gain meaningful
research experience or external affiliates providing consulting or administrative support to the Lab's activities.
</p>
<h2>Collaboration Opportunities</h2>
<p>
We are always interested in establishing collaboration links with leading
industrial and academic partners.
Becoming an ISTLab <em>collaborator</em> provides you a valuable
link with one of the most dynamic research groups in our area.
Benefits include 
research collaboration opportunities,
the participation in organised events,
advance information on new activities,
a listing of your organisation's name and logo in our site's web page, and
periodic research intelligence updates.
</p>
<p>
For more details contact the head of the group closest to your area of interest.
</p>

	</page_body>
</page>

