<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page id="ois_PastEvents" group="g_ois">
	<page_name>Past events</page_name>
	<page_body>

<h1>
5th Mediterranean Conference on Information Systems (2010)
</h1> 

<p>12-14 September 2010, Tel-Aviv-Yaffo, Israel
</p>

<img src="../images/MCIS_10.jpg" alt="MCIS2010"/>

<p>
MCIS 2010 aims to:
- Inspire innovative and informative IS research that is relevant to the
social, economic, and cultural particularities of the Mediterranean Region
- Foster ground breaking IS research to improve the quality of life in the
Mediterranean Region through further development of the regional
knowledgebase and its emerging collaboration infrastructure
- Raise the visibility of IS-related research, education, policy, and
practice carried out in the Mediterranean Region
</p>


<p>Link:" <a href="http://www.mcis2010.org">http://www.www.www.mcis2010.org"</a>.</p>
<p>
.
</p>

<p>
.
</p>
<h1>
4th Mediterranean Conference on Information Systems (2009)
</h1>

<p>
25-27 September 2009, Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece
</p>

<img src="../images/MCIS_09.jpg" alt="MCIS2009"/>

<p>
The Mediterranean Conference on Information Systems (MCIS) aims to:
 1. encourage and inspire innovative and informative IS research that is
relevant to the social, economic and cultural particularities of the
Mediterranean region
 2. raise the visibility of IS-related research practice, education and
policy carried out in the Med. region
 3. bring together researchers, educators, policy makers and practitioners
originating from, or working in the region, thus engaging junior and more
experienced members of the Mediterranean IS community in a creative
dialogue.
</p>
<p>
The MCIS conference series is held under the auspices of the Association of
Information Systems (AIS). The Athens University of Economics and Business
(AUEB) and the Department of Management Science and Technology (DMST) are
honored to host the MCIS 2009 event in Athens, Greece. Aspiring to set-up an
inclusive, high quality IS conference with solid academic and practitioner
foundations, the MCIS 2009 organization invites papers, case studies, panels
and workshop proposals in a number of areas that are relevant to IS
Research, Education, Policy and Practice in the Mediterranean Region.
</p>

<p>Link:" <a href="http://www.mcis2009.org">http://www.www.mcis2009.org"</a>.</p>

<p>
.
</p>

<p>
.
</p>


<h1>
Images of Virtuality: Conceptualizations and Applications in Everyday Life
</h1>

<p>
April 23-24, 2009 - Athens University of Economics and Business, Greece
</p>

<p>
An International Workshop of IFIP WG9.5 on "Virtuality and Society"
</p>

<img src="../images/ImagesOfVirtuality_09.jpg" alt="IFIP"/>

<p>Following on last year's International Working Conference of IFIP 9.5 Working Group on Virtuality and Society: "Massive Virtual Communities" at Leuphana University, Luneburg, this workshop will focus on conceptualizations and applications of virtuality in everyday life, including socialization, governance, education, entrepreneurship and entertainment.
</p>

<p>The main objective of this workshop is to encourage the continuation and enrichment of the discussion on virtuality and society, by focusing more on the technologies, arts, and practices of virtuality as they emerge in spaces and contexts of everyday life. The workshop constitutes an opportunity to bring together theoretical conceptualizations and practical applications of Images of Virtuality manifest in human interaction with information, social, professional and technological systems, art, culture, and nature.
</p>

<p>Link:" <a href="http://www.imagesofvirtuality.org">http://www.ImagesOfVirtuality.org"</a>.</p>




	</page_body>
</page>


