<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page id="ois_PhDs" group="g_ois">
	<page_name>PhDs</page_name>
	<page_body>


<h1>2009</h1>

<h2>E-Learning readiness assessment: Factors affecting learners' attitudes towards e-Learning in the enterprise</h2>
<p>By Dr. Spiros Borotis</p>
<h3>SUMMARY</h3>
<p>
e-Learning attracts considerable interest in contemporary corporate training curricula. As it usually concerns a significant investment, organizations that tend to adopt and maintain it effectively and efficiently in the long term, need to learn from the pioneers. Literature and practical experience indicate critical success factors and frameworks for adoption in both organizational and individual levels. This study tries to examine thoroughly the acceptance of e-Learning from employees - learners.
</p>

<p>...................................................................................................</p>


<h1>2008</h1>

<h2>The adoption of collaborative technologies in project based teams: Investigating the role of collaboration intensity in individuals' perceptions and beliefs</h2>
<p>By Dr. Athanasios Nikas</p>
<h3>SUMMARY</h3>
<p>
The research interest is focusing on studying the social and organisational dynamics which underlie recent technological and work developments in networked organisations. In the effort of investigating factors affecting the intention to adopt collaborative technologies in project based organizations for improving project management and coordination it is interesting to study: 'How best to develop a research framework that organizes and guides research efforts as well as offering insights to management practice. This effort is based on investigating the influence of collaboration intensity of team members on their attitudes and beliefs regarding the adoption of collaborative technologies in project work'. Further, the research challenge is to study the social and organisational dynamics which underlie recent technological and work developments in project based organizational settings. Finally, the empirical data of my study are extracted from both qualitative (case study) and quantitative methods (survey analysis) by applying structural equation modelling techniques.
</p>

<p>...................................................................................................</p>

<h1>2007</h1>

<h2>A Usability Evaluation Method for E-Learning Courses</h2>
<p>By Dr. Panagiotis Zaharias</p>


<p>...................................................................................................</p>

<h1>2006</h1>

<h2>The Role of Affordances' Perception in the Adoption of Information Technology Innovations: The Case of Knowledge Management</h2>
<p>By Dr. Konstantinos Samiotis</p>


<p>...................................................................................................</p>


</page_body>
</page>



