<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page id="ois_Upcoming events" group="g_ois">
	<page_name>Upcoming events</page_name>
	<page_body>
	
<h1>
Hackathon SAP University Alliances, InnoJam++ @ CeBIT 2016 presented by SAP and Volkswagen (March 2016)
</h1> 

<p>14-17 March 2016, Hanover, Germany
</p>

<?image?>

<p>
Dear Students,
The InnoJam++ at CeBIT 2016 in Hanover, Germany is rapidly approaching! We are particularly thrilled that for this year’s hackathon SAP University Alliances is partnering with Volkswagen one of the world’s leading automobile manufacturers, with exciting challenges all around mobility of the future and Internet of Things. The event will take place on March 14-17, 2016.
As this year’s hackathon will be even larger and greater than ever we are extending the application deadline till February 18, 2016.
So if you enjoyed our last SAP InnoJams then apply again because hackathons @ CeBIT are a class on its own! And if you are new to this kind of event get ready for a once in a lifetime experience!
About the Event Format
Our hackathons are a 30 hours hands-on experience using SAP's coolest and newest technologies supported by SAP domain experts and branch experts. Learn about innovative SAP technologies, collaborate and co-innovate with fellow students. Expand your network by meeting other participants from dozens of countries. Get a crash course in Design Thinking and apply your knowledge by developing prototypes of solutions to real business cases e.g. relevant for the automotive branch and compete to win awesome prizes.
Accommodation and Organization
We will cover accommodation in a hostel from Monday (March 14) to Friday (March 18) as well as food throughout the whole Hackathon event and the CeBIT-ticket. You will have to pay for all other additional costs (e.g. travel). For travel within Germany a partial subsidy for travel by bus (Fernbus only) can be offered upon request.
Application process
For this hackathon we are particularly looking for students with technical, business or design/UX skills who are strong team-players. Technical students need to be fluent in JavaScript – knowledge in SAPUI5 is preferred but not necessary. Furthermore, they should have basic skills in Java programming and SQL skills are an advantage. Business students should be familiar with business model development and design students should have skills in user experience design and user interface development.
If you want to join please send your CV and a short statement why we should pick you to uasupport@sap.com.
The extended application deadline is February 18, 2016. 
Team applications of up to 5 people are also allowed. In case you are admitted, you will receive a registration link and an invitation to a collaboration group (SAP Jam) where you will get further information on exact dates and times as well as logistics. 
Brief information about CeBIT in Hanover, Germany (March 14 – 18, 2016)
•         The world’s largest trade fair for IT
•         More than 220.000 participants are expected
•         SAP University Alliances will be present in Scale 11 (Hall 11) at the SAP booth and available for personal meetings
•         Link to trade fair’s homepage
If you have open questions, please do not hesitate to ask. We will be happy to answer them.
We look forward to seeing you at the CeBIT!
Best regards,
SAP University Alliances
 
 

</p>


<p>Link:" <a href="http://events.sap.com/hackathons/en/innojamhanover?bc=3%3%0"</a>.</p>

</page_body>

