<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page id="sense_software" group="g_sense">
<page_name>Public Software</page_name>
<page_body>
The goal of SENSE is to practice what we preach by
developing software following or deomonstrating the
techniques or methodologies we advocate. When there are
no intelectual property rights conflicts we try to make
our software available in free and/or open-source form.
Software we have released includes the following projects:
<br />
<ul>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/cscout">CScout</a>
is a source code analyzer and refactoring browser
for collections of C programs. It can process workspaces of multiple
projects mapping the complexity introduced by the C preprocessor back
into the original C source code files. CScout takes advantage of modern
hardware advances (fast processors and large memory capacities) to
analyze C source code beyond the level of detail and accuracy provided
by current compilers and linkers.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/umlgraph">UMLGraph</a>
allows the declarative specification and drawing of a number of UML
diagrams. See also the
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/pubs/jrnl/2003-IEEESW-umlgraph/html/article.html">article</a>
titled On the declarative specification
of models. IEEE Software, 20(2):94-96, March/April 2003.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/outwit">Outwit</a>
A tool suite that provides console-based access to the Windows clipboard,
registry, databases, document properties, and links. See also the
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/pubs/conf/2000-Usenix-outwit/html/utool.html">conference paper</a> Outwit:
Unix tool-based programming meets the Windows world. In USENIX 2000
Technical Conference Proceedings, pages 149-158, San Diego, CA, USA,
June 2000. Usenix Association.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/unix/socketpipe">Socketpipe</a>
connects a remote command to local input and output processes without
the data copy and context switching overhead of the customary rsh or
ssh pipelines.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/unix/fileprune">Fileprune</a>
will delete files from the specified set targeting a given
distribution of the files within time as well as size, number, and age
constraints. Its main purpose is to keep a set of daily-created backup
files in manageable size, while still providing reasonable access to
older versions. Specifying a size, file number, or age constraint will
simply remove files starting from the oldest, until the constraint is
met. The distribution specification (exponential, Gaussian (normal),
or Fibonacci) provides finer control of the files to delete, allowing
the retention of recent copies and the increasingly aggressive pruning
of the older files. You can read more in the
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/pubs/trade/2003-login-prune/html/prune.html">article</a>
Organized pruning
of file sets. ;login:, 28(3):39-42, June 2003.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/textproc/bib2xhtml">bib2xhtml</a>
is a program that converts BibTeX files into HTML (specifically XHTML
1.0). The conversion is mostly done by specialized BibTeX style files,
derived from a converted bibliography style template. This ensures that
the original BibTeX styles are faithfully reproduced.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~dimitro/sdriver/">SDriver</a> 
secures web applications from SQL injection atacks. See also the <a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/pubs/jrnl/2009-CompSec-SQLIA/html/sqlia.html">article</a> titled, Vassilios Karakoidas and Diomidis Spinellis. SDriver: Location-Specific Signatures Prevent SQL Injection Attacks <i>Computers and Security</i>, 2009
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://gaijin.dmst.aueb.gr/~bkarak/programs/fire/index.html">FIRE/J</a> 
is a very fast regular expression library for java. See also the article titled, Vassilios Karakoidas and Diomidis Spinellis. FIRE/J: Optimizing regular expression searches with generative programming. <i>Software: Practice and Experience</i>, 38(6):557-573, May 2008
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://gaijin.dmst.aueb.gr/~bkarak/programs/fire/benchmark.html">Regular Expression Benchmark Utility</a> 
is an application written in 100% Java. It was implemented to test FIRE/J execution speed and compatibility 
against other Regular Expression Engines in Java.  The FIRE/J regular expression library is designed to 
provide maximum execution speed, while remaining portable across different machine architectures. 
To achieve that, FIRE/J transforms each regular expression into a tailor-made class file, which is 
compiled directly to Java virtual machine (JVM) bytecodes.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://gaijin.dmst.aueb.gr/~bkarak/programs/regex-api/index.html">SARE - Simple API for Regular Expressions</a> 
-  SARE stands for Simple API for Regular Expressions. Its an API that provides event 
based regular expression parsing. SARE's API is very simple. The developer need only to 
implement an interface, action event handler and attach it to the specific group of SARE parser.	
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~vbill/ngce/">NGCE - Network Graphs for Computer Epidemiologists</a> 
Graphs are useful data structures capable of representing eficiently many technological and social networks. 
Because of this specific property they are utilized in the simulation-based studies of new algorithms and protocols. 
Inspired by the popular TGFF (Task Graphs For Free) toolkit, which creates task graphs for embedded systems, 
we present the NGCE, an easy to use graphical graph generator that produces graphs for the study of the 
propagation of viral agents in complex networks.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/ckjm/">ckjm - Chidamber and Kemerer Java Metrics</a>. 
The program ckjm calculates Chidamber and Kemerer object-oriented metrics by processing the 
bytecode of compiled Java files. The program calculates for each class the following six 
metrics: (1) <i>WMC: Weighted methods per class</i>, (2) <i>DIT: Depth of Inheritance Tree</i>, 
(3) <i>NOC: Number of Children</i>, (4) <i>CBO: Coupling between object classes</i>, 
(5) <i>RFC: Response for a Class</i> and (6) <i>LCOM: Lack of cohesion in methods</i>
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.spinellis.gr/blog/20050413/">Pipe Namespace in the Portal Filesystem</a>. 
The portal filesystem allows a daemon running as a userland program to pass descriptors to 
processes that open files belonging to its namespace. It has been part of the *BSD operating 
systems since 4.4 BSD. I recently added a pipe namespace to its FreeBSD implementation. 
This allows us to perform scatter gather operations without using temporary files, create non-linear 
pipelines, and implement file views using symbolic links. 
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://indywiki.sourceforge.net">Indywiki</a> aims to explore
different ways of browsing the Wikipedia universe, through an intuitive GUI
application.
</li>
</ul>
</page_body>
</page>
