<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page id="sense_software" group="g_sense">
<page_name>Public Software</page_name>
<page_body>
The goal of SENSE is to practice what we preach by
developing software following or deomonstrating the
techniques or methodologies we advocate. When there are
no intelectual property rights conflicts we try to make
our software available in free and/or open-source form.
Software we have released includes the following projects:
<br />
<ul>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/cscout">CScout</a>
is a source code analyzer and refactoring browser
for collections of C programs. It can process workspaces of multiple
projects mapping the complexity introduced by the C preprocessor back
into the original C source code files. CScout takes advantage of modern
hardware advances (fast processors and large memory capacities) to
analyze C source code beyond the level of detail and accuracy provided
by current compilers and linkers.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/umlgraph">UMLGraph</a>
allows the declarative specification and drawing of a number of UML
diagrams. See also the
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/pubs/jrnl/2003-IEEESW-umlgraph/html/article.html">article</a>
titled On the declarative specification
of models. IEEE Software, 20(2):94-96, March/April 2003.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/outwit">Outwit</a>
A tool suite that provides console-based access to the Windows clipboard,
registry, databases, document properties, and links. See also the
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/pubs/conf/2000-Usenix-outwit/html/utool.html">conference paper</a> Outwit:
Unix tool-based programming meets the Windows world. In USENIX 2000
Technical Conference Proceedings, pages 149-158, San Diego, CA, USA,
June 2000. Usenix Association.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/unix/socketpipe">Socketpipe</a>
connects a remote command to local input and output processes without
the data copy and context switching overhead of the customary rsh or
ssh pipelines.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/unix/fileprune">Fileprune</a>
will delete files from the specified set targetting a given
distribution of the files within time as well as size, number, and age
constraints. Its main purpose is to keep a set of daily-created backup
files in managable size, while still providing reasonable access to
older versions. Specifying a size, file number, or age constraint will
simply remove files starting from the oldest, until the constraint is
met. The distribution specification (exponential, Gaussian (normal),
or Fibonacci) provides finer control of the files to delete, allowing
the retention of recent copies and the increasingly agressive pruning
of the older files. You can read more in the
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/pubs/trade/2003-login-prune/html/prune.html">article</a>
Organized pruning
of file sets. ;login:, 28(3):39-42, June 2003.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://www.dmst.aueb.gr/dds/sw/textproc/bib2xhtml">bib2xhtml</a>
is a program that converts BibTeX files into HTML (specifically XHTML
1.0). The conversion is mostly done by specialized BibTeX style files,
derived from a converted bibliography style template. This ensures that
the original BibTeX styles are faithfully reproduced.
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~bkarak/programs/fire/">FIRE</a> (Fast Implementation of Regular Expressions) is a regular expression library for java. It follows the POSIX syntax and is 100% compatible with the SUN regular expression library (java.util.regex.*).
</li>
<li>
<a href="http://istlab.dmst.aueb.gr/~bkarak/programs/fire/">FIRE Suite - Regular Expression Benchmark Utility</a> is an application written in 100% Java. It was implemented to test FIRE (Fast Implementation of Regular Expressions) execution speed and compatibility with other Regular Expression Engines in Java.
</li>
</ul>
</page_body>
</page>
