<?xml version="1.0"?>
<page id="wrc_calls" group="g_wrc">
	<page_name>Calls for Papers</page_name>
	<page_body>

<h2>The 4th International Workshop on Ubiquitous Computing (IWUC 2007)</h2>
<br/>12-13 June, 2007 - Funchal, Madeira - Portugal
<br/>In conjunction with the <b>9th International Conference on Enterprise Information Systems</b> (ICEIS 2007)
<br/><br/> 
Co-Chairs: 
<br/><b>Soraya Kouadri Mostefaoui</b> (primary contact), Mobile Information Systems Laboratory, University of Applied Sciences of Western Switzerland, Fribourg
<br/><b>Zakaria Maamar</b>, College of ISs, Zayed University
<br/><b>George M. Giaglis</b>, Dep. of Management Science and Technology, Athens University of Economics and Business (AUEB)
<br/><br/>
<b>Background and Goals</b>
<br/>The development and availability of new computing and communication devices, and the increased connectivity between these devices, thanks to wired and wireless networks, are enabling new opportunities for people to perform their operations anywhere and anytime. Furthermore, due to the high acceptance rate of such devices by the user community, it is expected that these devices will become so pervasive that most users will take them for granted. Generally known as Ubiquitous Computing (UC), the vision of UC is to push computational services out of conventional desktop interfaces into environments characterized by transparent forms of interactivity.
Despite the growing interest in UC, there is still some progress to be made before UC shifts from the research mode to the commercial and intensive use modes. The support technologies, however, are improving at an impressive pace. Most of the research and development activities are currently aimed at improving the devices themselves and the technologies these devices will use to communicate. At present, the main use of mobile devices is still voice-oriented, but several indicators show that this is changing. 3G networks (e.g., GPRS, UMTS) and recent development of communication and presentation protocols (e.g., XML, WAP) are being combined to give users a high-quality experience of data-centric services. 
Besides the central role that hardware infrastructure plays in the expansion and penetration of UC, other issues still need to be tackled to better assist developers of UC applications. Developers are put on the front line of satisfying the promise of businesses and service providers for delivering Internet content to mobile devices. Indeed, the fact that an application for mobile users has different requirements, calls for new techniques to identify and specify these requirements. With regard to users, it is expected that they will be frequently engaged in complex operations such as searching the net for better business opportunities. Therefore, their association with intelligent components, to act as proxies, is deemed appropriate. UC environments of the near future will be populated by a large number of computing devices, spread across the network, and often invisible. These devices need to be coordinated for better interactions. Devices, whether carried on by people or embedded into other systems (within the home or at other sites), will constitute a global networking infrastructure -- and likely to provide a new level of openness and dynamics. These interactions raise many new issues that draw upon existing research areas, as well as introduce new research and development challenges, in technical areas (such as device design, wireless communication, location sensing, etc), psychology (privacy concerns, attention focus, multi-person interaction, etc), and design (direct interaction, work patterns, etc).
Existing global efforts in Grid Computing also shares some similarities with the aims of this workshop, although Grid computing at present is restricted to high-end computational resources. Making the Grid more open, and accessible to a wider range of users will also require the need to address similar challenges. 
<br/><br/>
<b>Topics of interest</b>
<br/>In this workshop, we aim to identify ecent and significant developments in the general area of ubiquitous computing. Topics of interests include, but are not limited to:
<ul>
<li>Mobile computing vs. Pervasive computing vs. Ubiquitous computing.</li>
<li>Design methodologies and evaluation techniques.</li>
<li>New interfaces and modes of interactions between people and ubiquitous computing devices, applications or environments.</li> 
<li>Grid Computing technologies for Wireless networks </li>
<li>Context awareness.</li>
<li>Agent-based ubiquitous applications.</li>
<li>Services for ubiquitous applications.</li>
<li>Middleware for service discovery.</li>
<li>Integration of wired and wireless networks.</li>
<li>Enabling technologies such as Bluetooth, 802.11, etc.</li>
<li>Security and privacy issues.</li>
<li>Visionary future scenarios.</li>
<li>Mobile services </li>
<li>Performance tuning of mobile applications </li>
</ul>
<b>Format of the Workshop</b>
<br/>The workshop will consist of oral presentations. The proceedings of the workshop will be published in the form of a book by INSTICC.
<br/><br/>
<b>Submission of Papers</b>
<br/>There will be two types of papers: long (approx. 5000 words) and short (approx. 2000 words). Furthermore, a keynote speaker and a discussion panel are planned. Postscript/RTF versions of the manuscript should be submitted thru ICEIS web-based paper submission procedure.
<br/><br/>
<b>Important Dates</b>
<br/>Paper Submission: February 19, 2007
<br/>Author Notification: March 23, 2007
<br/>Final Camera-Ready and Registration: April 9, 2007
<br/><br/>
<b>Workshop Location</b>
<br/>The workshop will take place in conjunction with the 9th International Conference on Enterprise Information Systems (ICEIS 2007) in Funchal, Madeira - Portugal. 
<br/><br/>
<b>Registration Information</b>
<br/>At least one author of an accepted paper must register for the workshop. If the registration fees are not received by April 9, 2007, the paper will not be published in the proceedings. For registering go to http://www.iceis.org
<br/><br/>
<b>Secretariat</b>
<br/>ICEIS 2007 Secretariat - The Fourth International Workshop on Ubiquitous Computing (IWUC-2007)
<br/>E-mail: workshops@iceis.org 
<br/>Web site: <a href="http://www.iceis.org">http://www.iceis.org</a> 
<br/>

<h2>The 2007 International Conference on Mobile Business</h2>
The annual <b>International m>Business Conference</b> attracts leading scholars and industry leaders from around the world. The theme of m>Business 2007 is Harnessing the Potential of m>Business, and the conference will be in Toronto, Canada, on July 9-11, 2007.
The main aim of m>Business 2007 is to further research, business understanding, strategy and policy in the mBusiness wireless sector. The conference will focus on major trends and challenges in the mobile domain and will help provide a roadmap for future scholarship and business success in this important and wide-ranging arena, by fusing the state of the art in diverse research fields with best practices in industry.
We invite academic participation in the conference, through research papers on a wide diversity of mBusiness topics, in the form of articles, case studies, and posters that have not been published or submitted for publication elsewhere.
We also encourage proposals for panel discussions that explore various aspects of mBusiness, whether they are of short, medium or long-term impact, exploring provocative questions in a critical fashion. The panel proposal (2,000 words max) should indicate panel title, panelists (name, position, affiliation, country), and panel topic (domain, objectives, key issues). A brief list of questions to be addressed should be included. All panelists are expected to register for the conference.
<br/><br/>
<b>IMPORTANT DATES</b>
<br/>January 13, 2007 Abstract submissions due (strongly encouraged)
<br/>February 10, 2007 Full paper submissions due
<br/>March 27, 2007 Paper acceptance notifications
<br/>April 30, 2007 Panel proposals due
<br/>July 9-11, 2007 m>Business Conference
<br/>July 12-13, 2007 8th World Congress on the Management of eBusiness (same venue)
<br/><br/>
<b>AREAS OF INTEREST</b> for m>Business 2007
<br/>Conference tracks include:
<ul>
<li>Mobile Business Models</li>
<li>Usability and Adoption</li>
<li>Emerging Mobile Technologies</li>
<li>Privacy and Security</li>
<li>Social and Economic Impact</li>
<li>Context-Aware and Location-Based Services</li>
<li>Mobile Consumer Services</li>
<li>Mobile Payment and Financial Services</li>
<li>Mobile Healthcare</li>
<li>Mobile Enterprise and Workforce Support</li>
<li>RFID and Mobile Supply Chain Management</li>
<li>Policy and Regulation</li>
<li>Mobile Commerce in Asia</li>
</ul>
<b>PAPER SUBMISSIONS</b>
<br/>Prospective participants are strongly encouraged to submit paper abstracts in advance by January 13, 2007. Academic paper submissions should be completed papers in MS-Word format and should be approximately 7 pages in length. See the formatting and submission instructions on this site for further information. All submissions will be blind reviewed. Accepted papers will be published in the Conference IEEE Proceedings. High quality papers will be recommended for a special issue of the International Journal of Mobile Communications, and there will be a prize awarded for the best academic paper at the conference.
Authors of accepted papers are required to register for the conference and present their papers in the allotted sessions.
<br/><br/>
<b>ORGANIZING COMMITTEE</b>
<br/>For further information, contact:
<br/>Conference Chair Dr. Yufei Yuan yuanyuf@mcmaster.ca McMaster University
<br/>Program Chair Dr. Khaled Hassanein hassank@mcmaster.ca McMaster University
<br/>Research Track Chair Dr. Norm Archer archer@mcmaster.ca McMaster University
<br/>Industry Track Chair Dr. Christian Couturier christian.couturier@nrc-cnrc.gc.ca National Research Council
<br/>

</page_body>
</page>
